<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="acquire-v">    
   <commentary>
	No VPCs to add
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="develop or internalize a new ability, skill, or preference" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Includes: NP1[agent] ACQUIRE NP2[patient]
                         NP1[theme] AQUIRE NP2[patient]      
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
	She acquired fluency in French during her years in Paris.
	This strain of bacteria is acquiring immunity to antibiotics.
	He has acquired an aversion to broccoli. 
	These children are not acquiring the skills they'll need to succeed in the world.
        I learned to work well under a deadline, and acquired confidence in my abilities.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,6,7</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>acquire.01</pb>
         <vn>learn-14</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="take on, display, or exhibit a characteristic" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Includes: NP1[topic] ACQUIRE NP2[patient]
                         NP1[topic] ACQUIRE SCOMP[attribute]
	Note: Implies the physical or outward display of the attribute.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	Bob has acquired a limp since the last time I saw him.
	The demon acquired the form of a young maiden.
	Sally is acquiring a chip on her shoulder. (figurative)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>acquire.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="become the owner or posessor of something" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1[agent] ACQUIRE NP2[patient]
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
	The giant software firm just acquired two small start-ups.
	She acquired several works of art from her uncle's estate.
	We acquired a permit to add an extension to our kitchen.
        The Beaufort County Trust aquired the property and sold it to Joel Silver.
        At the Investor Day, Penim was clearly motivated to acquire the football rights.
        No one knows how the New River acquired its name given all these theories.
        Early in his career he acquired the title 'Duke of Tralee'.
        Lopardo acquired the team in 2002 when he purchased the then-Waterbury Spirit.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>acquire.01</pb>
         <vn>obtain-13.5.2-1</vn><fn>Getting</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="locate something moving, obtain a fix on something moving" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Includes: NP1[agent] ACQUIRE NP2[target]
                         NP1[theme] ACQUIRE NP2[target]
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
	The missile has acquired its target and locked on.
	The police acquired the getaway car through triangulation.
	They weren't able to acquire the aircraft on their radar.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>acquire.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
     <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>