<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="adjust-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="reorient, realign or reposition something" type="">
      <commentary>
       Note: Transitive.
      Syntax Is: NP[agent] ADJUST[transitive] NP[target]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Adjust the height of your chair so that your wrists can rest comfortably on the keyboard.
        The dance instructor adjusted her position.
        If it's too hot under the electric blanket, they can adjust the dial down.
        Adjust your seat belt so that you are comfortable.
        Don't forget to adjust the clocks tonight when we go on daylight savings time.
       Boot camp will adjust your expectations of doing as you please. (figurative extension)
       Analysts have adjusted their economic outlook based on these new figures. (figurative extension)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>adjust.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Adjusting</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
 
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="accept, acclimate or adapt to a context, situation" type="">
      <commentary>
      Note: Intransitive. The situation being adjusted to is presented in a PP with TO.
        The TO PP may be omitted. See ex. 4 and 5.
      Syntax Is: NP[agent] ADJUST[intransitive] to NP
        Note: implies the subject is changing state
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Many teens have difficulty adjusting to a new stepparent.
        The pets who survived the hurricane are adjusting to new homes.
        Mary and John are adjusting to having a baby in the house.
        Living in the same house isn't awkward just for me; I'm sure he's adjusting too.
        If you're not adjusting as well as you'd like, seek help from professional counsellors.
        The salinity of the water must be lowered gradually to give the fish time to adjust.
        Some of the workers had difficulty adjusting to the new management.
        Give your eyes time to adjust to the darkness.
        Let the engine adjust to the cold temperature before starting it up.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>adjust.01</pb>
         <vn>adjust-26.9</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="3" name="decide the amount to be paid on an insurance claim" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: a narrow specialized sense related to deciding insurance claims.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        It will be possible to pay the policy limits through dialogue with the insured and without waiting for a site visit 
to adjust the loss.
        Many times an insurer will adjust the benefit after receiving additional information that justifies the higher charg
e.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>adjust.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="duffielc, ahouston, brownsw" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>