<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="administration-n">
    <commentary>
        27sep06, updated to wn2.1, added features, examples, definitions. ahouston
        27sep06  split sense 1 into sense1, new sense 4. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a governing organization or entity" type="">
        <commentary>
            ADMINISTRATION[+entity][+social][+group][+organization][+governing]
            The people, groups, or departments that make up a larger governing body
            Note: refers to the people, not to a time span of management (see Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            All these workers are political appointees of the current administration. 
            I'm working for the Food and Drug Administration.
            The university administration is taking their demands seriously.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Overseeing, supervising or management of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            ADMINISTRATION[+activity][+management][+ongoing]
            The act of supervising or tending to something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You're in charge of the administration of the entire department.
            I have a degree in business administration.
            This banking firm is involved in the administration and regulation of banks.
            The Systems Administrator is in charge of the administration of our computer network.
            The island has remained under French administration. (managing is done by the French)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="dispensing, handing out a treatment" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    ADMINISTRATION[+event][+action][+dispensing][+medicine/+justice]
	    The act of giving something, often medical treatment
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The patient fell asleep after the administration of a sedative.
            The improper administration of drugs can have a harmful effect.
            Only after a number of administrations of the therapy did doctors see an effect.
            The torture victim finally talked after the administration of electric shocks.
            The administration of justice will be swift.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a period of time in office, a tenure" type="">
        <commentary>
            ADMINISTRATION[+extent][+temporal][+term][+office][+elected/+appointed]
            Note: refers to a span of time, not the body of people comprising the office (see Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            During that administration there was a national draft.
            His administration lasted eight years.
            Nixon did not complete his second administration.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>