<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="afford-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="manage or bear to do something; spare something" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        No nation can afford to ignore the threat of flu pandemic.
        Hypocrisy can afford to be magnificent in its promises.
        We need to focus on the amount of data the organization can afford to lose.
        The MPAA can afford to relax.
        I can't afford to spend two hours babysitting this person! I have my own work to do.
        We can't afford any more lost time or we'll lose the competition.
        The new regime can afford a few concessions because it will beat the opposition in the elections.
        Both players have realized that they can afford a couple of calls going against them.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>afford.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>     
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="have the financial means to obtain, buy, or do something" type="">
      <commentary>
        NOTE: Unlike sense 1, this sense has to do with having means to obtain something
        NP1 desires or needs. Specifically a financial sense.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        We can't afford a vacation this year.
        If our insurance won't cover the costs, we can't afford it.
        Calvin didn't buy a house he couldn't afford.
        How can we afford to send our kids to an Ivy League college?
        Can you afford to buy the new iPod?
        Who can afford a $200 loss per cow?
        The company can't afford to send you to Europe to meet with clients.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>afford.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="provide" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The hut afforded little protection from the elements.
        Her seat afforded her an uninterrupted view of the stage.
        The Court has afforded bloggers the same kind of protection usually reserved to journalists.
        If you are jumping with just a body harness you are afforded quite a bit of freedom to move around.
        Our meeting afforded much interesting information.
        1901 Ash Creek Bridge Crossing this bridge affords access to the original stagecoach trail.
        It's the sliding door affords access to the patio or deck.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>afford.02</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,hwangd,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>
