<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="apply-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) be applicable; utilize" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Syntax Is: NP1[agent] APPLY[trans] NP2[instrument]
       Note: Utilize with the purpose of achiving something.
        Literal and metaphorical use.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He applied his first-aid skills to help the accident victims.
        Apply these rules on your problem set.
        Practitioners apply magnetic field therapy to the outside of the body.
        The first basic change in lamps applied a principle that was later adapted to gas burners.
        Do you just randomly apply insults to a situation as you can think of them?
        He applied a punch to his face.
        The couple applied their money and efforts to their morgage.
        The same rules apply to everyone! 
        I applied the breaks but couldn't avoid the head-on collision.
        The theory applies here.
        Offer applies to US and Canadian addresses only.
        Please also see the following information as it applies to you.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,5,6,7,8,9</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>apply.02,apply.04</pb>
         <vn>use-105.1</vn><fn>Using</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="formally request or ask" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Is: NP1[agent] APPLY[intransitive] PP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He applied for a job in Limerick.
        Apply for admission to any public university in Texas.
        You can apply for a loan on your own or with a cosigner.
        Cingular applied to patent smileys?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>apply.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="cause to spread over a surface, make contact" type="">
      <commentary>
        NP1[agent] APPLY[transitive] NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        They applied red paint to their torsos, highlighting their tattooed designs.
        The boy applied glue sparingly to the paper.
        She applied makeup in bold strokes, outlining her almond-shaped eyes in black.
        He drills them for the keychain, paints them and applies stickers.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>apply.03</pb>
         <vn>put-9.1-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="work diligently (on something)" type="">
      <commentary>
        APPLY ONESELF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I could have done better if I'd applied myself a little more.
        Apply yourself, child!
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>