<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="area-n">
    <commentary>
        30aug06 split sense 2 into sense 2, sense 5. ahouston
        30aug06 added features, examples, modified defs, update to WN 2.1 ahouston.
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="Geographic region" type="">
        <commentary>
            AREA[+location][+geographical][+region][+indefinite]
            A physical region of indefinite boundry.
            Note: a vague, large-scale region, not small and well-defined (see Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bill lives in a mountainous area.
            These homes are in one of the best areas of town.
            People in rural areas didn't get electricity as soon os those in the city.
            Food and medical supplies are being airlifted to the disaster area.
            It's a terrible slum area with a high crime rate.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="social sphere, scope of activity or interest" type="">
        <commentary>
            AREA[+environment][+social][+scope][+interest/+activity]
            Reference to a particular situation, interest or activity.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Science has influenced every area of my life.
            George's areas of interest include: fishing, biking, swimming, baking, and knitting.
            He thinks the administration has been incompetent in the area of foreign policy.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a circumscribed place with a specific characteristic" type="">
        <commentary>
            AREA[+location][+locale][+circumscribed][+characteristic][+specified]
            A section of something having a specific characteristic or function.
            Note: the modifier usually describes the function or characteristic of the locale.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It is important to stretch even before excercising the abdominal area.
            The kid's play area slowly took over more and more of the house.
            We'll turn the storage area of the attic into the guest room.
            Please proceed to the main check-in area.
            There's a little picnic area in the park beside the new house.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="2D bounded space in geometry" type="Technical">
        <commentary>
            AREA[+quantity][+extent][+geometric][+bounded][+2D]
            A measurement of flat space in square units.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Determine whether the area of this triangle is equal to the area of that square.
            The garden covers a total area of 200 square feet.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="field of study, knowledge domain" type="">
        <commentary>
            AREA[+entity][+symbolic][+knowledge][+domain]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The comprehensive exam will cover four areas of computer science and applied mathematics.
            Orthodontics is his area of specialization.
            It's an area of economic analysis that has been largely ignored by mainstream academia.   
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>