<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="assume-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="accept as true without verificaiton" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I assume his train was late.
        To assume good faith is a fundamental principle on any wiki, including Wikipedia.
        It's politely assumed that democracy is a means of containing and restraining violence.
        Man has always assumed that he was more intelligent than dolphins.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>assume.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
 
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="take on a feature, position, responsibility, right, etc." type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        When will the new President assume office?
        She assumed strange manners.
        The gods assume human or animal form in these fables.
        He assumes the lotus position.
        Increasingly, families with limited resources have had to assume debt to defray these costs.
        He assumed to himself the right to fill all positions in the town.
        The contractor shall assume responsibility for all functions.
        Dress then assumed a more natural appearance.
        She assumed indifference.
        You'd put on a costume, assume a character, and act out a part.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,3,4,5,6,7</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>assume.01</pb>
         <vn>adopt-93</vn><fn>Adopt_selection</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="3" name="take someone's soul into heaven" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This is the day when Mary was assumed into heaven.
        Many believe that she did not die at all, but was Assumed directly into heaven.
        If the George Mason Law faculty were suddenly assumed into heaven, would there be any loss to the legal profession here on earth?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="4" name="wear, put on" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The queen assumed the stately robes.
        In the third frame, the youth has assumed clothing, jewelry, and thus identity.
        There are no beings known as hats, coats, shoes, dresses, and trousers--those are just the clothing assumed by us humans.
        The young black throat bunting, although full grown, had not yet assumed their second clothing, in which the sexes are distinguished.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>