<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="attention-n">
    <commentary>4oct06 update to wn2.1, added features, changed examples, modified definitions. ahouston
        16Jan09 - merged S1 and S3  ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="mental focus or observation on a subject of interest" type="">
        <commentary>ATTENTION[+state][+mental][+observation][+focused]</commentary>
        <examples>My attention was suddenly directed to a loud crash outside the window.
            The speaker had the audience's complete attention.
            The crisis in Lebanon has become the center of attention in recent weeks.
            Some drivers don't pay attention to their driving while on the cellphone.
            The teacher drew attention to the spelling errors in the compositions.
            The administration has turned its attention to the educational system.
            Mary decided the slacks drew unflattering attention to her hips.
            This story originally drew the attention of a freelance journalist from New York.
            Sally never paid much attention to her sister's views on politics.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="action of administering aid or maintenaince" type="">
        <commentary>ATTENTION[+action][+administration][+of_aid][+maintenance]
            Note: implies the assistance or care is required, not optional
        </commentary>
        <examples>The doctor told him the infection would require further medical attention.
            John's old car needed constant attention to keep running.
            A leaking roof requires prompt attention.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="3" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="">Placeholder Sense</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="affection, courteous assistance" type="">
        <commentary>ATTENTION[+action][+assistance][+optional][+courteous]
            Note: refers to social, physical and/or communication acts towards another
        </commentary>
        <examples>Betty was flattered by the attentions of the handsome life guard.
            They bestowed every possible attention on the visiting dignitary.
            The wealthy old lady was amused by the attentions of her fortune-seeking nephew.
            Unwanted attentions in the workplace can constitute sexual harassment.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="military physical stance" type="Military">
        <commentary>ATTENTION[+state][+physical][+posture][+erect][+motionless]
            a motionless erect stance with arms at the sides and feet together;
            assumed by military personnel during drill or review (only used in the
            phrase &quot;at attention&quot;)
        </commentary>
        <examples>The troops stood at attention for an hour.
            He was told to stand at attention by his commanding officer.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>