<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="baste-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="drench periodically with liquid while cooking" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate]] BASTE NP2[destination] (PP[theme])
      NP1[agent[animate]] BASTE NP2[theme] (PP[destination])
      NP1[theme] BASTE NP2[destination]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      The cooks basted the carcasses with a preparation of butter, pepper, salt and vinegar.
      The meat must be basted, and dredged with flour, as carefully as beef.
      It should be well basted, and served with a good gravy and currant jelly.
      The chicken must be repeatedly basted, and cooked until it is tender.
      It is basted with a 20% solution of natural turkey broth and light seasonings.
      I flipped the legs 2 times and basted the sauce on them.
      This time the juice basted the brisket.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>baste.01</pb>
         <vn>spray-9.7-1</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="strike violently and repeatedly" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate]] BASTE NP2[patient[animate]] (PP[instrument])
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Mine had struck down Creed's boy in the dirt, but I basted my rogue soundly.
      I took a broom and basted her till she cried extremely.
      One man was basted by the keeper, for carrying some people over on his back through the water.
      The attackers basted him with a stick.
      If she had had an umbrella she would have basted him over the head with it.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>baste.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="sew together loosely with large stitches" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate]] BASTE
      NP1[agent[animate]] BASTE NP2[patient1] (PP[patient2])
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      I cut and fitted and basted garments that were easily finished.
      She basted and stitched as if there were nothing else in the world to do.
      When all seams are basted, try on the skirt and make all changes necessary before stitching.
      The lining is cut, basted, and fitted before the outside is cut.
      The waist may be basted to the outside piece of the band.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>baste.03</pb>
         <vn>shake-22.3-2</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="bonnj" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
