<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="battle-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a large military fight, by land, sea or air" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            BATTLE[+event][+fight][+large][+military][+land/+air/+sea]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The Battle of Midway is one of the most famous naval battles in history.
            They fought a pitched battle with hand-to-hand combat and bayonets. 
            The young soldier wondered whether he would be brave on the field of battle.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>battle.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="an ongoing attempt to overcome an adversity" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            BATTLE[+attempt][+ongoing][+overpower][+adversity][+disease/+poverty/+prejudice/+fear]
            Note: focus is on an individual or group changing their own state of affairs, different from Sense 3
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She finally lost her battle against breast cancer.
            Alcoholics Anonymous helps people fight their personal battles with alcoholism.
            No one realized the battles John was having with his personal demons. (anxieties, fears)
            These people have fought a long hard battle for their civil rights.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>battle.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an ongoing attempt to prevail in a contest" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            BATTLE[+attempt][+ongoing][+prevail][+contest][+ideological][+cultural][+financial][+political][+will]
            Note: is an abstract extension of Sense 1, but is not military in nature
            Note: focus is on two contesting groups trying to prevail over the other, not over an adversity in themselves.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That game show is a battle of wits.
            Bob and Betty are in a fierce custody battle over their two small children.
            Sara had many battles with her mother as a teenager.
            The lines of battle have been drawn on the issue of the town's tax override. (figurative extension)
            It's an ideological battle being waged in classrooms across the country. 
            The marketing department is formulating their battle plan for the new product launch.  (beat the competition)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>battle.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>