<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="body-n">
    <commentary>
        26sep06 fixed typo; final sense 9 (had been 2 sense 8) ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="any intact living organism" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+organism][+living]
            Note: focus is on the individual being, not its form or physique (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I need two able bodies to guard the front door.
            Foreign bodies can enter the bloodstream through a wound.
            The wealthy man is traveling with two body servants. (attend to the man, not his physique)
            These tiny bodies form a symbiotic relationship with the algae. 
            Can't a body find some peace and quiet around here? (archaic)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the overall form or structure of something, often a living being" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+form][+whole][+/-organic]
            Note: focus is on the body as a possession of a being, not the being itself. (see Sense 1)
            Note: focus is on the whole form, not a component of it, (see Sense 5)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John thinks Sally has a beautiful body.	
            They are studying the human body in anatomy class.
            Their bodies were exhausted from the long five-day march.
            His body's immune system fought off the infection.
            The creature had a round body and large green eyes.
            These robots have squarish bodies and run on wheels.
            The man had strong body odor.
            The soldiers are wearing a new type of body armor.
            John likes the sleek body of that new sports car.
            Dogs pay attention to your body language.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="any dead organism, most often people" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+organism][-living]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The police have cordoned off an area around the dead body.
            Jane swept up the bodies of dead cockroaches with a broom. 
            Bodies lay strewn among the wreckage of the building.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="any assembly of people" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+assembly][+people]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The principal spoke before the entire student body.
            The legislative body is currently in recess.
            He reached out to the body politic of his land.  (countrymen) 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the primary anatomical or structural component of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+anatomy][+component][+primary][+car/+statue/+garment]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That auto repair shop does good body work. (of a car)
            Only the body remains of this statue, the head and limbs were broken off centuries ago.
            The body of this loose garment is cinched at the waist with a belt.
            They found only the bodies without their heads in the mass grave.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,11</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the primary component of a communication" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+communication][+component][+primary][+letter/+speech/+story]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The body of this letter is about why the condominium association is raising fees next year.
            The body of the play centers around the romantic tensions between the two leads.
            He broke the body of the speech into three smaller, but related, topics.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a collection of something, often a large amount" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+quantity][+amount]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The map shows several large bodies of water to the east.
            They have accumulated a body of evidence against the corporate officers.
            The body of Old English literature is not large.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="any distinct object with mass" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+entity][+distinct][+mass]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The mass of a moving body increases with acceleration.
            It is among the largest bodies in the asteroid belt.
            Max Planck puzzled over the apparent paradox of black body radiation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="the quality of fullness, as in taste, touch or sound" type="">
        <commentary>
            BODY[+quality][+fullness][+taste/+touch/+sound]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John enjoys red wines with a full body.
            This shampoo will give your hair more body.
            There is a lot of body in her low notes now. (a singer)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>