<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="business-n">
    <commentary>Sense groups redefined, examples, definitions, comments redefined. ahouston
        includes idiom 'give_one_the_business
        24nov08 - further revisions to defs, exs, features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the commerce sector, a profession within the commercial sector" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+sector][+commercial][+profession]
            Note: refers to general commerce, profession, or sector of industry as a whole
            Note: does not reference a specific company or enterprise (Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>Computers are now widely used in business.
            This bill has not received much support from the business community.
            A group of business leaders are meeting with Congress in Washington next week.
            Their government is not very business friendly.
            This index tracks performance in the oil and other energy businesses.
            This part of town is zoned only for residential housing, not business.
            The men were dressed in business suits.  (professional attire)
            Sally wants to go into show business.
            What line of business did he say he was in?
            He is considered to be the best in the business.  (implies a business -sector-, not a specific single enterprise)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7,3</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a specific commercial enterprise or company" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+organization][+enterprise][+commercial][+specific]
            Specific commercial enterprises
            Note: occurs naturally in the plural, countable, specific establishments.
        </commentary>
        <examples>They have run a family business for three generations.
            Several new businesses opened this year on Main Street.
            John and Bob decided to start their own dry-cleaning business.
            You can deduct these items as business expenses.
            How much did Bob's business actually make last year after expenses?
            That catering business went bankrupt last month.
            There are a lot of small businesses and shops along the town's main boulevard.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the activity or event of commercial transactions, e.g., purchases and sales" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+event][+transaction][+commercial]
            Note: refers to commercial transactions, e.g., purchases, sales, trades.
            Note: can be quantified, e.g., how much business did his company do last year refers to the events, not the organization itself.
        </commentary>
        <examples>Their recent ad campaign has brought in a lot of new business for them.
            Business was slow all week at the Italian restaurant.
            How is business these days?
            She is planning to give all her business to one interior decorating firm.
            I've decided to take my business elsewhere.
            The manager worried that poorly trained staff was driving away business.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,8</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a concern or situation" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+state][+situation][+concern]
            Note: implies an issue or situation rather than a circumscribed, usually physical, action (sense 5)
        </commentary>
        <examples>The first order of business is to have the accountant give us this month's sales figures.
            This business of skateboarding on the bike path has gotten out of hand.
            It seemed that gossip was the main business of that meeting last night.
            He is making it his business to go around and introduce himself to each employee.
            The employees wondered what business the consultants had visiting their department.
            It's none of your business.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a specific behavior or activity" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+event][+behavior][+specific]</commentary><examples>The comedian's business with the hat and cane was hilarious.
            Mary waited for her dog to do his business.
            Cleaning out the septic tank was an evil business.
            Let's get down to business and just finish this report before Monday.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a concoction or creation" type="">
        <commentary>BUSINESS[+structure][+artifact][+concoction]</commentary><examples>He chopped vegetables and sliced meat, then threw the whole business into a sizzling wok.
            Her hat with the purple and green feathers is an elaborate business.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="scold, tell off" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: give_one_the_business</commentary>
        <examples>
            That old lady is really giving that driver the business for
            stopping in the crosswalk.
                </examples>
                <mappings>
                    <wn version="MW online">9a</wn>
                    <omega/><pb/>
                    <fn/>
                </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
            <sense group="1" n="8" name="none of the above" type="">
                <commentary>
                    Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
                </commentary>
                <examples>
                   </examples>
                <mappings>
                    <wn version=""/>
                    <omega/><pb/>
                    <fn/>
                </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>