<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="cancel-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="stop, postpone or annul something from happening" type="">  
      <commentary>
       Note: This sense is strictly for events or processes that were scheduled to happen
             but did not, due to cancellation. If the cancellation happened mid process,
             then the sense 2 would apply.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The guest speaker is sick and has had to cancel class.
        If it rains tomorrow, we'll have to cancel our picnic.
        The 7am train to New York has been cancelled.
        We were forced to cancel our vacation cruise.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>cancel.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="put an end to, make invalid a process that's already begun" type="">
      <commentary>
        Note: This sense implies a process or a series of events have been put to effect
              then put to end by either nullification or invalidation of the process.
        Note: This sense implies something is being stopped after already starting
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Could you cancel my subscription to your magazine?
        Members are free to cancel at any time.
        How do I cancel the download from the internet?
        He is calling on the CEP to cancel the results at this polling station.
        A customer cancelled his personal check on me after receiving the product!
        The bank cancelled the check because it was fraudulent.
        If the stamp has been canceled, the stamp should be light.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,4,5</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>cancel.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="neutralize or counterbalance an effect with an opposite effect" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: CANCEL OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This month's paycheck will cancel out his debt, but it won't give him any extra money.
        The new tax effectively cancels out my raise.
        The `A' will cancel out the `C' on your record.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="cancel_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>cancel.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd,duffielc,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>