<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="capacity-n">
    <commentary>
        22jan07 - update to wn2.1, added features, added/modified examples. ahouston
        22jan07 - split wn '2' out of Sense 1 into separate sense. ahouston
        22jan07 - split wn '9' out of Sense 3 into separate sense. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="inherent competence or ability" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+quality][+competence][+inherent]
            An agent/actor's inherent ability to do something. Often followed by a verb.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our capacity to learn language is largely innate.
            John has a superhuman capacity to memorize names and dates.
            His capacity to inspire his troops was famous throughout the military.
            After such an experience, I'm amazed she still has the capacity to love and trust someone.
            The stroke impaired the patient's capacities of speech and walking.
            These students are performing below their intellectual capacity. (refers to inherent ability, -not- output over time)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Amount that can be contained" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+quantity][+amount][+static][+maximum][+storage]
            The amount, either physical, electronic, or electric, that something can hold.  
            Note: refers to a static contained quantity, -not- a rate of output over time. (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The gas tank has a capacity of twelve gallons.
            The capacity of a hard drive is usually expressed in megabytes.
            Their rock band is playing to capacity crowds around the country. (every seat filled)
            Mary filled the water jugs to capacity.
            What is the seating capacity of this stadium?
            The battery capactiy will be better with lower drain currents.
            What is the carrying capacity of this truck?  (how much cargo it can pull)
            The field capacity of clay is lower than that of rich loam. (how much water a soil type can hold)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="output rate measured over time" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+quantity][+amount][-static][+temporal][+rate][+output]
            Often used to express the rate of industrial production, a limit of output
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The machines are operating at ninety-percent capacity.
            Upgrading our rotors has increased our production capacity.
            When running at full capacity, the factory will employ 1000 workers.
            The company is aiming to double its electrical-generating capacity within three years.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Function or job description" type="Activity">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+relation][+role][+function][+designated]
            Usually used to refer to jobs.  The specific function of a thing or person.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was employed in the capacity of director.  
            He should be retained in his current capacity at a higher salary.
            They are working only in a voluntary capacity for the organization.
            She could authorize it in her capacity as head of the department.
            Sally said she'd be glad to help us in any capacity.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="relative measure of endurance or tolerance for something" type="">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+quality][+endurance][+measure]
            Note: a relative measure  of endurance or tolerance for something. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob needs to recognize that he has no capacity for alcohol.
            Their people have a greater capacity to work in incredible heat than ours do.
            We were amazed at her capacity for hot chili peppers. (she ate a lot of them)
            The capacity to withstand cold temperatures varies somewhat across individuals.
            Practice will increase your capacity to hold your breath while swimming underwater.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the potential state of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+state][+potential]
            Note: refers to a possible state something can exist in
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Which metals have the capacity to combine together into alloys?
            He has the capacity to fly off the handle if his views are challenged in any way.
            This novel may have the capacity to be reworked into a good film.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="legally-defined competence" type="">
        <commentary>
            CAPACITY[+quality][+competence][+legally][+determined]
            Note: a specialized legal usage of Sense 1, implying adequate mental facility established -by experts-
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Psychiatrists are determining whether or not he has the capacity to stand trial.
            The prosecution has questioned the patient's competence as a witness. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>