<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="carry-v">
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="transport, move, or extend (from X) (to Y)" type="">
      <commentary>
         Includes: CARRY AWAY, CARRY OFF, CARRY OVER, CARRY FORWARD, CARRY BACK

         Note: X, Y can be location, state, or time 
         Note: Movement is explicit or entailed.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         I can't carry all these bags into the house at once.
         That player can really carry the ball!
         Just carry the total from that column to this column.
         For 68+57, I add 8 and 7 to get 15, that I put down 5 and carry 1.
         Small plankton and shrimp are carried by the ocean currents.
         The ambulance carried the injured athlete away this morning.
         While traveling with her husband she was carried off by the centaur Nessus.

         It is easy, however, to carry the argument too far.
         The civil war carried into the neighboring province.
         The news was carried by word of mouth to every settlement. 
         His considerable fame carried him to Rome and Milan.
         Her voice carries well in this big opera house.
         Sound carries well over water.
         I try not to let my problems at work carry over into my private life.

         The news carried from village to village.
         How do you carry forward the balance (good or bad) of the previouse month?
         You cannot carry the credit back to taxation years that end before April 23, 2003.
         It is possible to carry over the budget beyond the expected completion date. 
         This rifle carries 3,000 feet (has a range of 3,000 feet).
         The dog was taught to fetch and carry. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3,8,9,16,17,19,28,29,30,32,35,36</wn>         
         <wn lemma="carry_away" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_forward" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_back" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_off" version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_over" version="3.0">1,2,3,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.01</pb>
         <vn>carry-11.4</vn><fn>Bringing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="have, contain, hold, or feature" type="">
      <commentary>
         Note: No movement of the carried thing entailed.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         He always carries a cane.
         These jugs will carry our water supply.
         How many people are carried on the payroll?
         Do you carry karosene holders?
         I will always carry his smile in my mind.
         Darien's face carried frustration.
         His opinion carries a lot of weight.

         The crime carries a penalty of five years in prison.
         This loan carries a high interest rate.
         Citibank carries $150 million in earthquake insurance.
         The restaurant is now carrying a new menu.
         The morning news carried the press conference.
         It was a candid story of an athlete, who carried a cause and succeeded.
         His heart still carried scars from what Boyer had said about riders like him.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4,7,10,12,14,15,18,21,22,25,26</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_weight" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.01</pb>
         <vn>cost-54.2,fit-54.3</vn><fn>Bringing, Bearing_arms</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="support, sustain, bear, or be responsible for" type="">
      <commentary>
         Syntax Includes:
         NP1[agent] CARRY NP2[patient]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The weight of the cathedral roof is carried by two rows of pillars.
         The biology majors are carrying a heavy course load.
         The middle class carried the largest tax burden for many years.
         He resented having to carry his brother through years of illness.
         He really drank more than he could carry.
         This land will carry ten cows to the acre.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,20,24,31,33,34</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.01</pb>
         <vn>fit-54.3</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="win or be approved" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The senator will probably carry his home state.
         He carried the crowd with his impassioned speech.
         the troops carried the town after a brief fight.
         The motion to nominate John as president carried easily.
         She lost the game but carried the match.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">11,23,27,37,38</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="behave or move in a certain manner" type="">
      <commentary>
         Includes: CARRY ONESELF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         He always carried himself with dignity.
         Still carries herself with her trademark style.
         You can tell she's a dancer from the way that she carries herself.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6,13</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="lose control of action, emotions, or behavior" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: CARRY AWAY, CARRY ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Sorry, I got carried away in the moment.
        The crowd was carried away by his passionate speech.
        The children have carried on all day!
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="carry_away" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_on" version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="achieve something successfully" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: CARRY A TUNE, CARRY OFF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He can't, for his life, carry a tune.
        I thought he carried off the part of Hamlet with great skill.
        She was nervous about giving a talk, but she carried it off very well.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">39</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_off" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.05</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="8" name="continue or do something as desired or planned" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: CARRY ON, CARRY OUT, CARRY THROUGH
        Includes: LIGHT VERBS
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Let's carry on this discussion at some other time.
        You just have to carry on as if nothing's happened.
        Daphne is carrying on the family tradition by becoming a lawyer.
        We need solid plans to carry out this task properly.
        Will it be possible to carry through the reforms as quickly as we hope?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_on" version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_out" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_through" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>carry.02,carry.03,carry.04</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="9" name="be pregnant or continue to be pregnant" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        It was quite a shock to learn that she was carrying twins.
        I was enormous when I was carrying Josh.
        Most women who miscarry, will carry to term if they become pregnant again.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">40</wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_to_term" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="10" name="CARRY OFF: eliminate or decimate" type="">
      <commentary>
      Is: CARRY OFF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He admitted that the disease carried off large numbers of persons.
        In 1160, Saracens carried off the entire population of Porquerolles.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_off" version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="11" name="CARRY THROUGH: (cause to) endure or survive through hardship" type="">
      <commentary>
      Is: CARRY THROUGH 
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The soldiers' courage carried them through.
        I force her to eat a snack at bedtime to carry her through the night.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="carry_through" version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>