<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="challenge-n">
    <commentary>
        Groups, defintions, comments and examples revised by ahouston
        Note: WordNet version 2.1 is being used here, not 2.0
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="stimulating or demanding factors of a situation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CHALLENGE[+event][+state][+factor][+stimulating]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            This rocket ship has been built to withstand the challenges of deep space.
            John likes the challenge of running his own company.
            Her challenge will be to bring the three parties to the negotiating table.
            The challenge of feeding a starving population and fighting a war was beyond the government's ability.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="objection or protest" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CHALLENGE[+event][+activity][+communication][+objection]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The audience made several challenges to the claims of the speaker.
            Her challenge of the assumption that extra dimensions must be tiny has stirred the physics community.
            There are already legal challenges to this bill on constitutional grounds.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a summons or call to action, as a contest or showdown" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHALLENGE[+activity][+summons]
            a call to engage in a contest or fight
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            When she accepted his challenge, she knew there was no turning back.
            Jane and Bob signed on for the BP Challenge, a sailboat race around the world.
            Will the heavyweight champion accept this challenge from the young Bulgarian fighter?
            Count Cristo made his challenge to the Duke by slapping his glove across the man's face.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="demand for a code or password" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHALLENGE[+test][+demand]
            a demand  for a password or ID
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The computer will present you with a challenge, at which point you type in the access code.
            You must know the answers to the troll's three challenges to enter the castle in that adventure game.
            The enemy scout got caught when he failed the sentry's challenge at the gate.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="formal objection to a candidate juror" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHALLENGE[+activity][+rejection][+juror]
            a formal objection to the selection of a particular person as a juror
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            If the judge allows the challenge, the juror will be replaced.
            Both attorneys are allowed to make challenges to the jury selection.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="testing physiological activity by exposure to a substance" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CHALLENGE[+event][+activity][+test][+experiment][+physical]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            They used two different antigens as challenges to the human immune system.
            These chemicals seem to form a family of challenges to certain metabolic processes.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>challenge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>