<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="chamber-n">
    <commentary>
        Revised ANN file
        merged senses 3 and 4. ahouston
        26sep06 added dummy sense 4. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a room, serving a human activity" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHAMBER[+structure][-movable][+room][+work/+sleep/+death]
            Note: implies an unmovable structure, (different from Sense 2)
            Note: purpose is for social or human activity.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The master chamber of the old house had a magnificent canopied bed.
            This room of the palace served as a torture chamber.
            The attorneys are in chambers right now with the judge. (private rooms for legal affairs)
            The committee is holding a meeting in the council chamber.
            Millions died in the gas chambers during World War II. 
            Chamber music is best played in intimate room settings and small halls, not huge venues.
            The large, ornate burial chambers of the ancient pharaohs were pillaged by grave robbers.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a compartment of a larger structure" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHAMBER[+structure][+moveable][+component][+compartment][+purposeful]
            Note: implies the compartment and/or its whole is movable. (different from Sense 1)
            Note: purpose is of a physical or chemical nature
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob uses a cloud chamber to study tracks produced by moving particles.
            The munition of a gun is discharged in the firing chamber.
            The human heart has four chambers, two ventricle and two atria. 
            John spent hours in a hyperbaric chamber after he got the bends while diving.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a legislative or administrative body" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHAMBER[+role][+authority][+administrative][+legislative/+legal/+business]
            [+group][+assembly][+people][+judge/+legislator/+councilor]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That reporter has been assigned to cover the Senate chamber.
            Both chambers of the House have approved the bill.
            He is working the chamber trying to get enough votes to pass his bill.
            The entire chamber stood up and gave him a standing ovation for three minutes.
            It's an event put on by the local chamber of commerce.
            Much speculation today about what may be going on in the policy chambers of Washington.(metaphoric extension, decision-making parallel to a legislative body)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
            
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="an underground cavern" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHAMBER[+structure][-moveable][+natural][+cavern][+underground]
            Note: perhaps an extension of Sense 1, but is a natural phenomenon with no purpose.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The underground passage opened up into a vast chamber with stalactites and stalagmites. 
            A series of underground chambers were formed by water eroding limestone.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>