<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="chance-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an opportunity" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHANCE[+state][+situation][+opportunity]
            Note: implies a situation where one can achieve a goal
            Note: does not imply the situation arose randomly, different from Sense 2
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They never gave him a chance to explain what happened.
            This turn of events presents a chance for peace negotiations to go forward.
            She had many chances to apologize but never did.
            This program aims to give poor children a fair chance of getting an education.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="events without apparent cause, random occurrence, luck" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHANCE[+event][+random][+apparently]
            Note: emphasis is on a specific event which has no apparent cause
            Note: does not imply an undesirable outcome, different from Sense 3
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            By chance I found Jane's watch under the car seat.
            The staff left nothing to chance when preparing the president's trip abroad.
            Black jack is supposed to be a game of chance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="risk, potential bad outcome" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHANCE[+state][+potential][-desirable]
            Note: entails a notion of likelihood, but the focus is on the avoidance of a negative outcome
            Note: a restricted, negative usage of Sense 4, emphasizing avoidance, not the abstract measurement of probability.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John is taking too many chances on the stock market with his portfolio.
            This is a chance we'll have to take. (implies we'd prefer -not- to take it)
            They fenced their yard to avoid the chance of having the children run into the street.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a measure of the likelihood or probability of an event" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHANCE[+quantity][+measure][+likelihood] 
            Note: emphasis is on the amount of likelihood of some situation, not the situation itself.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Is there any chance of him taking that job in London?
            What are the chances of rolling ten sixes in a row?
            Our team doesn't stand a chance to win the championship. (the odds are against us)
            Fat chance!  (slang meaning almost no likelihood)
            There's a slim chance it will rain tonight.
            Chances are they are sitting on a beach somewhere with a cold drink in hand.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>