<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="charge-n">
    <commentary>
        8Jan08 update to wn2.1.added features, examples, modified definitions  ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="4" n="1" name="the price of a good or service" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+quantity][+money][+price][+of_something]
            price charged for some good or service
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Admission charges at movie theaters have been going up recently.
            The bar doesn't have a cover charge except on Friday and Saturday nights.   
            We'll send you the first two issues of the magazine free of charge.   
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">13</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="4" n="2" name="financial liability, what is owed" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+quantity][+money][+debt][+owed]
            a financial liability, what is owed
            Note: implies a relation between parties, one owes the other, in contrast to pure abstract pricing of an object (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They submitted their charges to customers at the end of each month.  (amount customers owe them)
            These charges on my bill don't seem to add up correctly.
            The accountant said that a corporate asset of $500,000 should have been taken as a charge against earnings.
            If you decide not to sign up for a subscription, the copy of the magazine is still yours, free of charge. (no payment owed)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7,12</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="4" n="3" name="accusation of guilt or wrong-doing" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+event][+speech_act][+accusation][+of_guilt]
            an assertion that someone is guilty of a fault or offense; 
            typically used in criminal law
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The newspaper published charges that the attorney had tried to bribe members of the jury.
            He was arrested on a charge of murder.
            Three people were arrested but later released without charge.
            The woman may press charges against the doctor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,10</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="4" n="4" name="legal directive or command from a judge to a jury" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+event][+speech_act][+directive][+instruction][+legal][+by_judge]
            formal instructions, directives from an authority, e.g., a judge advising  a jury
            a formal statement of a command or injunction to do something
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The judge's charge to the jury was to ignore the preceding statement of the witness.
            Before the jury retired for deliberations, the judge issued several charges concerning the legal points of the case.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">15</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.04</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="physically rushing at something intentionally" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+event][+physical][+intentional][+rushing][+towards_object]
            an impetuous rush toward someone or something
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The wrestler's charge carried him past his adversary.
            The battle began with a cavalry charge.
            The offensive charge gained their football team 22 yards in the last play.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="4" n="6" name="a mission, an important assignment" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+state][+goal][+assignment][+important]
            a special assignment that is given to a person or group
            Note: a somewhat dated usage
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His charge was to deliver a message behind enemy lines.
            The spy fulfilled his charge of smuggling fissile materials into the country.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.04</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="3" n="7" name="dependent, person under the care of someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+entity][+person][+dependent][+with_guardian]
            a person who is committed to your care
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The kindergarten teacher led her young charges across the street.
            That nursing home was cited for several types of negligence concerning its charges.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="3" n="8" name="having responsibility for managing or supervising" type="">
        <commentary>
	    CHARGE[+event][+state][+responsibility][+supervisory]
	    implies an ongoing responsibility to supervise, manage, oversee something
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The Admiral has charge of the entire Pacific naval fleet.
            They have put Mary in charge of the London sales office.
            The new CEO will have to take charge of the financial mess left behind by his predecessor.
            The patients in her charge are all terminally ill.  (she oversees their care - refers to the responsibility -not- the people)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.04</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="measure of electricity in a body or particle" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+quantity][+electricity][+on_body]
            the quantity of unbalanced electricity in a body (either positive or
            negative) and construed as an excess or deficiency of electrons
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The battery needed a fresh charge.
            The electron has a negative charge and the proton a positive charge.
            This particle has no charge.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="explosives, ordinance" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+entity][+substance][+explosive][+chemical]
            explosive charge - 
            a quantity of explosive to be set off at one time
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This cartridge has a powder charge of 50 grains.
            The charges got wet and would not detonate.
            The demolition crew planted charges strategically throughout the building.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">14</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="a thrill, exhilaration" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+state][+emotional][+exhilaration]
            a feeling of exhilaration,  a thrill or rush
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They got a great charge out of going over the waterfall in a kayak.
            What a charge!
            He got a quick charge from injecting heroin.
            She gets a real charge out of working hard and solving problems.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="cathexis" type="Psychoanalysis">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+state][+mental][+concentrated][+fixation][+on_something]
            the libidinal energy invested in some idea or person or object
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Freud thought of charge as a psychic analog of an electrical charge.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="2" n="13" name="armorial decoration, heraldry" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+entity][+artifact][+component][+heraldry][+on_shield]
            heraldry consisting of a design or image depicted on a shield
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His charge is a sharp design with lots of pointed edges
            His opponent's charge consists largely of curved lines.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="2" n="14" name="buy with credit card" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CHARGE[+event][+transaction][+purchase][+with_credit_card]
            the act of purchasing on credit
            Note: nominalization: X's charge of Y -&gt; X charged Y
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's charge of the dress on her old credit card would not go through.
            The charge of $900 dollars of merchandise to his father's credit card got John into big trouble.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>charge.05</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <sense group="1" n="15" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>