<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="child-n">
    <commentary>
        Includes idioms: child's_play, from_a_child, with_child
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a biologically immature person, girl or boy" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHILD[+person][+age][+young]
            Note: the focus is on the youthful age of the individual
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His legal work mostly involves child abuse cases.
            The theater doesn't allow children under the age of four.
            Children seem to like simple food like macaroni and cheese.
            It was as though he were seeing the world through a child's eyes.
            The pro-lifers have argued for the rights of the unborn child.
            Mary was thrilled by ultrasound images of her child in utero.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the immediate biological descendent of human parents" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHILD[+role][+descendant][+biological][+offspring]
            Note: the focus is on the status as an immediate biological descendant of someone.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Megan is the second child from Mary's first marriage.
            That couple had no children of their own.
            Their grown children have moved away.
            Whose children are playing in the street in front of our house?
            The king had a love child with one of the ladies in waiting.
            This is the brain child of our chief technology officer.  (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a grown-up who is inexperienced or immature in some way" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHILD[+person][+age][-young][+naive/+selfish]
            Note: emphasis is on the person's behavior, perceived as inappropriate for their age.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm a child when it comes to repairing electrical fixtures.
            Mary can act like such a child when she doesn't get her way about where to go for dinner.
            John is rather a child about financial matters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a member or descendent of a clan or social unit" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHILD[+role][+descendant][+tribal][+member]
            Note: emphasis is on a social and biological (in a broad sense) connection to a social group.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He led the children of Israel from Egypt.
            No child of the Navajo nation would ever say or do such a thing.
            The novel is a classic read by all French children.
            The senator argued his bill would only improve the lives of our children. (those in our society)
            She said it would place a tax burden on our children for generations to come.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="someone significantly influenced by tastes or trends" type="">
        <commentary>
            CHILD[+role][+descendant][+cultural][+example]
            Note: emphasis is on behavior or beliefs of an individual.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sally was a flower child in the sixties.
            They are the children of poverty.
            He was a child of a broken home.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="an easy task" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: chld's_play
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bill thought fixing the kitchen drain would be child's play.
            Running a bed and breakfast has not turned out to be child's play.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Mac">child's_play</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="since childhood" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: from_a_child
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He showed extraordinary musical gifts from a child.
            From a child she was always easily excitable.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Mac">from_a_child</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="pregnant" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: with_child, formal usage
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            And Joseph led Mary on the donkey when she was with child.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Mac">with_child</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>