<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="claim-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the assertion or demand of the right to own or possess something" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM [+action][+assertion][+right]
            Note: the ownership is not a given, but is being sought
            Includes idiom lay_claim_to
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children have made a claim for an increase in their weekly allowance.
            Their claim will ask for damages.
            The wage claim is higher than management anticipated.
            Sally was angry that Bill had laid claim to all the research results from her own experiments.
            Three Caribbean nations have claims to the remains of that 16th century shipwreck.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,3,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>assert.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the assertion of a proposition offered as true" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM[+action][+assertion][+truth]
            Note: the truth of the assertion is not a given, but can be challenged.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their claim of authenticity in regards to this alleged Rembrandt has been proven false.
            Her claim is counter to what the neighbors told the police.
            Their claims of being mistreated appear to be highly subjective.
            The claim is that this drug is very effective in treating asthma. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>claim.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a state of ownership, usually legal, sometimes metaphoric" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM[+state][+ownership][+legal/+metaphoric]
            Note: this implies a current state of ownership, not an ongoing seeking or challenging of it.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was disappointed to learn that he had no claim to any of his grandfather's estate.
            The child's claim on his mother's attention was absolute.
            So what is her claim to fame?
            The legal claim to this invention belongs to the patent holder.
            Their claim of 51 percent of that company gives them the controlling share of it.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>claim.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="physical property identified as owned by someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM[+physical][+property][+possessed]
            Note: Implies either legal ownership or simply possession of property.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His claim stretches fifteen miles in that direction.
            The prospectors each set up their own claim along the river bed.
            They had to keep family members on the property at all times to prevent claim jumpers from taking over.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="legal document of obligation or title" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM[+document][+obligation][+due]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was shocked at the amount indicated on his insurance claim.
            The previous owner has already signed the claim that transfers ownership to us.
            Fill out this claim form and then take it to the next window.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>claim.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a locale to pickup belongings, e.g., luggage or hats" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLAIM[+locale][+pickup][+possession]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We told John we'd meet him at the baggage claim.
            Mary recovered her glasses at the lost and found claim.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="">?</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>