<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="class-n">
    <commentary/>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a socioeconomic group of people, a social stratum" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+group][+stratum][+socioeconomic][+of_people]</commentary><examples>He grew up in a neighborhood that was mostly working class.
            Their society afforded upward mobility through the socioeconomic classes. 
            These pronunciation patterns are unique to the upper class of their society.
            The educated class finds his writing overly sentimental and lacking in nuance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="students who attend an instructional course together" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+group][+student][+attendees][+of_course][+instructional]
            Note: refers to the students taking the instruction, -not- the instructional material itself (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>The class became quiet when the principal entered the room.
            The science teacher announced, &quot;class, today we are going to learn about levers and pulleys&quot;.
            She invited her Sunday school class to a picnic at the lake.
            The class always met for beer and pizza at the student union on Friday afternoons.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an instructional event or course" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+event][+scheduled][+instructional]</commentary><examples>Quantum mechanics was the most difficult class John attended in college.
            You can take the sailing classes on weeknights or weekends.
            John is always late to class on Mondays.
            Mary took an Italian cooking class when she was in Venice.
            The class is from 2-4 on Fridays.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a collection of things defined by shared characteristics" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+collection][+with_characteristics][[+shared]
            Note: Does not rank the classes along a continuum of measurement with other classes (Sense 6)
        </commentary>
        <examples>German has three major noun classes - masculine, feminine and neuter.
            You'll need to include these Java classes to create a 3D interface for your program.
            This mathematical set forms an equivalence class because every pair of elements has an equivalence relation.
            There are three classes of solvents that would be appropriate to use for removing this paint.
            It was filed as a class action lawsuit. (on behalf of a group with a shared, common grievance which defines their 'class')
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="group of students who graduate the same year in school" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+group][+student][+with_same_year][+graduation]
            Note: the word 'year' may substitute for 'class' without loss of meaning.
        </commentary>
        <examples>Sally was in the graduating class of 1993 at Princeton.
            The class of 1986 is having its 20th reunion this year.
            Peter graduated first in his class at law school.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a ranking compared to other groups" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+quality][+comparative][+rank]
            Note: implies the existence of other classes which are ranked with respect to this one, often quantitatively
        </commentary>
        <examples>His level of chess playing is considered world class.
            Mary has moved up to the class of A-league beach volleyball.
            They traveled mostly third class on buses through South America.
            We had expected more from a first-class hotel in Manhattan.
            Billy was promoted to airman first class.
            His sailboat races in the fastest class in the regatta.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="quality of well-mannered social style or grace" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+quality][+manner][+social][+highly_commendable]</commentary><examples>Bob thinks Jane dresses with a lot of class.
            He is a class act all the way. (someone of integrity and good manners)
            They showed a lot of class in how they conducted themselves after losing the tournament.
            That guy who threw fast food trash out his car window has absolutely no class!
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a taxonomic group in biology more specific than phylum, more general than order" type="">
        <commentary>CLASS[+entity][+group][+biologic][+taxonomic][+phylum][+subordinate]
            Note: a technical biological ordering between two specific categories. 
            Note: Don't choose this sense unless it's clear that 'phylum' and/or 'order' in their technical senses are being implied as above or below 'class'.
        </commentary>
        <examples>Primates are in the class of mammals which, in turn, are in the phylum of chordata.
            Fruit flies are in the class of insects.
            How many classes are currently defined for the animal and plant kingdoms?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
            <sense group="1" n="9" name="none of the above" type="">
                <commentary>
                    Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
                </commentary>
                <examples>
                </examples>
                <mappings>
                    <wn version="3.0"/>
                    <omega/><pb/>
                    <fn/>
                </mappings>
                <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
            </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>