<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="club-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a social group, whose members share an interest or goal" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+social][+association][+membership][+interest][+shared][+recreation/+privilege/+planning]
            Note: 'club soda' was a proprietary name in the 19th century
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John was accepted to the fanciest country club in town.
            The high school chess club meets Tuesdays.
            The girl felt out of place with the hunt club crowd.
            Only members may enjoy an airline's club lounges.  (e.g., American's Admiral's Club)
            Betty made a lot of money last year with her investor's club.  (common goal is investing)
            Their nation wants to join the nuclear club. (figurative)
            Smoking is allowed in the club car.  (railroad car with an intentional club-like, privileged atmosphere)
            Pete ordered a club steak and I had a club sandwich with a club soda. (implies something fancy, privileged)
            That two-story white building near the water is our yacht club.
            The two Marines walked into the service club for a drink.
            You drive two miles east, past the tennis club, then turn right at the fork.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a sports team, a sports franchise" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+business][+franchise][+sport]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They are considered to be the best baseball club in the league this year.
            Their new rookie outfielder was drafted from a farm club.
            Their ball club may be moving to the west coast next season.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a stout stick or cudgel" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+artifact][+stick][+stout]
            [+role][+weapon]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The police used clubs to subdue the rioting crowd.
            A night stick is also called a billy club.
            This baseball bat can serve as an effective club against a home intruder.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="golf equipment" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+equipment][+golf]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John gave away his old golf clubs to his nephew.
            This club is actually called a driving iron.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a playing card of the suit of clubs" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+card][+playing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary bid five clubs in the opening hand. 
            I was out of hearts, so I put down a club.
            The magician said the three audience members were each holding a club. (a card)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a nightspot, bar, cabaret" type="">
        <commentary>
            CLUB[+business][+entertainment]
            [+building][+recreation][+public][+cabaret/+disco]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob's younger brother has performed in clubs in Las Vegas and New York.
            He met the woman at a disco club on the lower east side.
            That was a comedy club until it burned down a year ago.
            John took Mary out to a fancy supper club last night.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>