<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="comfort-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a feeling or state of contentment, relief" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMFORT[+state][+contentment]
            Note: refers to any physical or psychological sense of well-being, pleasantness
            Note: implies a recipient is experiencing contentedness
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The servant attended to our comfort in every detail.
            The thermostat is set within the comfort zone.
            We took comfort in the fact that medical help was on the way.
            This car is big enough for four adults to travel in comfort.
            The team's comfort level with the new coach is improving.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the act of providing help or aid to someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMFORT[+action][+providing][+aid]
            Note: implies an agent is administering aid to a recipient
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It is an act of treason to give comfort to the enemy in time of war.
            Her words of comfort soothed the frightened child.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="someone or something that provides contentment, solace" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMFORT[+relation][+role][+provider][+contentment]
            Note: may occur in the plural as well as singular.
            Note: refers to anything which -is- the comfort
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John's hotel had few comforts, but it was clean and inexpensive.
            His grandchildren were a comfort to him in his old age.
            Enjoy all the comforts of home anywhere you travel!
            The wintry weather made us hungry for some real comfort food.
            He found peace in the comfort of her arms.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">3,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="financial affluence" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMFORT[+state][+financial][+affluence]
            Note: refers specifically to having money, material wealth
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their father left them enough to live in comfort.	
            She had always enjoyed a life of privilege and comfort.
            The winnings were enough to keep them in comfort for years.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>