<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="commitment-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the quality of dedication, fixity of purpose" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMMITMENT[+quality][+purposive][+dedication]
            Note: focus is on an attribute of a person, their dedication.
            Note: does -not- imply an obligation (Sense 2) or a promise of contributing (Sense 3) or a consignment (Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She has exhibited great commitment to getting this project off the ground.
            They have doubts about that nation's commitment to peace.
            Only employees who show total commitment to the job will make partner in this firm.
            The company's commitment to funding research and development is beginning to pay off.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>commitment.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a state of obligation" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMMITMENT[+state][+obligation]
            Note: implies that someone/something has an obligation, whether they actually meet it or not.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We are under no commitment to take this offer.
            John has too many commitments at work and can't fulfill them all.
            They are reexamining what their commitments to their allies should be.
            I have no commitments this afternoon, so let's go sailing!
            Raising children is a major life commitment.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>commitment.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a declaration or promise, usually to contribute" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMMITMENT[+action][+declaration][+promise][+contribution]
            Note: implies a promise to contribute, it is the act of someone placing themselves under obligation, but not a pre-existing state of obligation (Sense 2)
            Note: frequently implies an agreement to contribute financially to something
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We have received financial commitments from a number of organizations.
            I can't get a commitment from Sally about whether she's coming to the company potluck.
            Make whatever commitment you can to our fund raising drive for public television.
            Congress is debating the level of troop commitment in Iraq. (what -should- the contribution be)
            He has stuck to his commitment to lower taxes. (He promised he would do so)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>commitment.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an official consignment of someone or something, as to an institution" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMMITMENT[+action][+consignment][+official]
            Note: implies placing someone or something in a location, or internment. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His commitment to a mental hospital is being challenged by his parents.
            The commitment of spent uranium to underground salt deposits is controversial.
            The prisoners have objected to their commitment to a maximum security prison.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>commitment.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>