<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="competition-n">
    <commentary>
        Merged groups 1 and 3, modified examples, added commentary. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an ongoing process of rivalry" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            COMPETITION[+activity][+ongoing][+rivalry]
            An ongoing activity of rivalry between opposing forces, e.g., businesses, organisms, ideas, teams
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In a capitalist society, competition leads to improved quality and lower costs.
            Business competition can be fiendish at times.
            A spirit of competition motivated the employees.
            Natural selection involves competition among organisms for available resources.
            John's love for Mary led to bitter competition with Jack.
            The teams were in fierce competition for first place.
            The two political parties were in competition for the hearts and minds of the voters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a contest, a specific event" type="">
        <commentary>
            COMPETITION[+event][+contest][+specific]
            Note: can be pluralized
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We held a hot-dog eating competition, and I won!
            Mary is skating in three competitions at the nationals.
            The competition ended in a dead heat.
            Jane's dog won second prize in the large breed competition.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="rival or group of rivals" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            COMPETITION[+entity][+contestant][+person/+group]
            The people who compete, either a group or an individual
            Note: whether a group or individual, occurs naturally in the singular
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He wanted to know what the competition was doing.
            John never had respect for his competition.
            Your competition in today's race will be Quickness Racer and Velocity Racer.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>