<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="conflict-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="physical battle" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONFLICT[+event]
	    An open clash between groups or individuals.  Often military-related.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Grant's army fought a decisive conflict at Chickamauga.
            The greater the conflict, the more glorious the triumph.
            Protesters occasionally came into conflict with the police.
            I was involved in several bloody conflicts in Korea.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">1,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="emotional state" type="">
        <commentary>
	    CONFLICT[+event]
	    The state of having different, incompatible ideas or feelings.  Being conflicted.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was immobilized by conflict and indecision.
            There's conflict in my heart when I think about you.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="incompatibility of ideas" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONFLICT[+event]
	    The state of several concepts, persons, ideas, or interests being opposed to one another.  Often used with schedules.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I've got a schedule conflict on Tuesday, so I'll have to cancel our meeting.
            The CEO has a conflict of interest that prevents him from making a reasonable decision.
            John felt a conflict of loyalties between his girlfriend and his boss.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">4,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="narrative drive" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The opposition between characters or forces in a work of fiction or drama; usually what drives the plot.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It seems like the major conflict is within the protagonist.
            There's not enough conflict to move the story.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="non-physical dispute" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONFLICT[+event]
	    A difference of opinion; a disagreement or argument among people.  Does not involve the event of physical violence.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            My wife and I came into conflict about what to name the baby.
            The property conflict with my neighbor lasted three years, until he took me to court.
            John and Mary saw a conflict-resolution therapist.
            The new law has set off the familiar conflict between Democrats and Republicans.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>conflict.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>