<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="consist-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="be inherent in or expressed by" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Syntax Is:	
       NP1[topic] CONSIST PP{OF/IN NP2[state]}
       NP1[topic] CONSIST PP{OF/IN NP2[attribute]}
        Note:(might be paraphrased as, &quot;Basically, NP1 is (or is due to) NP2.&quot;)
	Note: the focus is on a state or attribute inherent or central to the topic. Unlike 
        sense 2, NP2 could be considered as the key or necessary ingredient to NP1.
        NOTE: The key attribute or state mentioned (NP2) is adequate to summarize NP1 (although it may
              not be the entire content of NP1).  This is not always the case in sense 2, 
              where if only one part is mentioned, it does not adequately summarize the whole.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	The problem consisted of a torn ligament in his shoulder.
	Her popularity consists of an ability to make friends easily.
	Success will consist in our meeting the shipment date for the new product.
        The beauty of air travel consists in its speed and ease.
        For her, happiness consists in watching television and reading magazines.
        My religion consists of a humble admiration of the illimitable superior spirit...(Einstein)
        This week consists of very sad days.
        My exercise consists of another lap to the coffee pot!
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>consist.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="be composed of or be made of, as parts to a whole" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Is:	
        NP1[topic] CONSIST PP{OF NP2[attribute[plural]]}
        Note: the topic is a whole made from the parts. Unlike sense 1, the NP2s are not the
        central attributes for NP1. They are just one of the many pieces that make up NP1.
        NOTE: If the entire list of parts is given, NP1 will be completely described, but if only 
              a portion is given, NP1 is not completely described (ie, you couldn't say, &quot;Basically,
              Internet content is material unsuitable for children.&quot; That material is only a portion of the 
              content, not a defining characteristic.)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	The exhibition consists of early drawings and several large canvases by the painter.
	This simple cake consists of only flour, butter, eggs and chocolate.
	The new task team consists of two people from engineering, one from marketing and our supervisor.
        The team consists of four Europeans and two Americans.
        Apporximately 69% of all Internet content consists of material unsuitable for children.
        The CHILDES Parental Corpus consists of utterances of parents, caregivers, and experimenters.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>consist.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="match, correspond to, fit" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Is:	
        NP[target] CONSIST PP{P NP[source]}
	Note: a comparison of two things
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	His decorum does not consist with the company's policies.
	They will go along with the agenda as long as it consists with their own goals.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>