<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="consumption-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="usage" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONSUMPTION[+event]
	    The usage of something, in a general way.
	    Most economic statistics will use this sense, even when they refer to food products.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The consumption of energy has increased steadily this century.
            Rich people often engage in &quot;conspicuous consumption&quot; to show off their wealth.  
            America has a materialistic &quot;culture of consumption&quot;.
            Typically, there is no production without consumption.
            Food consumption is much higher in the United States than in South America.
            Sugar consumption is off the charts lately.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="using up" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONSUMPTION[+event]
	    Refers clearly to using up a resource or exhausting it.  Not simply using it.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The consumption of the world's oil supply will have disastrous consequences.
            Unfortunately, the complete consumption of our funding only took a few hours.
            The rate of fuel consumption is pretty high for some trucks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="bodily ingestion" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONSUMPTION[+event]
	    A special kind of usage.  The eating or drinking of a substance, or taking something into the body.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Irresponsible alcohol consumption is very bad for you.
            Some fish are not safe for human consumption.
            The consumption of red meat can lead to heart and liver problems.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="tuberculosis" type="">
        <commentary>
            An old name for the disease tuberculosis, which affects the lungs; also refers to the state of having the disease.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He caught consumption by walking through a boggy marsh.
            She has consumption and will surely die from it.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
            <fn/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>