<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="control-n">
    <commentary>
        Senses regrouped, new group added, definitions, examples and commentary modified. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a state of an authority managing or dominating a circumstance" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+state][+authority][+dominance]
            Note: the authority(agent) is often implied, rather than explicit in the sentence.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Everything is under control for our big party tonight.
            Jane disliked the assistant's apparent control of Jane's boss.
            The car spun out of control on the black ice.
            His control of the classroom only lasted fifteen minutes.
            The effective control of this disease will require educating the public. (future state)
            The control of the mob by police was admirable.
            With the resignation of our COO, Bob will take over control of the daily operations.
            Dogs must be under voice control at all times.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,5,6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>control.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="policy or guideline to constrain specified conditions or situations" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+role][+standard][+regulatory][+policy/+custom/+law]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There are few regulatory controls for construction and manufacturing in developing nations.
            The administration has instituted controls over drinking on campus.
            Nixon's price controls were an economic failure in the 1970s.
            John does not support gun control.
            Our music society has implemented strict financial controls on our annual operating budget.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,11</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="self discipline, personal restraint" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+ability][+restraint][+personal]
            discipline in personal and social activities, including physiological activities
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The timing and control of his hand movements were unimpaired.
            The baby has no control over his bowel movements.
            Tom had a difficult time gaining control over his voice after the emotional speech.
            She never lost control of herself.
            The animal lost its motor control from the disease.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="mastery or skill at something" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+ability][+skill]
            skillfulness and knowledge of some subject or activity
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A good control of French is necessary for this job.
            A great violinist must develop control of the instrument at an early age.
            The critics quipped that there was little control of the medium displayed in Jane's artwork at the gallery.
            That tenor has great breath control!  (Ability to sing long musical phrases)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a device or mechanism, e.g., a knob, dial, gear" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+artifact][+mechanism][+directing]
            a mechanism that controls the operation of a machine
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The speed control on his turntable was not working properly.
            The pilot handed the controls over to the co-pilot.
            Mary's car is equipped with cruise control.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="standard" type="Science">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+role][+standard][+experimental] 
            a standard against which other conditions can be compared in a scientific experiment
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The control was inappropriate for the conclusions he wished to draw.
            The placebo group served as the control for this medical experiment.
            What was the control group for this experiment?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="an organization that directs or manages" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+organization][+directing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mission control has started the countdown of the Shuttle.
            Air Traffic Control has cleared that plane for an emergency landing.
            The pilot asked flight control to route him through some calmer air at 27,00 feet.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">3c</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="spiritual helper" type="">
        <commentary>
            CONTROL[+individual][+spiritualist][+assistant]
            a spiritual agency that is assumed to assist the medium during a seance
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            As I align myself with Jane, my control, I hear her say &quot;George stinks&quot;.
            Mary thinks the control at our seance is a fraud.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="none of the above" type="">
        <commentary>
            Automatically generated NOTA sense (bbn)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>