<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory
  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'>
<inventory lemma="control-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="exercise power or influence over; hold within limits" type="">
      <commentary>
     Syntax Is:
      NP1 CONTROL NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Some of those operations are now controlled by Homeland Security.
         That teacher knows how to control a rowdy class.
         Are you doing all you can to control your sodium intake? 
         The skater was having trouble controlling his spins during the competition.
         He couldn't control his drinking on the job.
         The child needs to learn to control her temper.         
         We controlled the fire by dousing it with water.
         The weather controls what we do, what we eat, and what we wear.
         How do these laws control drugs and poisons?
         The company is controlled largely by foreign interests.
         Can you control the tiller while I go forward to untangle the jib?
         I love that I can finally control my Pocket PC from my desktop.
         On the inside, a control panel can be used to control the lights in the apartment.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,4,8</wn>
         <omega/><pb>control.01</pb>
         <vn>enforce-63</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="verify something by comparing to a standard" type="">
      <commentary>
      Note:  SCIENCE-Verify by conducting a parallel experiment or comparing with a set standard.
      Note:  FINANCE-Verify by using a duplicate register for comparison.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Are you controlling for temperature in this experiment?
         Effluents should be controlled for pH by neutralization. 
         The auditor controlled the physical count of inventories performed by the manager.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,6,7</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>