<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="convention-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an assembly" type="">
        <commentary>
	    CONVENTION[+event]
	    A large, typically formal assembly.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The Republican National Convention is being held in Philadelphia this year.
            John went to a comic book convention dressed as The Flash.
            The Constitutional Convention essentially created the United States as we know it.
            The convention broke down into a riot after everyone had enjoyed a few beers.
            The convention lasted for days.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="forming an assembly" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    CONVENTION[+event]
	    The act of convening or coming together into a group.  Probably a rare sense.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The first convention of our assembly took place on January 14, 1919.
            I find that the convention of two quarreling people is an important step in conflict resolution.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="normal example" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            Something regarded as normal; a pattern, rule, or formula.  
            Something that has been done before, or the expectations of a community.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Having a nameless narrator is a common literary convention.
            John went against fashion conventions by wearing a bowtie to class.
            The mores of a society are the conventions that express its fundamental values.  
            There are certain conventions that make it easier to read Java code.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="international agreement" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A diplomatic agreement that a number of countries have ratified.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The Bush Administration has called the Geneva Convention, which protects prisoners from inhumane treatment, &quot;old-fashioned&quot;.
            The United Nations promoted the Chemical Weapons Convention to limit the stockpiling of toxic substances.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="being conventional" type="">
        <commentary>
            Conventionality or conformity; the orthodoxy that comes as a result of being conventional or normal.
            A quality that a person or a thing can have.  Probably a rare usage.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I thought of myself as a person of convention.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>