<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="convey-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="express, symbolize, mean; be a medium of
expression or transmission" type="">
      <commentary>
        NOTE: compare carefully to sense 3; in this sense, the transmitted
              thing cannot be clearly said to leave the possession or
              location of NP1 (if you transfer a message or an idea, do you
              no longer have that information?--it's unclear and up for
              philosophical debate!)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The visits have conveyed the message to Central Africans that they are not abandoned.
        There was an atmosphere of excitement, which conveyed the impression that we would not have long to wait.
        Topped off with a messy ponytail, this look conveyed the cool of a New York girl.
        That one look conveyed unspoken words; words that frightened me to the core.
        Critics charge the EPA has downplayed risks and conveyed false assurances.
        Hypertension in renal allograft recipients may be conveyed by cadaveric kidneys.
        As a cartoonist, he conveyed the newspaper's political opinions to a wide audience.
        He called a press conference at which he conveyed the government's decision to repeal the law.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,5</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>convey.01</pb>
         <vn>say-37.7-1</vn><fn>Successfully_communicate_message</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="transfer location or possession" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Is:
        NP1[agent] CONVEY NP2 PP{P NP[location]}
        NP1[agent] CONVEY NP2 PP{P NP[recipient]}
        NOTE: compare carefully to sense 1; in this sense
              the conveyed object leaves the location
              or possession of NP1
        NOTE: includes legal transmission of a title or property
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The wooden plow was equipped with a seed hopper and a tube that conveyed the seed.
        Are souls conveyed thither immediately after death?
        In 1992, Patrick and his wife Joann conveyed the parcel to the defendants.
        In April of 1999, the appellant conveyed the property to the appellee.
        John de Vaux conveyed the manor to his brother Oliver.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">4,6,7</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>convey.01</pb>
         <vn>send-11.1</vn><fn>Bringing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,corvey" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>
