<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="count-v">    
   <commentary>
	Includes VPCs count_down, count_off, count_on, count_out
	Includes idiom: count_one_in
   </commentary>

   <sense group="1" n="1" name="enumerate, determine a quantity" type="">  
      <commentary>
	NP1[+agent] COUNT  NP2[topic]
	Includes: COUNT DOWN, COUNT OFF, COUNT UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	The teacher counted noses once the children were seated on the bus.
	Her baby brother can count to ten.
	The clerk counted off four yards of material from the bolt of fabric.
	They are counting down again at t minus 40 seconds.
	Mary counted up the receipts for the day.
	How do I love thee, let me count the ways.
	We couldn't count all the stars in the sky.
	Don't count your chickens before they hatch.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,4</wn>   
         <wn lemma="count_down" version="3.0">1</wn>
	 <wn lemma="count_off" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>count.01</pb>
        <vn>estimate-34.2,multiply-108</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="matter; have a value or importance" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax: NP1[theme] COUNT
        Includes: COUNT FOR
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Let your employees know that their suggestions count.
	What really counts in life is that you love your work.
        These practical walking shoes don't count for much in terms of style.
        My opinion doesn't count for anything around here.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>count.04</pb>
         <vn>matter-91</vn><fn>Importance</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="(cause to) classify, consider as, include as if by counting" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax: NP1[+/-agent] COUNT NP2 (as) (NP3)
        Includes: COUNT ONE IN, COUNT ONE OUT, COUNT FOR
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	Our department has ten staff members if you count the summer interns.
        That bag of potato chips hardly counts as a meal.
        The fact that it's his third offense will count against the defendant.
	Count me in for the company picnic next weekend.
        Definitely count me out if we have to bike to those far places.
	He counts himself lucky to have survived the accident.
	These nations had always been counted as allies in previous crises. 
	The rebate will count as taxable income.
        The professor told the students that the final exam counted for half their grade.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,5,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>count.02</pb>
         <vn>characterize-29.2,masquerade-29.6,multiply-108</vn><fn>Being_in_category,Categorization</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="depend on, expect" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Includes: COUNT ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	Mary knew she could always count on John.
	In New England you can count on a lousy spring.
	Sally's cousin is counting heavily on getting into Harvard.
	I wouldn't count on there still being cheap seats on that flight.
	Their crops count on seasonal flooding of the river.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">8,9</wn>   
         <wn lemma="count_on" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>count.03</pb>
         <vn>rely-70</vn><fn>Reliance</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>