<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="course-n">
    <commentary>
        includes idioms: in_due_course, of_course
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a series of lectures or classes on a subject, a curriculum" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+series][+lecture]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Differential geometry is a required course for a degree in cosmology.
            Architecture is not a course of study yet offered at that small private college.
            Are you planning to attend the orientation course?
            John didn't get a course credit for that class because he just audited it.
            He needs to take a refresher course in manners! (figurative, ironic)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the natural progression or development of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+action][+development][+progression]
            Note: does not imply an intentional motive, as does sense 4
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She knew many of the century's greatest writers during the course of her lifetime.
            We got to know each other in the course of working on that project together.
            Throughout the course of history wars have destroyed what civilizations have built.
            He grew weaker and thinner as the disease ran its course. (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a piece of land set aside as a facility for a sporting activity" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+physical][+grounds][+facility][+sporting]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Tom and Mary played the new championship golf course at the resort.
            We laid out a course of wickets for the children's croquet game.
            The race course at Churchill Downs is a mile and a quarter.
            They incurred a penalty for sailing outside the official course as they rounded the marker.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an intentional procedure or series of actions" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+action][+procedure][+intentional]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They have questioned the wisdom of their CEO's course of action in regards to this.
            A real change of course may be needed to get the peace process on track again.
            He is following the course of his father in becoming a physician.
            They have chosen a difficult course for their industry by encouraging these new tariffs.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the route or track along which something travels" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+form][+line][+track]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They are following the course of the hurricane on Doppler radar.
            I could see the wet trail of the snail's course across the walkway.
            Marine biologists have monitored the course of certain whales around the planet.
            Mary's daily jogging course takes her past the post office, the nail salon, and finally the bakery.
            The rocket was off course by about a mile. (an intended trajectory)
            Sally has been following the course of his meteoric career as a concert pianist. (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the orientation of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+quality][+orientation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The river takes a southern course once it traverses the plain.
            The course of the current generally follows the shoreline.
            The wind course is south by southwest.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="part of a meal, e.g. salad or dessert" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+food][+meal][+component]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob served broiled scallops for the first course.
            I ordered roast duck for my main course.
            The prix fixe menu includes three courses and a dessert.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a continuous horizontal layer of brick" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+construction][+row][+brick]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We admired the course of bricks along the top of the old Gothic-style library.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="a program of medicine doses" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+series][+dose][+medication]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She has been taking a course of antibiotics for the infection.
            The oncologist ordered a course of chemotherapy treatments for the patient.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4b</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="lowermost sail on a square-rigged mast" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+artifact][+sail][+lowermost]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The captain asked the mate to repair the torn course.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="adjacent musical strings tuned the same" type="">
        <commentary>
            COURSE[+set][+string][+adjacent][+musical]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These strings on the lute, tuned to one pitch, comprise a course.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Mac">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="after a normal passage of time" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: in_due_course
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She expects her son to finish his undergraduate degree in due course.
            In due course the competitors will figure out how to market a similar product.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">in_due_course</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="as might be expected, as normal" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: of_course
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Of course they will want to have a bite to eat before going to the show.
            Mary told us that of course we could borrow her guest cottage for the weekend.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">of_course</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>