<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="crack-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a fissure, flaw, discontinuity o a surface" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+form][+structure][+discontinuity][+fissure]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            From here you can see the cracks in the ice out on the lake.
            The antique plate had one small crack on the back side of it.
            This type of finish has intentional cracks running through it for a rustic look.
            The chess player found a crack in his opponent's defenses. (figurative extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,3,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a small space or gap" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+space][+gap][+narrow]
            Note: does -not- refer to a flaw or fissure in an otherwise continuous surface. (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We could see light coming up through the cracks between the floorboards.
            Mary left the window open a crack to let in some fresh air.
            He slipped the envelope through a crack under the door.
            His request for a transfer fell through the cracks of the big bureaucracy. (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a sudden sharp noise" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+event][+physical][+sound][+sharp][+sudden]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There was a loud crack of thunder.
            We heard the crack of gunfire during the night.
            With a crack of the whip, the coachman urged the horses forward. (a whip makes a cracking sound because the tip of it is actually traveling supersonic speeds through air - breaking the sound barrier)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crack.04</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an attempt at trying something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+action][+attempt][+beginning]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Do you want me to take a crack at this problem?
            This short story is his first crack at writing fiction. 
            He's decided to take a crack at running his father's business.
            The interns will get the first crack at the full time positions opening up next fall.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crack.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="an unkind, but often witty, remark" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+action][+utterance][+remark][+unkind][+witty]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            After a crack like that, I doubt he'll be invited to join the club.
            She ignored the rude cracks of the drunkard who was sitting on a park bench.
            Her brother always had to get in the last crack. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crack.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="cocaine in a form that can be smoked" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+entity][+substance][+cocaine][+crystal][+smokable]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            People sell crack on the street corners in this neighborhood.
            Mary read a sad children's book called 'The House that Crack Built'. 
            He said he used to smoke crack during tours. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a sharp punch or blow" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+action][+blow][+sharp]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She gave the home intruder a crack over the head with the fire poker.
            He gave the bag of ice a sharp crack on the kitchen counter.
            The drunk man tried to take a second crack at Bob in the parking lot of the theater.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="the beginning moment or instant of a temporal event" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+event][+punctual][+temporal][+beginning]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We'll have to get up at the crack of dawn to catch that plane.
            During vacation, Bob gets up at the crack of noon. (humorous extension)
            At the first crack of light, the roosters start to crow.
            Snow drops and crocuses appear at the first crack of spring in New England.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="a break in the human voice" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+quality][+break][+voice][+human]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There was a crack in her voice when she announced the layoffs.
            Sally's adolescent son is starting to develop a crack in his voice.
            The soprano's crack on the high C drew boos from the audience in the opera house.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2b</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="a deciphering or figuring out" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRACK[+event][+deciphering][+code]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The diamond thief's crack of the jewelry safe took less than a minute.
            The allies' crack of the Enigma machine gave them an important military advantage.
            They are claiming that no crack of this quantum-based encryption algorithm is possible.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>