<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="crash-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a forceful collision, an accident" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRASH[+event][+accident][+collision]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The plane made a crash landing, but everyone survived.
            I didn't see the crash although I heard it. (primarily sense 1, but implies sense 2)
            The running back  is still recovering from his crash with a linebacker in the third quarter.
            Wear a crash helmet when you ride a motorcycle.
            A five-car crash brought the commuter traffic to a halt.
            The race car went spinning through the crash barrier.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crash.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a loud sound or noise" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRASH[+event][+acoustic][+loud]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our ears were deafened by the crash of lightening.
            The crash of the symbols startled the audience.
            We heard the crash of dinner plates coming from the restaurant's kitchen. (emphasis on sound)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crash.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a sudden or rapid decline" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRASH[+event][+decline][+rapid][+business/+physiology]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The stock market crash of 1929 was the beginning of the Great Depression.
            The children are experiencing a sugar crash after eating all that candy a few hours ago.
            Over-speculation led to a crash in the Japanese real estate market during the 1980s.
            A heroin crash can be deadly for some addicts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>crash.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a computer malfunction" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CRASH[+event][+malfunction][+computer]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I have experienced some unexplained disk drive crashes this week.
            Planetary launches cannot afford to have software or hardware crashes in any system.
            After the 100th crash, John erased Windows from his disk and installed Linux.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>