<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="credit-n">
    <commentary>
        11Jan08 update to wn2.1,  split sense 1 ahouston
        12Jan08 added senses 9,10, added features, examples, modified definitions ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the act of giving acknowledgment, recognition to someone or something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+event][+communication][+acknowledgment][+for_achievement]
            Note: the act of giving recognition, not the published citations themselves (Sense 8)
            The act of giving recognition, acknowledgment for an achievement
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The inventor never received real credit for his achievements.
            We should give her credit for trying.
            Supporters said the administration should take full credit for the booming economy.
            John gets credit for identifying the problem, and Bob gets credit for solving it.
            The editors discovered that the author had taken credit for experimental work he had not actually conducted.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>credit.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a measure of personal achievement in some endeavor" type="">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quantity][+score][+achievement][+personal]
            A narrow usage, implying an additional achievement to a list
            Note: almost always in the phrase 'to X's credit'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She already had several performances to her credit.
            John was pleased to add his summer internship to his credit.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>credit.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
            
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="money returned to a financial account" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quantity][+sum][+money][+returned][+to_account]
            Note: an amount of money returned to a financial account and available for use 
            Note: implies the client owns the money, it is not additional borrowed funds (Sense 5)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The bookstore double-charged me for a book, and the credit for one of them hasn't yet appeared on my statement.
            The store gave me a credit of $100 dollars after returning my gifts. (funds returned)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>credit.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="money available to borrow" type="">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quantity][+sum][+money][+available][+for_borrowing]
            Note: implies money not belonging to a client, but which the client can borrow from another source
            money available for a client to borrow
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The bank refused to extend him a line of credit.
            I've bought all of my furniture on credit.
            The mortgage companies are lending credit at higher rates now.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a positive financial entry in a record" type="">
        <commentary>
            ENTRY[+entity][+symbolic][+entry][+financial][+positive][+in_record][+accounting]
            an accounting entry acknowledging a received sum of money
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Credit entries often have a '+' before them, while debit entries have a '-'.
            These amounts will appear as credits on the balance sheet.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="academic course units" type="College">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quantity][+measure][+unit][+academic][+of_achievement][+curriculum]
            recognition by a college or university that a course of studies has
            been successfully completed: typically measured in semester hours
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm taking 10 credits this semester.
            The students who fail this course will receive no credit for it.
            Mary needs six more credits to complete her double major.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="written or published notification of acknowledgment" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+entity][+symbolic][+notification][+published][+of_acknowledgement]
            Note: refers to actual published notes of recognition, not the act of acknowledgment (Sense 1)
            Note: often occurs in the plural form, 'credits'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We watched the credits of the film to see who performed the music in it.
            The author's credits were listed at the end of the article.
            The student's paper had no citations nor credits to previous work done on this problem.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7,8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="a source of merit, distinction" type="">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quality][+public][+distinction][+merit]
            Note: refers to a person or thing which is well regarded
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children were a credit to their school during their musical tour of Europe.
            These people were viewed as the citizens of credit and renown in their community.
            His credit with his political base has been undermined by these continuous scandals.
            The idea of intelligent design has little credit among molecular biologists.  (not well-regarded idea)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="reliability of a person to repay borrowed money" type="">
        <commentary>
            CREDIT[+quality][+financial][+soundness][+of_customer]
            Note: refers to the overall trustworthiness or reliability of a potential customer to repay borrowed money.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They will run a credit check on every new customer.
            You generally need to establish a credit history in order to apply for a home mortgage.
            The proprietress informed John that his credit was no longer good at her shop.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>