<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="crime-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an illegal or unlawful act" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRIME[+action][+illegal]
            Note: refers to something that is against the law.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Studies show a decrease in crime over the past two decades.
            He served six years in prison for a crime he did not commit.
            This legislation would reclassify these illegal acts as hate crimes.
            In that era it was not a crime to dump raw sewage into the bay. 
            He is being tried by an international tribunal for his crimes against humanity.  (illegal act against many others)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a morally repugnant act, not necessarily illegal" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRIME[+action][+repugnant][+morally]
            Note: implies that the action should be regarded as illegal, even though it is not.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It was considered a crime against civilization for the Taliban to destroy the giant Buddha statue.
            The environmentalists view this policy as a crime against the old growth forests.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an unfortunate situation" type="">
        <commentary>
            CRIME[+state][+unfortunate][+shameful/+wasteful]
            Note: usually refers to a situation or state of affairs, not a specific act.
            Note: unlike Senses 1 and 2, does not imply something of a truly serious nature.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It's a crime to waste good food, let's save it for leftovers tomorrow.
            It was a crime to visit Hawaii and spend most of the time indoors at meetings.
            It'll be an unforgivable crime if you don't visit Aunt Jane when you are in Chicago.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>