<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="crown-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="coronate" type="">  
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      The winner of today's game will be crowned the best club team in Europe.
      This bronze sculpture depicts a young athlete crowning himself. 
      America has been crowning kings ever since. 
      They're crowning the wrong person. 
      Is it time to drop the pretext of purity when crowning a beauty queen?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>crown.01</pb>
         <vn>appoint-29.1,butter-9.9,dub-29.3</vn><fn>Change_of_leadership</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="culminating event" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Republicans are rebelling against the president's crowning achievement. 
      Samaranch's hoped to crowning his 18-year-tenure with glory.  
      Crowning all this, her personal charm irradiates all her art.
      He was crowning a venture that had taken six years when disaster stuck. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>butter-9.9</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="uppermost part of" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Crenellated spires crown the Norman towers of St. Peters Cathedral.
      Calypso's magenta sepals crowned the white apron. 
      A band of dark rocks crowned the ridge.
      I could see a magenta glow crowning her head with a sickly halo. 
      Crowning the eastern slope is Mount Monah Cemetery. 
      Stork nests crown church spires and rooftops.   
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>butter-9.9</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="put an enamel cover over a tooth" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
    We wanted to wait to see if the nerve would die before crowning the tooth.
    The crowning of a tooth would most likely be contradicted by her dentist.
    The crowning of two fairly large molars is costly. 
    Therefore, posterior teeth should be crowned after root canal therapy.
    The most common method of crowning a tooth involves dental impressions.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>butter-9.9</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="congerk" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
