<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="cure-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="treat a condition completely" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The constitutional remedy cured the patient of all the disease symptoms.
        The new gene cured the disease in 12 patients, but went on to cause leukemia in three of them.
        At any rate, the lesson cured him of his laziness.
        I don't know if it cured her of biting, but it cured her of biting Mike.
        The roots of Artichokes smeared on, does not only cure the ill scent of armpits, but of the whole body also.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>cure.01</pb>
         <vn>cheat-10.6,free-80-1</vn><fn>Cure</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="preserve, pickle" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Whisk in prepared mustard to taste and use this liquid to cure fruit.
        Dad always sugar-cured the hams and bacon and sometimes the shoulders.
        To dry cure the ham butt, apply 2 tablespoons of Tender-Quick for each pound.
        Does anyone grow it for culinary purposes and if so how do you cure the berries?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>cure.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Preserving</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="prepare, make usable" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        After it is cured, the resin can be abraded and polished as necessary.
        The amount of water present need only be sufficient to cure the cement.
        Curing the soap can take anywhere from 4-8 weeks depending on the soap!
        After curing the clay, soaking the image, and placing it on the clay glue side up, I cured the piece.
        My Aunt had been a milliner, and she cured the skins and made gloves.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Preserving</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,greenlm" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>