<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="deepen-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="intensify, make or become stronger" type="">  
      <commentary>
       Syntax Is:
        NP1 DEEPEN (NP2)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This event only deepened my convictions.
        A rebel leader deepened the crisis in eastern Uzbekistan by announcing an Islamic uprising in his border town.
        No Child Left Behind has deepened the need to communicate effectively.
        She said the cancer diagnosis had deepened her faith in God and in others.
        The chaos deepened despite the promise of 1400 National Guardsmen a day to stop the looting.
        The California energy crisis was deepened by the bankruptcy filing of a utility company.
        Misery deepened for Georgians on Thursday, as millions were without power.
        The color deepened a bit, but not much.
        The color deepened a shade in Christie's cheek, but she went on with no other sign of shyness.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="make or become deeper" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is:
        NP1 DEEPEN NP2[patient[concrete]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        To provide sufficient depth for boating and fishing, approximately 25% of the lake basin was deepened to a depth of over ten feet.
        During the last 10000 years or so, the river has not deepened the gorge very much.
        As the miner's pit was deepened, new exposure was available for sampling.
        Next the cavity was deepened until only 3/8&quot; remained on the top surface.
        A second incision is made in the abdomen and deepened to open into the peritoneal cavity.
        This $196 million proposal plans to deepen the Columbia River channel.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>deepen.01</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="3" name="lower in tone" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Her voice deepened when she whispered the password.
        His voice deepened and went husky.
        In her later years, Vaughan's voice deepened significantly, yet it remained a remarkable instrument.
        In the past couple of years, his tone has deepened, his soloing has become at once more assured and adventurous.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>