<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="determination-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="deciding" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    DETERMINATION[+event]
	    The act of determining the properties of something, or the act of reaching a decision about something
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The supercomputer attempted a determination of the exact value of pi.
            Has the panel reached a determination?
            The Library of Congress published a determination of the rates and values of recordings.
            The jury's determination of a verdict will occur tomorrow.
            Your genetic code is responsible for the determination of your sex.
            Self-determination is a right of every American citizen.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1 4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="quality of being determined" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A personal quality that somebody can have; namely, the quality of being a determined, steadfast, resolute person.
            The quality of being determined to do something-- does not apply to a specific thing that a person wants to do.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            President Bush praised the determination of the Slavic people.
            John shows such determination when he's running the marathon!
            My strongest assets as an employee are my persistence and determination.
            Seeing my father in the stands filled me with determination.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="desire to do something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            An opinion, position, or judgment, or a desire to do something.
            Appears most often with &quot;to&quot;.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The employee has a determination to succeed.
            The determination of the mountain climbers to reach the summit kept them going through rough weather.
            John shows such a determination to win when he's running the marathon!
            &quot;For my determination is to gather the nations,&quot; said the Lord.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>