<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="difference-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the quality of dissimilarity" type="">
        <commentary>
            DIFFERENCE[+quality][-similarity]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We discussed similarities and differences between French and California wines.
            The jeweler could easily tell the difference between the diamond and the zirconian earrings.
            There is almost no difference between these two shades of blue.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a degree of variation or variability" type="">
        <commentary>
            DIFFERENCE[+quantity][+degree][+variability]
            Note: implies the existence of a norm around which the values can vary.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The differences in the results across ten experiments were quite small.
            They can't eliminate all differences in color across different dye lots.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a dispute, conflict or disagreement" type="">
        <commentary>
            DIFFERENCE[+state][+dispute]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The couple put aside their differences and decided not to divorce.
            These nations' differences may be too deep to hope for a lasting peace.
            She's a good manager who quickly resolves differences that arise in the workplace. 
            John and Mary have a major difference of opinion about many political issues. (idiomatic usage)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a state of detectable change" type="">
        <commentary>
            DIFFERENCE[+state][+change][+detectable]
            Note: implies change in a given direction, often stable (not fluctuation around a norm, see sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            What a difference a good night's sleep makes!
            This after-school program has made a difference in the lives of many children.
            It makes no difference to John what time we go to dinner this evening.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="arithmetic or numerical remainder" type="">
        <commentary>
            DIFFERENCE[+quantity][+remainder][+arithmetic]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The difference between 10 and 6 is 4.
            The gross margin is the difference between the selling price and the total cost of producing the goods.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>