<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="direct-v">
   <commentary>
    No VPC to add
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="order, guide, or dictate with the authority to do so" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax Is: 
       NP1[agent] DIRECT NP2[patient] (ADVP)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       The commander has directed the troops to evacuate the flood victims.
       Mary is directing a documentary about windsurfing.
       Who directs the new product division?
       Toscanini directed his orchestra with an iron hand.
       They think one terrorist group has directed most of these attacks.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3,4,8,13</wn>
         <omega/><pb>direct.01</pb>
         <vn>performance-26.7-1</vn><fn>Behind_the_scenes</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="purposefully aim, cause to move" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] DIRECT NP2[instrument] PP{P NP[target]}
        NP1[agent] DIRECT NP2[patient[abstract]] PP{P NP[target]}
        NP1[instrument] DIRECT NP2[patient]
        NP1[agent] DIRECT NP2[patient]
        Note: implies motion, sometimes literal, sometimes figurative
        Note: includes directing emotions at others
        Note: implies that something is being directed by an agent or instrument toward something/someone
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The robber directed a gun at John's head.
        The camera was directed at the athlete's feet.
        The industry has been directing its attention on foreign competition.
        Can you please direct me to the nearest gas station?
        Those ads are directed primarily at pre-teens.
        She is trying to direct her teenaged daughter towards more intellectual pursuits.
        The naughty dog was directed into the backyard by the scruff of his neck.
        With a mighty swing, the batter directed the ball past the outfield and over the left wall of the stadium.
        Don't direct your anger at the townspeople, they are not responsible.
        In her early career, she directed her energies towards functional pottery with painted surfaces.
        Initially she directed her efforts towards the implementation of the new program.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,5,6,7,9,10,11</wn>
         <omega/><pb>direct.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
      <sense group="1" n="3" name="label something" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I directed the envelope 'Office of the President'.
        Jane directed all her wedding invitations with gold ink.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>