<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="discipline-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a field of study, a domain of knowledge" type="">
        <commentary>
            DISCIPLINE[+entity][+symbolic][+domain][+knowledge][+science/+medicine/+literature]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The discipline of molecular biology has advanced enormously in recent decades.
            Sociology is a fairly new discipline.
            He is pursuing the scholarly discipline of Indo-European philology.
            Those disciplines are taught only at the graduate level.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the trail of focused, controlled behavior" type="">
        <commentary>
            DISCIPLINE[+quality][+behavior][+controlled][+intentionally]
            Note: refers to a quality possessed by the subject, not an external system or domain
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These modern dancers do not exhibit the discipline of the Russian ballerinas. 
            The troops showed great discipline on the battlefield.
            It took more discipline than Mary had to stick with her austere and boring weight-loss diet.
            He was able to maintain discipline among his soldiers. (keep them in that state of behavior)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="training or guidance to improve a skill or ability" type="">
        <commentary>
            DISCIPLINE[+activity][+training][+guidance]
            Note: implies someone or something is providing the training
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Many parents would like the public schools to exert more discipline over the students.
            The dogs were provided with discipline to learn good off-leash manners. 
            He quickly experienced the discipline of prison life. (somewhat ironic)
            A storm at sea will offer you a lot of discipline in the art of sailing.
            They don't give the children much discipline at that daycare center.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the act of punishment" type="">
        <commentary>
            DISCIPLINE[+activity][+punishment]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            No form of corporal discipline was allowed at that school. (spanking, slapping, whipping, etc.)
            Mary thinks the offenders deserved the harsh discipline they received.
            The pranksters received no discipline whatsoever for spraying graffiti on the walls of the school.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>