<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="dry-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) lose moisture" type="">
      <commentary>
     Note: Does not imply a loss of productivity.
     </commentary>
      <examples>
        A dry wind came and dried up the crops.
        Scientists have finally found out how the Ice Age in Europe dried up the West African monsoons.
        The plant has turned yellow and has dried out.
        The hot dry sand and the warm desert winds quickly dried out the body so it did not decay.
        The eye cream dried out the skin around my eyes. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <wn lemma="dry_out" version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="dry_up" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4-1</vn><fn>Cause_to_be_dry</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="(cause to) become unavailable or unproductive" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: DRY OUT, DRY UP; does not imply a loss of moisture. 
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        When the tech bubble burst, contract work dried up and he was among thousands without a job.
        But they cannot pay what they don't have since a famine has dried out all resources. 
        The Vegas show fell through, which pretty much dried up our funds.
        All my possible excuses to delay my recovery have dried up.
        My ideas dried up, and I needed to reinvent myself.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>dry.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="become sober" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: DRY OUT, DRY UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This addiction would pursue me, even if I dried up temporarily.
        Many times he sought help, dried out, and wouldn't drink for six months or more.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="preserve (fruits, meats, etc)" type="">
      <commentary>
     Note: Compare to Sense 1: loss of moisture is designed to preserve the object.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        They ate it fresh when ripe and also dried the fruit to consume during winter.
        They dried meats back in the day because they had no choice.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Preserving</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,corvey" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>