<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="emerge-v">    
   <commentary>
	No VPCs to add
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="issue forth from; exit or come from somewhere" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Includes:
        NP1[topic] EMERGE (ADVP) PP[location]
        NP1[topic] EMERGE (ADVP) PP[temporal] 
        Note: can be used metaphorically
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
	The Bengal tiger emerged from the forest. 
	I couldn't believe the imperious stream of words emerging from her lips. 
	The fugitive emerged from hiding after ten years. 
	Some new fiscal problems are emerging on the horizon. (metaphoric)
	Jealousy emerged in his heart at the sight of Mary dancing with Bob.
	Some fruitful discussions emerged during those weekly meetings.
	He always emerges from his house at six o'clock sharp.
        They have emerged intact from their recent bankruptcy
        Jane has not emerged without scars from the ordeal.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>emerge.01</pb>
         <vn>appear-48.1.1</vn><fn>Departing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="develop or surface (as); become known or perceived (as)" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1[topic] EMERGE (PP)
	Note: links NP with a quality of the NP, not the location of the NP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	He is quickly emerging as the leading candidate of their party.
	This stock has emerged as the one to buy in recent weeks.
        India has emerged as the most attractive global retail destination for a second straight year.
        Palestinian Islamic Jihad emerged in the early 1980s.
        The tourism report emerged from four studies over a three year period.
        But the next day, when the fog has lifted, a starkly different image emerges.
        The facts behind the scandal are sure to emerge eventually.
        It has emerged that secret talks had been going on between the two companies.
        She's the most exciting British singer to emerge on the pop scene for a decade.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>emerge.02</pb>
         <vn>appear-48.1.1</vn><fn>Coming_to_be</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>