<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="establish-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="found or institute something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] ESTABLISH NP2
        Note: NP2 is a (somewhat) permanent institution, process, or rule
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         He established a food bank in his town.
         The university is going to establish a department of interactive media.
         Let's establish some ground rules before we begin.
         Critical limits must be established for each CCP identified in the hazard analysis.
         It is incumbent upon libraries to understand the rules, establish internal mechanisms for compliance, and monitor these activities.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>establish.01</pb>
         <vn>establish-55.5-1</vn><fn>Intentionally_create</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="prove, justify or demonstrate the validity of something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 ESTABLISH NP2[abstract]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Researchers haven't yet established a cause-effect link.
         This cancelled check establishes the fact that she did pay that bill.
         This theory of global warming is established only on data from the past ten years.
         His reputation as a brilliant doctor has been established by his patients' survival rates.
         His work for the magazine established him as one of the greatest photographers of the decade.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,8,7</wn>
         <omega/><pb>establish.01</pb>
         <vn>base-97.1,indicate-78-1-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="bring about an effect" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 ESTABLISH NP2
        Note: NP2 is a feature or effect
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Our centralized grid system and the environmental consequences of fossil fuel production have established a ripple effect.
         The trompe l'oeil-illusion establishes depth.
         Using cream in the sauce will establish a smooth texture.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>establish.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="to install or set up in a place or situation" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 ESTABLISH NP2
        Note: NP2 is generally reflexive. 
        Note: NP2 has been already instituted or already exists. All NP1 is doing is
        locating or installing into NP2.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Economic exiles from expensive Aspen are establishing themselves in Basalt, Colo.
         Widespread pests quickly establish themselves in ecologically disturbed communities.
         Paige Rowland has established herself in the industry as an intelligent and hard-working performer.
         We finally got established at our new digs after the long flight.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>establish.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,brownsw,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>