<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="event-n">
    <commentary>
        7nov06 - update to wn2.1, added features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a recognized social, purposeful gathering" type="">
        <commentary>
	    EVENT[+event][+activity][+demarcated][+temporally][+social][+gathering][+purposeful][+celebration/+competition/+entertainment]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The event is open to the public.
            Her holiday open house is always -the- event of the season.
            Parking for this event will cost $20.
            John is competing in two different events in the nationals.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a happening or incident of human significance" type="">
        <commentary>
	    EVENT[+event][+occurrence][+incident][+meaningful][+social]
	    happenings, incidents revolving around humans, having social significance
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Events developed rapidly in the days following the president's admission of guilt.
            This latest event in the Middle East has eclipsed the developing story in North Korea.
            That unfortunate event at work was caused largely by John's inability to be discreet.
            The years in France had included many of the happiest events of her life.
            The CEO's sudden death from a heart attack was an unforeseen event.
            These safety measures have reduced the incident of such events in the work place.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="any physical occurrence perceived by an observer" type="">
        <commentary>
	    EVENT[+event][+occurrence][+physical][+perceived]
	    Note: these events do not revolve around human activity
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The coin was tossed thirty times and 19 of the events were heads up.
            This study reports on metabolic events in synchronized cell cultures of Acer pseudoplatanus L.
            The event horizon defines a boundary surrounding a black hole past which no information can be accessed by an outside observer.
            One consequence of special relativity is that two events appearing as simultaneous to one observer may appear at different times to another observer.
            These tracks indicate events of high energy particles colliding with other particles.
            Some significant geological event of the past caused the upthrust of this mountain chain.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="in case of" type="">
        <commentary>
            idiomatic usage
            Note: functions as a quantifier adjunct to a noun
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In the event of fire, do not use the elevator.
            The picnic will be postponed to next week in the event of rain.
            In the event that an attack is launched, the defenders will have been significantly weakened by preceding air attacks. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">idiom</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="consequently" type="">
        <commentary>
            idiomatic usage
            Note: functions as an adverbial phrase
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In any event, be sure to call us when you get there.
            At all events, they decided to anchor the boat and wait out the storm.
            In that event, the U.S. would incline towards a lifting of the arms embargo.  
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">idiom</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>