<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="exposure-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a living being's subjection to prolonged harmful weather conditions" type="">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+state][+physical][+subjection][+prolonged][+weather][+harmful]
            Note: 'exposure' in this sense occurs alone without prepositional phrase that identifies an agent, the agent is always understood to be adverse weather conditions.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The two climbers died from exposure near the summit of the mountain.
            They got heatstroke from exposure while trekking across the desert during midday. 
            Without the warmth of their mother, the baby squirrels could die of exposure.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the event of being subjected to a harmful agent" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+event][+physical][+subjection][+to_agent][+harmful]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They argue that the dangers posed by exposure to asbestos have been overstated.
            The lawn furniture cushions have faded from long exposure to the summer sun.
            The mother tried to protect her retarded son from exposure to ridicule.
            These health care workers risk exposure to a dangerous flu virus.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>exposure.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="state of being financially vulnerable to an economic downturn" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+state][+financial][+vulnerability][+downturn][+economic]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Can John risk the exposure of having all his savings invested in the stock of one company?
            These firms invest in hedge funds to limit their exposure to currency devaluations.
            A balanced portfolio can reduce your exposure to market fluctuations.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the act of having contact, familiarity with some knowledge domain" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+activity][+interaction][+familiarity][+with_content][+domain][+knowledge]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My parents gave me a broad exposure to the theater and the arts.
            She is concerned about the potential exposure of children to pornography on the Internet.
            His exposure to the European banking system makes him an excellent candidate for this job.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a disclosure or uncovering, revealing something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+event][+communication][+social][+disclosure][+pejorative]
            Note: has a pejorative tone (opposite of Sense 7)
            Note: implies subject is target of the revelation, 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The politician feared exposure of his extramarital affair during the campaign.
            Her exposure as a foreign spy made headlines in the news today.
            They wanted to avoid an exposure of their past.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a physical orientation, location or setting" type="">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+location][+physical][+orientation][+directional]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This artist loft has a nice northern exposure through this window.
            The exposure of the new building is a gentle slope to the southeast.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="receiving beneficial publicity, attention" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+event][+social][+communication][+publicity][+beneficial]
            Note: implies subject is recipient of the publicity -&gt;  X[+recipient] need/get EXPOSURE 
            Note: opposite of Sense 5
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The young actor got a lot of exposure from his role in that new film.
            A politician needs a lot of public exposure in order to win an election.
            Mary thinks she'll get more exposure in her new position as marketing director.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2a</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a unit of photographic film" type="">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+entity][+artifact][+unit][+film][+photographic]
            Note: refers to a physical bit of photographic film
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There are 24 exposures on this roll of film.
            Here is an exposure I took of Bob in front of the summer cottage last year.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="the amount of light allowed to strike photographic film" type="">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+quantity][+intensity][+light][+absorbed][+on_film]
            [+event][+physical][+striking][+light][+on_film]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You'll need a long exposure in this light to get a good picture of the lake.
            This camera has different F-stops for different exposures.
            The photographer described the exposure he used to create the atmospheric landscape of the desert.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="physical geographical structures that are visible" type="">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+entity][+geological][+structure][+visible]
            Note: refers to physical structures in the world
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The pilot pointed out large ice exposures on the small islands.
            The exposure of the rock face revealed twisted layers of sedimentary composition.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1b</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="the act of physically uncovering or displaying something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            EXPOSURE[+event][+physical][+revealing][+entity]
            Note: implies an agent is exposing -&gt; X's{+agent} EXPOSURE OF Y{+patient/+result}
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The surgeon's exposure of the left lung revealed a large undifferentiated mass, probably malignant.
            The man has a history of arrests for exposure of his private parts in public parks and shopping malls.
            These animals will react to any exposure of fear on your face, so try to project confidence around them.
            The church does not permit exposure of bare heads in the main sanctuary.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>