<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="extend-v">
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) lengthen or stretch out in space" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       He extended one foot into the water.
       Let's extend our right arms over our heads.
       Would you mind extending the TV antenna?
       I can't seem to extend the legs of this folding table.
       The train service doesn't yet extend to the outer suburbs.
       His property extends to the stone wall over there.
       The epidemic currently extends from Malyasia to Singapore.
       We saw the rock that was extending in the river just before we collided with it.
       The emperor has been extending his empire to the west.
       The civil war extended into the neighboring province.
       Mosquitos have extended malaria onto the islands off the mainland.
       We can extend the stew by adding some more potatoes and carrots.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,5,6,8,11,16,17</wn>
         <omega/><pb>extend.01</pb>
         <vn>exist-47.1-1</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="(cause to) lengthen or expand in time or some abstract realm" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       I'll need to extend my stay for two more days.
       They suggested that the existing freeze be lifted and the period extended from one year to 15 months.
       Deregulation is also a megatrend that will probably extend into the twenty-first century. 
       The full destructive impact of the war extended to Iraqi civil infrastructure. 
       That tax law was extended to now include S corporations as well.
       The governor is attempting to extend his influence as far as possible.
       Travelling to Asia extended John's horizons.
       The military's goal of morale through knowledge of the facts extended into army hospitals.
       The investor has extended his offer of $20 a share until midnight tomorrow.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,9,10,15</wn>
         <omega/><pb>extend.01</pb>
         <vn>exist-47.1-1</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="offer or make available" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] EXTEND NP2[recipient] NP3[patient]
        NP1[agent] EXTEND NP2[patient] PP{to NP[recipient]}
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       The bank has extended him credit to start his company.
       I would like to extend my congratulations to you.
       Are they extending an apology to her?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,7</wn>
         <omega/><pb>extend.02</pb>
         <vn>contribute-13.2-2,future_having-13.3</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="exert something" type="">
      <commentary>
       Includes: EXTEND ONESELF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       He told the jockey to go ahead and extend the colt on the back stretch.
       Mary really extended herself to pass the advanced class in quantum mechanics.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">12,14</wn>
         <wn lemma="extend_oneself" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>extend.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston, duffielc,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>