<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="face-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the front of a head, human or animal" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+entity][+structure][+anatomical][+head][+front][+animal][+human]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They use models with very beautiful faces to advertise cosmetics.
            Mary thought the koala bear had a cute face.
            The face of the victim was beaten beyond recognition.
            Betty told Sue to get out of her face. (figurative usage)
            The soldiers were very brave in the face of danger. (metaphoric extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a referent to a whole person" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+entity][+person]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I saw many familiar faces at the conference.
            Jane is tired of seeing the same old faces each week at the social mixer.
            We didn't see one familiar face in the crowd.  
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a specific expression or look" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+quality][+expression][+physical][+specific][+happy/+angry/+sad/+shocked]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There were a lot of smiling faces at work today when our stock rose 20 percent. 
            The child made a face after sucking the sour lemon.
            Put on a happy face!
            We all had sad faces after our team lost the playoffs.
            Pete simmered at Judy's gloating face in the corridor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a side or surface of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+entity][+object][+side]
            Note: often refers to the visible, or sometimes the important, side of something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John looked up at the face of the clock to see what time it was.
            She dealt the cards face down.
            These special dice have eight faces on them, not six.
            The climbers are attempting the north face of the mountain.
            The face of this building has decorative brickwork. 
            When he flipped the coin, it landed face up.
            One face of the moon is always oriented away from the earth.
            Mary sewed the sequins onto the face of the cloth. (on the side to be shown)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,8,13</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the apparent condition or state of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+state][+condition][+apparent]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The face of the city has changed a lot over the past two decades.
            The dealer said the face value of this antique vase is $300.
            On the face of it, I'd say we are through the worst of the crisis.
            They have put on a brave face throughout this ordeal. (figurative, a front, not a facial expression)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a style and size of typeset" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+quality][+style][+type]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The chapter headings are all in bold face.
            Use a smaller face, say 8 point, to fit all the text on one page.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="social stature" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+state][+social][+stature]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The president backed down on the issue, allowing the prime minister to save face.
            Their firm has lost face because of this scandal.
            Mary just ignored his social gaffe, saving face for him.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="the striking surface of a tool or implement" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+entity][+structure][+component][+tool][+surface][+striking]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Center the face of the hammer over the nail and strike it hard.
            Dig the dirt towards you, dragging the face of the hoe smoothly.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="boldness, audacity, nerve" type="">
        <commentary>
            FACE[+quality][+personality][+boldness]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The teacher couldn't believe the student's face to tell him off that way. 
            What face!
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>