<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="failure-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an unsuccessful effort to do something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+action][+effort][-successful]
            Note: nominalization - his failure to win - he failed to win
            Note: implies an attempt was made, but did not succeed
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We were all shocked at John's failure of the entrance exam.
            Their failure to agree on a treaty has led to another outbreak of violence in the region.
            His failure to win the primary made him decide to drop out of the race.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a deficiency, state of disappointment, non-achievement" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+state][+deficiency][+goal]
            Note: refers to a resulting or existing state, not an action that fails (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Are all our efforts going to be doomed to failure?
            The drought has caused widespread crop failures.
            The company has learned from its previous failures and has gained some market share.
            They have finally realized that their marriage is a failure.
            Critics said the soprano's operatic debut was not a total failure.
            The dinner was a failure because the roast was overcooked.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a person who is a non-starter, non-achiever" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+entity][+person][-achiever]
            Note: refers to a person
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary would never tell Bob that he was a failure as a father.
            Bob felt like a failure when he got laid off from his job.
            Both artists were failures in their own lifetimes and only appreciated much later.
            This greyhound was a failure on the race tracks. (extension to animals)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a state of omission, lacking" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+state][+omission]
            Note: Implies an effort was -not- attempted, so opposite of Sense 1
            Nominalization:  their failure to call us - they failed to call us
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their failure to return our call was perceived as a lack of interest.
            The company is being sued for failure to comply with certain safety regulations.
            The country's failure to perceive the growing menace may end in disaster.
            The only thing holding them back is a failure of imagination.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a bankruptcy, financial insolvency" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+state][+financial][+bankruptcy]
            Note: a specialized sense referring to legal bankruptcy
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Economists have noted an increasing number of bank failures this quarter.
            John gave up on the restaurant business after two business failures.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a loss of function" type="">
        <commentary>
            FAILURE[+state][+loss][+function]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The coroner determined the cause of death was heart failure.
            Several cities had power failures from the ice storm.
            Hallucinations can actually be a symptom of kidney failure.
            The plane made an emergency landing after an engine failure.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>