<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="fear-v">    
   <commentary>
	No VPCs to add
        Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="feel scared, in danger, or frightened" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1[experiencer] FEAR NP2[stimulus]
        Note: This sense implies a more specific version of sense 2. That is, one who is 
        scared or frightened will most likely also be anxious, uneasy or apprehensive about 
        the very thing they fear. But this sense implies feeling scared and in danger, 
        which second sense lacks.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	That child greatly fears dogs.
	Do you think the suicide bomber feared her death?
	Bob has always feared his mother's alcoholic rages.
        We huddled together, fearing we might be killed.
       </examples>    
       <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fear.01</pb>
         <vn>admire-31.2-1</vn><fn>Experiencer_subj</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="feel anxious, concerned, uneasy, or apprehensive about" type="">
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1[experiencer] FEAR [stimulus]
	Note: implies an ongoing low-grade contemplative anxiety. See note in sense 1.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	She fears her son is not doing his assignments on time.
	Some fear that a sharp decline in real estate prices is coming.
	John fears his roof may not last another winter.
	These companies fear increased competition from overseas.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fear.01</pb>
         <vn>admire-31.2-1,marvel-31.3-3</vn><fn>Experiencer_subj</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="regard with feelings of reverence or respect" type="">
      <commentary>
        Note: Use: Generally this sense is used in relation to a deity or a position of power/honor.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She was taught by her grandmother to fear the kitchen god.
        The men quickly learned to fear the King, for they saw in him god's own wisdom and judgement.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fear.01</pb>
         <vn>admire-31.2-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="be sorry about or regret" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1[experiencer] FEAR [stimulus]
	Note: an expression of regret or apology.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	I fear I left my passport in the top drawer of my desk.
	I'll buy her book, but I fear it won't be the hardback version.
	Mary said she feared all there was to serve us were some cold leftovers.
	I fear my favorite old shoes have finally worn out.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>