<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="field-n">
    <commentary>
        
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="plain" type="">
        <commentary>
            a piece of land, cleared of trees and usually enclosed
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He planted a field of wheat.
            They emerged from the woods onto a vast open plain.
            He longed for the fields of his youth.
            No, Diamonds don't grow in diamond fields of South Africa.
            Try to land the plane in the landing field this time, Captain Bob.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">1 9 14 17</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="not the lab" type="">
        <commentary>
            somewhere (away from a studio or office or library or laboratory)
            where work is done or data is collected, usually preceded
            by &quot;the&quot;
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Anthropologists do much of their work in the field.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="discipline" type="">
        <commentary>
            subject, subject area, subject field, field of study, study, branch of
            knowledge, line of business, sphere, domain, orbit, arena - a branch
            of knowledge, a commercial enterprise, or a walk of life
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In what discipline is his doctorate?
            Teachers should be well trained in their subject.
            Anthropology is the study of human beings.
            They are outstanding in their field.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">4 6 7</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="battleground" type="Combat">
        <commentary>
            a region where a battle is being (or has been) fought
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They made a tour of Civil War battlefields.
            The army was in the field awaiting action.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">2 11</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="force field" type="Physics">
        <commentary>
            The space around a radiating body within which its electromagnetic
            oscillations can exert force on another similar body not in contact
            with it
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The magnetic field produced a force on the wire perpendicular to its current.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="playing area" type="Sports">
        <commentary>
            a piece of land prepared for playing a game
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The home crowd cheered when Princeton took the field.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="set" type="Mathematics">
        <commentary>
            a set of elements such that addition and multiplication are
            commutative and associative and multiplication is distributive over
            addition and there are two elements 0 and 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The set of all rational numbers is a field.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">10</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="contestants" type="">
        <commentary>
            all of the competitors in a particular contest or sporting event
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The field consisted of 7, including the Kentucky Derby winner.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">12 13</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="characters" type="Computer Science">
        <commentary>
            a set of one or more adjacent characters comprising a unit of information
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A bit field is a field containing only binary characters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">15</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="vision" type="">
        <commentary>
            &quot;field of view&quot;, the area that is visible (as through an optical instrument)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The operative field is the area that is open during surgery.
            Sally saw germs in the microscopic field.
            George heard barking nearby as the cat ran across his field of vision.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">16</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>