<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="fight-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a brief physical exchange of blows between people" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            FIGHT[+activity][+brief][+physical][+exchange][+blows]
            Note: refers to brief, isolated cases of physical confrontation between individuals.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A fight broke out in the stadium after a bad call by the umpire.
            The children were having a pillow fight.
            John had to break up a dog fight in the park.
            The boys got into a fist fight at school.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fight.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a battle, an ongoing struggle" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            FIGHT[+activity][+ongoing][+struggle][+physical][+military]
            FIGHT[+activity][+ongoing][+struggle][+physical][+illness]
            FIGHT[+activity][+ongoing][+struggle][+social][+campaign]
            Note: implies a long-term struggle, involving physical actions and/or social ones.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The fight for the city lasted three days with 10,000 dead or wounded.
            The custody fight over the children became nasty.
            Sadly, Betty's mother lost her fight against ovarian cancer.
            He has led many fights for social justice during his life.
            It is a fight for the very survival of that nation.
            There is expected to be a long and bitter fight in congress over this bill. (Also Sense 3)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fight.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an intense emotional argument" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            FIGHT[+activity][+argument][+emotional][+intense]
            Note: implies heated verbal exchanges, not physical blows
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She wanted to avoid a fight with the other board directors concerning the new policy.
            Mary and her sister had a big fight last night about who should host Thanksgiving this year.
            The child's fights with his parents in public usually ended with him getting his way.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fight.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a sporting match, boxing" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGHT[+event][+public][+sports][+match][+boxing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We watched the fight on television between the heavyweight champion and his contender.
            John and Bob got ringside seats to the fight at Madison Square Garden.
            This boxer has won about 70 percent of his fights.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="aggressive willingness to battle, pugnaciousness" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGHT[+quality][+disposition][+pugnacious]
            Note: describes the willingness of someone to engage in battle, not the battle itself
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They still have a lot of fight in them despite losing the game today.
            Cindy felt the fight drain out of her by the end of the day.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>