<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="figure-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a 2-dimensional representation, a drawing, illustration, design pattern" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+physical][+representation][+2D]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This figure shows the change in earnings over the past twelve quarters.
            The figures in the book will help explain the process more graphically.
            The children drew figures of triangles, circles, parabolas and parallelograms.
            Susan painted figures of birds and flowers on my dining room wall.
            The petroglyphs  were stick figures and circles drawn on volcanic rocks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,6,12</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a body or form, an observable intact entity" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+physical][+body][+existent]
            Note: the figure does NOT imply a reference to some separate entity, it -is- the entity.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John thinks Mary has a great figure.
            The figure of a great white shark loomed up out of the depths beyond the reef.
            They remember the figure of a man standing in the shadows near the library.
            The figures of starving children from her visit abroad still haunted her thoughts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,11</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a quantity expressed as a number" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+quantity][+number]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm going to write down a figure between one and ten and you have to guess which one.
            The firm's accounting firm attested that the figures for last year are correct.
            He quoted me a figure of two thousand dollars.
            The projected figures for the deficit are larger than expected.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,7,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a 3-dimensional representation of a body" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+physical][+representation][+3D][+model]
            Note: the figure implies reference to some other object, on which it is modelled.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sally made a beautiful horse figure out of clay.
            They are studying solid figures in geometry class.
            His cast bronze figures of nudes are among the most famous.
            She gave the children some glass figures of animals to play with.
            We admired the terminal figures of lions on the old Roman columns.
            These wax figures seem all too real to me.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a person of influence or public prominence" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+person][+influential]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He has been a major figure in public policy for years.
            Mary dislikes being an authority figure at her company.
            We read about the giant literary figures of the nineteenth century.
            The child looked up to John as a father figure.
            The old professor was a beloved figure on campus.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a metaphoric literary device, a trope" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+language][+device][+metaphoric]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The foreigner didn't understand all the figures of speech we were using.
            'Easy as pie' is a figure of speech.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="an impression or overall quality possessed by something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+quality][+impression][+perceptual]
            Note: This may be a metaphoric extension of Sense 2
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Don't they cut a pretty figure on the dance floor?
            John makes quite the rugged figure in his mountain climbing gear.
            I must have been a sorry figure straggling into the hotel, all wet and muddy.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a sequence of movements or gestures through time" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIGURE[+activity][+movement][+sequence]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The new dancer did the figures beautifully during her audition.
            The skaters must complete four different sets of figures in the competition.
            She is the best figure skater in the world.
            These five notes actually constitute a figure within the three-measure melody
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">13</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>