<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="fill-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="To make or become full, as in a physical container" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] FILL NP2[patient] (PP{P NP[theme]})
        NP1[theme] FILL NP2[patient]
        NP1 FILL
        Note: May be used in a literal OR metaphorical sense
        Includes: FILL UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Please fill this container.
        Her praise filled the child with pride.  (metaphoric extension)
        The dentist filled the cavity.
        You've filled the space with great ideas!
        I filled the beaker with boiling water and waited for the coffee to brew.
        They filled the hole with dirt.
        The liquid fills the container.
        The pool filled slowly with water.
        The theater quickly filled up.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,9</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_up" version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fill.01,fill.02</pb>
         <vn>contiguous_location-47.8,fill-9.8,other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>Adorning,Filling</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="employ or become employed in a position" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: implies an assignment/mapping between one person and one job role.
	Note: focus is on assigning a specific role to an individual, not adding an individual to a pool of others (see Sense 5)
        Syntax Includes:
	NP1[agent] FILL NP2[patient[abstract]]
	NP1[agent] FILL NP2[patient[abstract]] (PP{P NP[beneficiary]})  
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She filled the job as director of development.
        They quickly filled the position with one of the many qualified applicants.
        The company kept the job vacancy open until it could be filled.
        I have never filled a job so quickly in my entire career.
        Federal agencies fill jobs two ways, competitively and noncompetitively. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fill.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="meet or satisfy a want or need, supplement          or make complete" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: FILL IN, FILL UP, FILL OUT
        Note: implies adding to a list or set of people or things-- does -not- imply putting things into a space or a container
                (see Sense 1)
        Syntax Includes: NP1[agent] FILL OUT NP2[patient] (PP{P NP[theme]})
                         NP1 FILL NP2
                         NP1[agent] FILL OUT NP2
                         NP1[agent] FILL IN NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The volunteer experience was fun, educational and filled a need in our community.
        This church has evidently filled a want.
        Crime and horror comics filled a desire by that era's youth to experience some of the excitement the
        y imagined was part of World War II.
        This realization filled him suddenly and completely, leaving him feeling at peace.
        She had a hunger that longed to be filled.
        He filled up on turkey.
        They filled the bill in every way.
        A guest host filled in for Letterman.
        The assistant coach filled in for part of last season.
        The Florida Marlins filled out their coaching staff Wednesday.
        Filmmaker Mitch Davis has filled out his cast with appealing fresh
        faces.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,7,8</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_up" version="3.0">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_in" version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_the_bill" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_out" version="3.0">2,3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fill.04,fill.06</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="write all the required information" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: FILL OUT, FILL IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Fill out this questionnaire, please!
        Make sure to fill in all the blanks.
        The form will be automatically filled out for you.
        If they are logged in, the name is filled in for them.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="fill_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="fill_in" version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>fill.03,fill.05</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="supply with information" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: FILL IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She filled me in on a few points of Turkish culture.
        Craig filled me in on the challenges your sales department is facing.
        I was drawn to his office, dropping by to fill him in on what was happening.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="fill_in" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="use a shade, color, or pattern" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: FILL IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Ask students to use a red, blue, and yellow oil pastel to fill in the primary colors.
        Set the layers blending option to Hue, then fill in the selection
        by clicking inside it with the Paint Bucket tool.
        The picture will be repeated like a piece of tile to completely fill in the background of your page.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="fill_in" version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="to make or become larger, more substantial" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: FILL OUT
	Note: implies growing physically larger, NOT being assigned to a
	role/job (see Sense 2)
        Compare to sense 3. This sense involves growing larger physically,
	and does not include metaphorical uses.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        His new health book was titled, &quot;Business Eating on the Run: How to Fill Up Without Filling Out.&quot;
        You are still a teen - which means your body is still growing,
        filling out and adjusting itself to its ideal, mature weight and proportion.
        The downy parts of feathers as well as feathers that are totally
        downy provide insulation and filling out body contours.
        You will be growing taller and your body will be filling out.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="fill_out" version="3.0">4,5,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,ahouston,corvey,greenlm" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>