<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="film-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a specific motion picture, a movie" type="">
        <commentary>
            FILM[+artifact][+opus][+movie][+drama/+comedy/+action/+documentary]
            [+genre][+artistic][+cinema]
            Note: refers to the art form of cinema, not to the physical medium of recording (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The studio is shooting that film on location in Hawaii.
            That film is still showing in theaters and is not yet out on DVD.
            Mary watched a good horror film on TV last night.
            John's father is a famous film critic. 
            His books are very difficult to translate well into film. (into the artistic form, not the physical medium)
            The article was a critical overview of feminist writing on film.
            It is one of the most dramatic scenes after captured on film. (refers to the art form, not the physical medium)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the photosensitive material used in photography or cinema, celluloid" type="">
        <commentary>
            FILM[+strip][+flexible][+plastic][+coated][+photosensitive] 
            [+role][+medium][+dissemination][+celluloid] 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I have two rolls of film left. 
            The beating incident was captured on film. (refers to the physical medium the event was recorded on)
            This is an old 35 millimeter film projector.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a thin coating of material on the surface of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FILM[+material][+coating][+thin][+oil/+water]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The workmen had a film of perspiration over their skin as they labored under the hot sun.
            A thin film of ice had formed over the pond.
            There was a film of cream on the top of Mary's coffee.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a thin, usually plastic, sheet that serves as a layer or a wrapper" type="">
        <commentary>
            FILM[+sheet][+thin][+flexible][+wrapper/+liner]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The wrapping paper was an interesting shiny silver film.
            Mylar is a thin, polyester film, both strong and flexible.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>