<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="fit-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an emotional outburst" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIT[+event][+emotional][+outburst]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sally threw a fit when she heard Mary had been promoted above her.
            The child sat down on the floor in the restaurant and had a crying fit.
            He burned his old love letters in a fit of anger.
            The comedian's routine brought fits of laughter from the audience.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fit.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a physical convulsion, sudden attack" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIT[+event][+physiological][+attack][+violent]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John complained to the doctor about his coughing fits.
            The patient tried to swallow his tongue during an epileptic fit.
            With no warning the man fell to the ground, gasping in a fit.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fit.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the way something conforms to a shape" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            FIT[+form][+conforming][+to_shape]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These shoes are not a good fit, I'll try the smaller size.
            Mary liked the fit of the evening gown.
            The shelf was a perfect fit in the back of the closet.
            It'll be a close fit to get all the leftover stew into this container.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fit.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="how things match or correlate, especially data" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            FIT[+state][+correlation][+between_things]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This job is an excellent fit for Sally's skills and work experience.
            These data don't fit the climate computer model very well.
            The close fit of John's experimental results to an exponential curve is interesting.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1b</wn>
            <omega/><pb>fit.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a flurry or burst of activity" type="">
        <commentary>
            FIT[+event][+flurry][+of_activity]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We readied the house for sale in a fit of cleaning and repairs.
            The project is moving along in fits and starts.  (lots of work sometimes)
            There was a fit of activity in the bride's dressing room before the wedding.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>