<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="flood-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="fill or cover with" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] FLOOD NP2[location] PP{with NP[theme]}
        NP1[theme] FLOOD NP2[location]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He did not know the basement flooded when he purchased the house.
        The smell of gasoline vapors after a failed start may mean you have flooded the engine. 
        In the microcosms flooded with saline media, the initially present members of the N. oligotropha lineage were replaced.
        Jack stood up to reach for the tool catalog when suddenly the room flooded with fluorescent light.
        He was about to sit down on the floor when the room flooded with Enya.
        Thoughts of Keilan flooded to the front of her mind and she clenched her jaw.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>flood.01</pb>
         <vn>fill-9.8,other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>Filling</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="supply with an excess of" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] FLOOD NP2[patient[abstract]] PP{with NP[theme]}
        NP1[theme] FLOOD NP2[patient[abstract]]
        NP1[theme] FLOOD NP2[location[abstract]]
        Note: while the agent may not be explicitly stated in all utterances, an agent is understood
             (Tennis shoes can't flood the market without a supplier!)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Publishers flooded the market with books that matched this formula, giving readers more and more of what they demanded.
        Those of you that flooded the Montana Park system with calls and emails please know that you did make a difference!
        They spent roughly 5 million dollars on an aggressive campaign that flooded the airwaves with attacks against Senator.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>flood.01</pb>
         <vn>fill-9.8</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="arrive in great numbers" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Is: FLOOD IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Afterwards, hundreds of letters flooded in to the radio station.
        Hundreds of stories flooded in, everything from standard computer failures to tales of blue smoke and fire.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>   
         <wn lemma="flood_in" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Mass_motion</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="charge someone with too many tasks" type="">
      <commentary>
        Is: FLOOD OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He was flooded out with too many questions to solve to allow him the time to disentangle them.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="flood_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,greenlm" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>