<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="formulate-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="create or develop a concept or idea" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Note: this sense often entails expression through language, but focus is on the content, not on the grammar or discourse mechanisms.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        During this phase, participants formulate goals and specific strategies.
        More and more companies are formulating guidelines for cellphone use.
        A Korean bioethicist contends that &quot;we have our different social and cultural context, so we have to formulate our own bioethics.&quot;
        Formulate  a mental picture of yourself as succeeding.
        You formulate your own opinion, I'll provide the facts.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>formulate.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Invention,Encoding</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="construct a linguistic expression" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: focus is on the mechanics of grammatical construction and attributes.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Formulate your sentences using action verbs and avoid weak adjectives such as 'very'.
        The logic of this paragraph needs to be more tightly formulated with coherent discourse links.
        These Japanese phrases are difficult to formulate precisely in English.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>formulate.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Encoding</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="create a recipe for making physical things" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Wildcat manufactures, distributes and custom formulates high performance specialty chemicals.
        Porter Paints formulates all of our paints to the exacting standards demanded by the master painter, builder, and architect.
        Insight glaze software helps you apply glaze chemistry to formulate ceramic glazes and porcelain compounds.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>formulate.01</pb>
         <vn>build-26.1</vn><fn>Invention</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc, ahouston" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>