<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="form-n">
    <commentary>
        7nov06 update to wn2.1, added features. ahouston
        19Feb08 Sense 5 had to be split apart. combined senses 2 and 3, added Sense 14  ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="stylistic structure, arrangement or composition of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+shape][+abstract][+stylistic][+composition][+arrangement][+intentional]
            Note: a metaphoric extension of Sense 2 (physical shape) to more abstract intentional arrangement or structure
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This wine has good form and balance.  (refers to structure in flavor and taste)
            Their study of musical form included elements of harmony and melody.  
            Critics say his speeches have a lot of form but little content. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="geometric or spatial shape, configuration of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+shape][+spatial][+geometry][+of_object]
            shape, configuration, countour, conformation- 
            Note: implies a physical, geometric, spatial shape
            Note: X HAS FORM
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The form of that lake suggests it was created by a meteor impact.
            The painting has really captured nicely the form, texture and color of the tree.
            This physical pyramid is a close approximation to the perfect geometrical form of a pyramid.
            Mary admired the delicate graceful form of the vase.       
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="conduct, behavior" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+activity][+behavior][+conduct]
            Refers to human conduct in a social context
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It was poor form of John to show up at the dinner with an uninvited guest. (not proper conduct)
            What is the right form for greeting the Japanese guests and introducing them at the meeting?
            John has an excessive concern for legal form and precedent.
            True to form, they showed up at the meeting twenty minutes late.  (Idiomatic usage - based on past behavior, they did the expected thing)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">5a</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="particular modality, manifestation, appearance of an individual thing" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+state][+manifestation][+modality][+appearance]
            a particular mode in which something is manifested 
            Note: refers to the manifestation or appearance of a specific thing, not an abstract class 
            Note: X IS FORM
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The word 'swiftly' is the adverbial form of the English noun 'swift'.  (implies a specific manifestation)
            This expression is the polite form of address in German. 
            Her obsession took the form of compulsive exercise twice a day.
            The essay was in the form of a dialogue.
            Write down your ideas in outline form first, before beginning to write the actual story. 
            Although this form in English looks similar to that form in Mayan, the words are not related. (refers to specific tokens of writing, not whole system)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="abstract classification, category, variety or type" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+abstract][+category][+variety]
            a category of things distinguished by some common characteristic
            Note: refers to a collection of instances, not a single specific instance (compare to Sense 4)
            Note: substituting the word 'type' for 'form' should sound natural for instances of this sense., X IS TYPE/FORM OF Y
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sculpture and painting are forms of visual art.
            Although it is a form of cancer, it never metastasizes.
            Sponsorship is a form of advertising.
            The book describes various forms of worship in human society.
            This picture shows another rare form of that African butterfly.  (picture of a variant type)
            Was the fugue a popular form of musical composition during the 17th century? (refers to a whole type, not a specific piece)
            The microbiologist may have discovered a new form of this virus.
            Linear B is among the earlier forms of human writing.  (refers to the system as a type, not an instance of its manifestation)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="anatomical shape of the body of a being, physique" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+shape][+anatomical][+of_being]
            Note: refers to the whole physique of a human, or animal
            Note: related to Sense 2, but is a specific reference to anatomical shapes of humans, animals
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Leonardo studied the human form.
            The art class has been sketching nude forms in charcoal for the past several weeks.
            The man's eyes scanned the slender form of the woman from head to toe.
            The forms, both animal and human, on the left side of the wall were painted 1000 years earlier than those on the right side.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="2" n="7" name="worksheet, document with spaces to fill in" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+artifact][+document][+with_spaces][+for_writing]
            a printed document with spaces in which to write
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He filled out his tax forms.
            The lawyer requires our signature on three different forms.
            The nurse gave me a form to fill out while I waited.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="mold for casting, setting concrete" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+artifact][+mold][+temporary][+for_wet_concrete]
            a mold for setting concrete
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They built elaborate forms for pouring the foundation.
            You must pour the mixture into a form before it hardens.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">16</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="mannequin" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+artifact][+mannequin]
            a life-size dummy used to display clothes
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The forms in the front window of the dress shop displayed winter sportswear. 
            The storage area of the department store contained old forms and clothing racks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">15</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="ability, state of preparedness for performing" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+state][+preparedness][+performance]
            an ability to perform well
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was at the top of his form.
            The team was off form last night.
            The actor was in terrible form in last night's performance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">14</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="phase state of matter" type="Physical Chemistry">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+state][+manifestation][+modality][+phase][+of_matter]
            a distinct state of matter in a system, e.g, solid, liquid, gaseous, plasma
            Note: a narrower chemical usage of Sense 4
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Oxygen is very cold in its liquid form.
            Water vapor is just a gaseous form of H2O.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="class of students taught together" type="School">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+person][+group][+student][+same_class]
            grade - 
            a body of students who are taught together
            Note: British usage
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Early morning forms are always sleepy.
            His son is in the fifth form this year at school.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">13</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="sequence of physical movements" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+event][+physical][+movement][+sequence][+connected]
            pre-determined sequence of movements
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John practiced his forms for Tai-Kwon-Do.
            The ballerinas are learning all the basic forms, beginning with the first position.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="14" name="printed sheet with performance record of racing, e.g., racehorses" type="">
        <commentary>
            FORM[+entity][+artifact][+document][+record][+performance][+racing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John studied the racing forms before the Kentucky Derby.
            The forms are printed in the daily newspaper.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">-12_2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!--  -->
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>