<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="freedom-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the power of self-determination, to choose without being forced" type="">
        <commentary>
            FREEDOM[+state][+self_determination][+political/+personal]
            Note: implies a general state of being able to determine one's own thoughts, words and actions.
            Note: often occurs in phrases 'freedom of X' , and 'X's freedom'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The constitution guarantees the freedom of the press.  
            The shark thrashed its way to freedom.
            He worries there is less intellectual freedom in our society than there used to be.
            The children loved the freedom of summer vacation.
            The slaves won their freedom with the Emancipation Proclamation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="exemption or immunity from something undesirable" type="">
        <commentary>
            FREEDOM[+state][+exemption][+hardship]
            Note: refers to immunity or safety from something undesirable.
            Note: occurs in phrases 'freedom FROM X' , a disassociation with X.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These government polices were intended to achieve freedom from want and fear.
            The new high-paying job gave Bob freedom from care.
            The law is supposed to provide freedom from discrimination.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="having unrestricted access of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FREEDOM[+state][+access][+unrestricted][+resource]
            Note: refers to unrestricted access to something.
            Note: 'freedom of X' implies X is the resource to which there is access.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That treaty guaranteed freedom of the seas to all nations. (unrestricted access)
            Their dogs enjoy the freedom of the entire house.
            The robotic arm has six degrees of freedom. (can access six directions)
            The short skirt allows the dancer greater freedom of movement. (access to space)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">1h</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="improper familiarity" type="">
        <commentary>
            FREEDOM[+activity][+conduct][+social][+familiarity][+improper]
            Note: a somewhat archaic, rare usage.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He was reprimanded for taking freedoms with the new young assistant.
            In that society, talking to a woman alone in public is considered taking too many freedoms.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">1f</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>