<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="front-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the relation of near proximity to something/someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+relation][+proximity][+near]
            Note: often in the expression 'in front of'
            Note: focus is on the placement of something relative to something else.
            Note: in front of an audience -&gt; cannot say *the audience's front (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The boy was too shy to say anything in front of the famous scientist.
            John admired the black Porsche parked in front of the ice cream parlor.
            The child is not ready to perform out in front of an audience.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the foremost part of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+location][+front][+area]
            Note: focus is on the location of a part or portion of a thing, -not- relative to a separate thing.
            Note: front of the house -&gt; house's front
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She looked at the address written on the front of the envelope.
            The front of the house has curved glass windows.
            I recall a small passageway located towards the front of the cave.
            He wanted more salary up front instead of getting stock options. (figurative extension)
            She liked parking the Ferrari out front where all the neighbors could see it. 
            The front of Bob's shirt has a spot of mustard on it.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,4,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="state or condition of a social sphere of activity" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+state][+social][+situation][+specified]
            Note: occurs with a preceding modifier that defines the social situation
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            How are things going on the job front?
            Things seem to be looking up on the diplomatic front.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the foremost area of a combat zone" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+location][+boundary][+military][+combat]
            Note: when used figuratively, implies designated goals, perhaps difficult to attain.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He served on the front for two years during World War I.
            These troop trains are bound for the front.
            The supply lines are not getting through quickly because the front keeps moving forward.
            They are making progress on all fronts of this issue. (figurative)
            They haven't made much progress on the legal front. (figurative)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="an ideological or political movement" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+social][+organization][+movement][+ideological]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The rebels have joined forces in a national liberation front.
            Politicians were surprised by the number of people involved in that animal rights' front.
            He has been an organizer in several anti-war fronts over the past decades.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="atmospheric activity, a weather pattern" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+activity][+atmospheric][+weather]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A cold front is predicted to move in by tomorrow, bringing rain.
            Tornados formed along the boundary of the hot and cold fronts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="the role of serving as a cover or mask for something else" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+role][+cover][+disguise]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The CIA identified the company as a front for a terrorist group.
            They suspect these small groceries and pizzerias are money laundering fronts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="personal behavior or demeanor" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+activity][+social][+individual][+demeanor]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The child put up a brave front when he got his booster shot.
            Mary put on a welcoming front for her in-laws, even though she disliked them.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="serving as a prestigious representative on behalf of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            FRONT[+role][+representative][+prestigious]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They've found a local CEO to be the front for the new charity drive.
            The famous actress offered to be the front for their environmental initiative.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">7b</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>