<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="game-n">
    <commentary>25oct06  update to wn2.1. added features. ahouston
        25oct06  added Sense 9, added examples, modified definitions. ahouston
        9dec08   revised definitions, examples, features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="An actual, competitive event" type="">
        <commentary>GAME[+event][+competition][+actual]
            Note: Refers to specific events of game-playing, either past, present or future
            Note: Includes sports,cards,boardgames,quiz shows
        </commentary>
        <examples>The game starts at six-thirty tonight.
            The children played games and won prizes at Johnny's birthday party. 
            We played a great game of basketball today!
            The game between the chess masters lasted six hours.
            The games will be held in Seattle next year.
            John is appearing on a famous game show next week.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="System of rules defining the form of a contest" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>GAME[+system][+rule][+competition]
            Note: Refers to the rules and idea of a game, not a specific instance of it (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>We need four people to play my favorite card game, Hearts.
            In the game of football, you must annihilate everything in your path.
            &quot;River City Ransom&quot; is a great video game for the old Nintendo.
            This theory assumes a zero-sum game as an economic model.
            He was a pioneer in the field of game theory.
            There will be many unforeseen challenges in the game of life. (metaphoric extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Amusement, activity of diversion, caper" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>GAME[+activity][+diversion][+entertaining]
            A pastime or amusement for someone, not a competition between contestants.
            Note: does not carry pejorative connation that Sense 8 has.
        </commentary>
        <examples>It's all fun and games until somebody loses an eye.
            John didn't understand that Mary's flirting was just a game to her.
            Painting became a game for him to fill up the empty hours.
            Pete suddenly realized it was no game, his friends really meant to blow up the bridge. (not a joke)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Hunted animals, prey" type="Entity">
        <commentary>GAME[+entity][+organism][+animal][+wild][+hunted]
            An animal hunted for sport and/or food, or the flesh of a hunted animal.
        </commentary>
        <examples>His great-grandfather was a big game hunter in Africa and Alaska.
            This robust wine goes well with game meats such as venison or wild duck.
            Everyone in Washington D.C. was fair game for the famous satirist. (metaphoric extension, they are targets)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="Physical game equipment" type="Entity">
        <commentary>GAME[+artifact][+equipment][+playing]
            The actual pieces that comprise a game.  
            Only use this sense when a physical object is clearly being referred to.
        </commentary>
        <examples>My game of Monopoly is missing a few pieces.
            The deluxe version of the game has wooden pieces and a bigger board.
            Her son wants the new Playstation game console for Christmas.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="Occupation, pursuit, specific endeavor" type="Activity">
        <commentary>GAME[+activity][+pursuit][+specialized]
            Note: informal usage for job, interest, pursuit
        </commentary>
        <examples>He got out of the newspaper game a few years ago.
            Mary is tired of the dating game and would like to find a serious relationship.
            It takes money and influence to pursue the game of politics.
            She decided that academia was not her game.
            Their company got into online video early in the game.
            Acting is a tough game to break into.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="A quantitative unit of scoring in a contest" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>GAME[+quantity][+unit][+scoring][+of_contest]
            Note: use this sense only when 'game' clearly refers to a quantity, the score of the contest.
        </commentary>
        <examples>Mary and her bridge partner made a game. (100 points score for tricks bid and made)
            Pete is one game up in the second set of his tennis match with Bob.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="A manipulative scheme or ploy" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>GAME[+activity][+maneuver][+manipulative][+concealed]
            A social maneuver or manipulation, often intentionally concealed
            Note: carries a pejorative connotation
        </commentary>
        <examples>I saw through your little game from the start.
            He grew tired of the constant mind games at work.
            They are running some little game to sell non-existent real estate in Florida.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="Personal performance in a competition" type="">
        <commentary>GAME[+activity][+behavior][+performance][+personal][+in_contest]</commentary><examples>He's really taken his game to the next level this season.
            There is still a lot of game left in that ball club.
            He's a bond trader who's been off his game for some time. 
            The team's kicking game has been formidable the past few weeks. (one aspect of their performance)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1d</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>