<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="gap-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a difference or disparity between quantities" type="">
        <commentary>
            GAP[+quantity][+amount][+difference]
            [+relation][+difference][+numerical][+sums]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A gap between imports and exports creates a trade imbalance.
            This study disputes the claim that the income gap between rich and poor has increased.
            The accountant found a significant gap between assets and liabilities on the balance sheet.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a break, hiatus, an empty spatial or temporal expanse" type="">
        <commentary>
            GAP[+expanse][+empty][+spatial/+temporal]
            [+relation][+hiatus]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John saw a gap in the traffic and made his left turn. (space empty of cars)
            The child had a wide gap between his two front teeth.
            The interviewer asked Bob to explain the 2-year gap in his resume. (time unaccounted for)
            Electricity jumped the small gap between the terminals of the induction coil.
            There are still many gaps in our understanding of what happened. (figurative extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a narrow opening or passage" type="">
        <commentary>
            GAP[+location][+region][+opening][+small/+large]
            [+relation][+role][+passage]
            Note: implies the opening serves as a passageway for something
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The pioneers found a passable gap through the mountains. 
            The mouse crawled into the wall through a small gap near the floor.
            A red fox appeared through a gap in the hedge.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a disparity between perspectives, viewpoints" type="">
        <commentary>
            GAP[+state][+disparity][+perspective]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Parents felt a huge generation gap with their children during the 1060s.
            The senator has a major credibility gap now that he was discovered to have lied under oath.
            She was trying to bridge the gap between the two warring factions in upper management.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>