<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="headquarters-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the main office, or home office, of a civilian enterprise" type="">
        <commentary>
            HEADQUARTERS[+office][+primary][+administrative][+enterprise][+civilian][+business/+nonprofit/+political]
            Note: refers to an administrative hub for a civilian enterprise
            Note: usually (not always) implies the office is a permanent, non-mobile setup.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The headquarters of that manufacturing firm is located in Buffalo, NY.
            John decided to switch jobs when his company moved their headquarters to Atlanta.
            Sally's video game startup is setting up temporary headquarters in her garage.
            The headquarters of the United Nations is in New York City. (administrative civilian offices)
            Pete was a volunteer at the Chicago headquarters of a small political party.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the command post for a given non-civilian organization" type="">
        <commentary>
            HEADQUARTERS[+center][+command][+organization][-civilian][+military/+police/+espionage]
            Note: refers to a center for dispatching non-civilian orders to enlisted personnel
            Note: the center is often (not always) temporary or also can be mobile.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The generals plotted their military campaign at the supreme headquarters in Berlin.
            Several of his headquarters staff were killed when the plane hit the Pentagon.
            The U.N. troops set up temporary headquarters in a large downtown hotel.
            They took the suspect down to police headquarters for questioning.
            He worked for years as a field officer at the headquarters for British Intelligence. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>