<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="history-n">
    <commentary>
        7nov06 update to wn 2.1, added features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the past, the continuum of events aggregating over time" type="">
        <commentary>
            HISTORY[+expanse][+temporal][+continuum][+event][+past]
            the aggregate of past events
            Note: does not imply the existence of a specific document or account, just the events themselves.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The patient has no medical history of fainting spells.
            It was a turning point in the history of the American people.
            The history of the universe may have begun with a big bang.
            The Smiths have a family history of alcoholism.
            There have been wars throughout human history.
            The fossil record may not reveal the very earliest history of life on earth.
            The Red Sox defeated the Yankees four in a row and the rest is history. (more famous past events that followed defeating Yankees - winning World Series)
            Henry Ford said that history is bunk.  
            Those who ignore history are condemned to repeat it.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,4,5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a narrative of the past, a record" type="">
        <commentary>
            HISTORY[+entity][+artifact][+repository][+information][+past][+written/+spoken]
            Note: implies the existence of a particular account, chronicle or record of something.
            account, chronicle - 
            a record or narrative description of past events
            Note: often a document of some type
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He wrote the definitive history of the Roman Empire.
            These stories have been passed down through the oral history of the tribe.
            John is reading one of Shakespeare's histories, I believe, Richard III.
            The lawyer had his assistant review the case histories. (dossiers on individuals)
            Critics say this new history is full of factual error and poor scholarship.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a discipline, a branch of knowledge" type="">
        <commentary>
            HISTORY[+entity][+symbolic][+knowledge][+discipline][+scholarly]
            [+activity][+pursuit][+scholarly][+knowledge][+event][+past]
            the scholarly discipline that records and interprets past events involving human
            beings 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He teaches medieval history at the local college.
            Zoology is a branch of natural history.
            Mary is enjoying her art history class.
            History is a discipline that requires careful examination of primary sources and records.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="finished, irrelevant" type="Slang">
        <commentary>
            HISTORY[+state][+completed][-relevant]
            Note: a specialized, figurative usage of Sense 1
            slang term meaning done or finished, part of history now
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That guy is history.
            After that incident, the two of them are history.
            When I finished level two of the video game all those monsters were history.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>