<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="holder-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a physical device to support or contain something" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOLDER[+artifact][+device][+support]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary showed me her carved ebony cigarette holder.
            Most new cars and vans come with drink holders at every seat.
            I replaced my towel holders with fancy new brass ones.
            The candle holders need polishing before the dinner party tonight.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the owner of capital, e.g., commercial documents, property, human labor" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOLDER[+owner][+capital][+finance/+land/+resource]
            Note: what is 'held' is a commercial resource, to buy or sell (legally or not)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The shareholders may vote to have the CEO replaced.
            Our company is the major stock holder of its own stock.
            The holder of the title to this powerboat is John.
            Ticket holders may proceed to the front entrance now.
            The policy holder should sign only the first page.
            The lease holder is explicitly not allowed to sublet this apartment.  (lease = temporary ownership)
            For centuries the serfs worked the farmland for the landholders.
            The slave holders in the Caribbean mostly ran sugar plantations.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the occupier of a role, e.g., position or vocation" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOLDER[+relation][+role][+occupier][+vocation/+position]
            Note: what is 'held' is intangible, it is a relation, not a commercial resource to buy or sell.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These office holders have become complacent in their job.
            Bob is the record holder for the standing broad jump.
            Most job holders' health insurance is provided through their employer.
            In the number '405' the zero is a placeholder for the tens' column.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">1a</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>