<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="house-n">
    <commentary>
        Includes idioms on_the_house, full_house
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a domicile or physical place to live" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+physical][+building][+domicile]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We are selling our house and moving to California.
            Those houses have been on the market for two weeks.
            Can you read the address on that house?
            John took Mary to his new beach house.
            We went to several open houses last week.
            These refugees will need houses to live in.
            Sally has a beautiful Victorian doll house in her living room. (extension)
            The realtor showed us two townhouses and a row house, but we decided to buy the farmhouse.
            The spies met at one of the safe houses in Virginia. (extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="people living together" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+social][+group][+family/+order]
            Note: 'house' functions as an agent or patient
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our house hosts a scrabble game after dinner on Tuesday nights.
            Their house has a cooking audition for people who would like to move in.
            He joined a Christian house on campus.
            That fraternity house was shut down for underage drinking.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a building to store or shelter things" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+physical][+building][+shelter]
            Note: Differs from Sense 1 in 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our club is building a new boathouse. 
            Mary grows orchids in her greenhouse.
            There is concern that the earth could become a greenhouse. (metaphoric)
            Bob built a doghouse for his poodle.
            These are bee houses where the bees make honey.
            He's been living in an old brick carriage house. (original purpose was to hold carriages)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a public building where activities take place" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+physical][+building][+public]
            Note: house of/for NP/NP-house implies the service/activity of/to NP occurs in the house.
            Note: differs from sense 3; sense 3 'house of NP. NP-house' implies NP is located or protected by house
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This is the larger of the two opera houses which are both built out of granite.
            The old movie house burned down last summer.
            The gated community built a new two-story clubhouse last year.
            The lights in the house went down before everyone had taken their seat.
            We enjoyed the bathhouse at the old resort.
            There are two outhouses at the nearby camp grounds.
            The heroine spends two years in a madhouse in that Victorian novel.	
            The convicts broke out of the death house.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="aristocratic lineage" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+social][+lineage][+aristocratic]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He belongs to the royal House of York.	
            She is a descendant of the House of Medici.
            There has been turmoil in the House of Chanel since the departure of their top designer.  (metaphoric)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a business firm" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+organization][+business]
            Note: highlights the business venture itself.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She has worked for two different brokerage houses.
            The French fashion houses are presenting a pared-down silhouette this year.
            They periodically raid the flop houses in the Tenderloin district.
            They traced the stolen painting through a New York auction house.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="the management of a business or establishment" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+business][+management]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This house only takes a cut of the ante from the poker tables.
            When the house dims the lights it is time to sit down.
            John has beat the house many times at Black Jack with his card counting methods.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="an official or political assembly" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+assembly][+official][+legislative]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There are two houses in a bicameral legislature.
            The bill is expected to go before the House tomorrow.
            She was elected to the House three times.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="the people attending a theater or entertainment" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+assembly][+entertainment]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That joke brought down the house.
            The entire house jumped to its feet in a standing ovation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="regions of the zodiac" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+region][+astrological]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Do you know the twelve houses of the zodiac?
            The moon is in the seventh house right now.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="a child's game" type="">
        <commentary>
            HOUSE[+game][+child]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Let's play house with our Barbie dolls.
            Susie wants to play house and Johnny wants to play doctor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="free, without expense" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: on_the_house
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Drinks are on the house!
            Bob is always expecting things to be on the house.
            Dessert was on the house, but dinner was not.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">idiom</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="specific hands in five-card Poker" type="">
        <commentary>
            idiom: full_house
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Three of a kind and a pair makes a full house in poker.
            I raised the bet while holding a full house in my hand.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>