<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="intervention-n">
    <commentary>
        6oct06 update to wn2.1, added features, changed the examples and definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the activity of assisting a process or an individual" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    INTERVENTION[+event][+activity][+assistance][+individual/+situation]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            These are plants that grow naturally in this climate without human intervention.
            Without medical intervention, the baby would have died from the illness.
            She manages a center that does family crisis intervention, including drug and alcohol abuse.
            The central banks practice currency intervention to provide price stability to major world currencies.
            Economists don't predict further intervention by the Fed in terms of raising the interest rates this week.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a nation's imposition of policy on another nation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            INTERVENTION[+activity][+imposition][+official][+nation]
            a policy or act of a nation to impose policy or conditions on another nation
            Note: a narrow, specific usage of Sense 1 - always refers to the actions of a state, not an individual.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            'Let us decide our quarrels at home without the intervention of any foreign power.' (Sir W. Temple)
            They have been critical of the administration's policy of intervention in the Middle East.
            Pete believes that earlier military intervention against Hitler might have prevented World War II. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="legal right to enter an ongoing lawsuit" type="Law">
        <commentary>
            INTERVENTION[+state][+legal][+condition][+inclusion][+lawsuit][+ongoing] 
            Note: technical, legal sense
            a proceeding that permits a person to enter into a lawsuit already in
            progress; so that person can protect some right or interest that is allegedly
            affected by the proceedings
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Civil procedure in U.S. law recognizes two types of intervention; intervention of right and permissive intervention.
            Permissive intervention is up to the discretion of the court.
            The purpose of intervention is to prevent unnecessary duplication of lawsuits.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>