<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="irritation-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a state of annoyance, vexation" type="">
        <commentary>
            IRRITATION[+state][+emotional][+annoyance]
            Note: attributes an emotional state to a person
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Her irritation grew as the minutes went by and the bus still didn't come.
            Any irritation she may have felt earlier was dispelled by the bouquet of roses.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the act of annoying someone or something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            IRRITATION[+action][+annoy]
            Note: nominalization - the child's irritation of everyone - the child irritated everyone.
            Note: refers to an agent's -act- of irritating, not the agent itself (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The child's irritation of the entire cabin of the plane lasted for hours.
            The thistle's irritation of his back under the saddle caused the horse to buck.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a cause or agent of annoyance" type="">
        <commentary>
            IRRITATION[+cause][+effective][+annoyance]
            Note: refers to the cause or agent of annoyance.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These are just some of the minor irritations of life.
            Let me know if little Johnny becomes a major irritation at the day care center.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1b</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="physiological: abnormal, painful sensitivity" type="">
        <commentary>
            IRRITATION[+state][+physiological][+condition][-normal][+sensitivity][+inflammation/+swelling]	
            Note: abnormal condition of pain, inflammation, sensitivity
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The irritation in Mary's eyes is from tree pollen.
            This salve will soothe the irritations on your arms.
            The doctor could not determine what had caused the patient's stomach irritation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="physical excitation of a biological entity" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            IRRITATION[+event][+physiological][+response][+excitation][+normal][+cell/+organ/+organism]
            Note: a normal reaction of a living organism or cell to outside stimulation
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The cells reacted to the irritation of outside electrical stimulation.
            The irritation from the cold caused the muscle to contract.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>