<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="justify-v">    
   <commentary>
      FN Frame Deserving vs. Justifying differ only in terms of whether or not an Agent 
       is held responsible for the act needing justification.  Justifying covers such
       cases.  Deserving is for cases where the state of affairs thought to warrant
       an action are part of an external scene.  Most of the senses' examples listed
       here do not easily distingish between the two, so I included them both.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="give or be a good reason for something, rationalize" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 JUSTIFY NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Does the end justify the means?
        Whether or not we think the anger is justified by the action is immaterial.
        She justified each budgetary expense as necessary.
        I can't really justify taking another day off work
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>justify.01</pb>
         <vn>transfer_mesg-37.1.1</vn>
        <fn>Deserving,Justifying</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="LEGAL- demonstrate sufficent legal reason for a legal action" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        They have not taken any legal action to justify the discovery of Doe's identity.
        The action must justify the benefit that one set of creditors receives.
        You simply need to have enough co-plaintiffs to justify the suit as a class.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>justify.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>Deserving,Justifying</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="absolve from responsibility, guilt or blame" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 JUSTIFY NP2 (PP{FROM NP}) (PP{BY NP})
        Note: Religious meaning-'absolve from sin'.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        It does not justify him from him duties.
        It doesn't justify you from cheating on your wife.
        The authorities justified him from all the false charges brought against him.
        God justifies sinners by grace.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>justify.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>Deserving,Justifying</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="adjust spaces between words to produce even margins" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Justify the paragraph with respect to the graphic.
        Pressing Ctrl-J on your keyboard justifies the paragraph.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>