<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="keep-v">    
   <commentary>
	All VPCs included in the last entry of the file.
        Two VPCs (keep_in_hand, keep_track) do not have WordNet entries.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) maintain a particular state, activity, or position" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[agent] KEEP NP2[patient] (PP) (NP) (VP)

        Note: This sense includes both concrete and abstract uses.

        Includes: KEEP APART, KEEP AWAY, KEEP BACK, KEEP DOWN, KEEP GOING,
        KEEP IN, KEEP MUM, KEEP OFF, KEEP ON, KEEP ONE'S DISTANCE, KEEP ONE'S EYES OFF, 
        KEEP OPEN, KEEP OUT, KEEP QUIET, KEEP UP 
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The negotiators managed to keep their cool through the crisis.
        They kept radio silence for two hours.
        She kept mum about the party.
        She managed to keep back her tears.
        The ship's log needs to be kept up-to-date.
        The work in that class will keep you on your toes.
        He kept his family alive that winter by hunting deer and rabbit.
        The software giant complained that the EU kept changing the rules for compliance.
        She kept going despite her fatigue.
        His cryptic remark kept her guessing all day.
        This matter will keep until the morning.
        That chocolate cake will not keep long!
        The filter keeps down the dust in this room.
        They kept open the possibility of a merger.
        Keep up the good work!
        That cup of coffee kept me up until 3 in the morning.
        He tries to keep off drugs.
        The trees keep out the sunshine.
        Where do you keep your coffee grinder?
        They never kept guns in their house.
        John can't keep this much food in his small refrigerator.
        Keep these knives out of harms way in a drawer.
        Her company keeps old email on backup DVDs.
        Keep your hands in your pocket for warmth.
        Doctor adviced me to keep my foot on ice for a few minutes.
        He kept goats in his back yard, despite the zoning laws.
        You must build structures if you are going to keep bees properly.
        The deputy minister kept a mistress in his New York penthouse.
        She keeps an apartment in Paris for her shopping trips.
        Those two need to be kept apart.
        They could not keep the reporters away from the crime scene.
        Will you please keep your voices down?
        Keep off the grass!
        The cats need to be kept in tonight.
        The teacher recommended that Johnny be kept back a grade.
        Polly was kept after school twice this week for distrupting class.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,9,12,14,18,19,20,21,22</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_apart" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_away" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_back" version="3.0">1,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_down" version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_going" version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_in" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_mum" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_off" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_on" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_distance" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_eyes_off" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_open" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_quiet" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_up" version="3.0">2,3,5</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>keep.02,keep.04,keep.06</pb>
         <vn>keep-15.2,subjugate-42.3,seem-109,sustain-55.6</vn><fn>Avoiding,Cause_to_continue,Activity_ongoing,Storing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense n="2" type="" name="retain ownership, access or title to something" group="1">
      <commentary>
        Note: There is something that the agent is keeping - an abstract or concrete noun
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] KEEP NP2[patient]
        Note: FOCUS is on NP1's ownership of NP2
        Includes: KEEP BACK, KEEP IN HAND
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Keep the change.
        We need to keep some cash for a rainy day.
        Can I keep my email address after I graduate? 
        She kept her maiden name when she got married.
        The deposed monarch was allowed to keep his personal servants and cook.
        He's keeping an adjunct position at the university while working for a start-up.
        After the stock market bust, they couldn't keep both their weekend cottage and their sail boat.
        They kept back the security deposit until they could inspect the apartment.
        These bankers always kept in hand part of the money they received.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,10,16,17</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_back" version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>keep.01</pb>
         <vn>keep-15.2</vn><fn>Storing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense n="3" type="" name="stop (someone) from doing something" group="1">
      <commentary>
       Syntax Includes:
       NP1[agent] KEEP NP2[patient] PP{from NP[predicate]}
       NP1[instrument] KEEP NP2[patient] PP{from NP[predicate]}
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        What has been keeping them (from coming) for so long?
        Nothing could keep me from falling asleep last night.
        The senator couldn't keep from reminding everyone that he had first proposed that bill two years earlier.
        They bought back enough stock to keep their competitor from buying them out.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>keep.04</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense n="4" type="" name="behave as expected, promise, honor" group="1">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] KEEP NP2[patient[abstract]]
        Note: this sense includes conforming to social behavior norms.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He always keeps his promises.
        The firm has kept to the original conditions of the contract.
        Can you keep a secret?
        She taught her children to keep the sabbath.
        Sally isn't keeping her vow to stop smoking.
        Their commune decided to start keeping Druid holidays.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,13</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Compliance</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense n="5" type="" name="care for, sustain, look after" group="1">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] KEEP NP2[beneficiary]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I keep the shop for Mary while she picks up her children from daycare.
        Good luck and may God keep you!
        There's little to earn and many to keep.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">7,11,15</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>keep.10</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="observe, follow along, synchronize, track" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: KEEP ABREAST, KEEP AN EYE ON, KEEP UP, KEEP NOTE, KEEP PACE, KEEP STEP,
                  KEEP TABS ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        How do you keep time around the world?
        We don't keep track of the news anymore.
        Who is keeping score?
        During the audit they discovered that the accountant had kept sloppy records.
        She kept up with all the latest fashion trends.
        Bob could not keep up with the class assignments.
        She read three newspapers a day to keep abreast of current events.
        The boy tried to keep step with his father.
        The detective kept tabs on the suspect.
        He kept an eye on their progress.
        She kept note of how often Sally took a coffee break.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_abreast" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_an_eye_on" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_up" version="3.0">1,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_note" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_pace" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_step" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_tabs_on" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>keep.03</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense n="7" type="vpc" name="multi-word expressions" group="1">  
      <commentary>
        Note: These are multi-word expressions, and NOT verb-particle
        constructions. These are idiomatic.
        Includes: KEEP COMPANY, KEEP GUARD, KEEP IN LINE, KEEP NOTE, KEEP ONE'S EYES OFF,
                  KEEP ONE'S EYES OPEN, KEEP ONE'S EYES PEELED, KEEP ONE'S HANDS OFF,
                  KEEP ONE'S MOUTH SHUT, KEEP ONE'S NOSE TO THE GRINDSTONE, 
                  KEEP ONE'S SHOULDER TO THE WHEEL, KEEP TO ONESELF
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
  Why don't you keep me company while I run this errand?
  The jewels over which they kept guard were stolen.
  That teacher cannot seem to keep her children in line.
  Hey, keep your eyes off my younger sister!
  Keep your eyes open for a gas station.
  John kept his eyes peeled for speed traps along I-93.
  The secret service man kept his eyes skinned for snipers up on the buildings.
  Bob just couldn't keep his hands off the box of dark chocolates.
  Bill decided to keep his mouth shut about his wife's new hair color.
  Tom kept his nose to the grindstone for eight months and finished his dissertation.
  We must keep our shoulder to the wheel until this project is finished.
  He keeps to himself.
      </examples>
      <mappings>  
         <wn lemma="keep_company" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_guard" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_in_line" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_eyes_open" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_eyes_peeled" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_eyes_skinned" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_one's_hands_off" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="keep_to_oneself" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,hwangd,brownsw,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
