<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="law-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a legal rule" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A legal document that regulates something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Alabama has a law against kidnapping, among other activities.
            Senator McCain passed a law that reformed the funding of political campaigns.
            We have laws against that sort of thing!
            John broke about a dozen public-nuisance laws that night.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the set of rules" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The abstract collection of rules, or a division thereof, that governs human society.  Usually imposed by a ruling body.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Stealing music is against the law.
            Our city saw a breakdown of law and order.
            Civilization presupposes respect for the rule of law.
            The law forbids you to smoke in bars anymore.
            I don't know much about European contract law.
            Louis XIV ruled by divine law.
            Locke believed in a benign natural law, by which people can peacefully govern themselves.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2 4 7
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a scientific principle" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A generalization that describes a fact or recurring event in nature.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Newton's First Law of Motion was always my favorite.
            Only Bugs Bunny can defy the laws of thermodynamics.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the legal profession or practice" type="Activity">
        <commentary>
            Refers narrowly to what you learn in law school and to what a lawyer practices.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He studied law for three years at Yale.
            John wanted to get into law after graduation.
            Bobby Donnell practiced law for six years.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the police, in general" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            Refers to the police, or any law-enforcement body, in a general way.  Tends to have a long arm.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The law came looking for Billy the Kid.
            I don't want to get in trouble with the law!
            For years he'd been running from the law.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                6
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>