<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="level-n">
    <commentary>
        28aug06 upgraded to ordnet 2.1 ahouston
        28aug06 split sense 1 into sense 1, sense 5 ahouston
        28aug06 moved WordNet 8 from sense 2 to sense 5, created sense 6 from wordnet 3 ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="position or height, relative to a base - usually the ground" type="">
        <commentary>
            LEVEL[+quantity][+measure][+relative][+height]
            Position on a fixed physical scale.  Often indicating height above ground.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Glacial melt may raise the sea level by six inches.
            THe two pictures on the wall were placed at the same level.
            The mud was at ankle level in some places.
            Water seeks its own level.  (an equilibrium of height)
            The snow drift was at waist level.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the amount of something, as a concentration, degree or occurrence" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIMT[+quantity][+amount][+degree/+concentration/+occurrence]
            Note: answers the question 'how much X was there'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That job does not require a high level of intelligence.
            There is a high level of unemployment in that region of the country.
            The doctor told Mary she had a low level bronchial infection. 
            The candidate spoke to his audience with a refreshing level of frankness. (implies a lot of frankness)
            They found low levels of mercury in the harbor water.
            The sound engineer decreased the amplitude level of the recording equipment. (loudness)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Flat horizontal surface" type="">
        <commentary>
            LEVEL[+form][+surface][+horizontal][+flat]
            A flat surface at right angles to the plumb line.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Park the car on the level.
            The levels were flooded from the heavy rains. (flat lands)
            John didn't think the offer was on the level. (metaphoric extension, not perfectly straight)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a tool for measuring and adjusting the horizontal orientation of things" type="Technical">
        <commentary>
            LEVEL[+entity][+artifact][+tool][+adjustment][+horizontal]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The tripod had a level built into it for adjusting the three legs.
            The surveyor used his level to take a measurement.
            The carpenter used his spirit level to check the alignment of the shelving.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="structural layer or stratum" type="">
        <commentary>
            LEVEL[+entity][+structure][+stratum][+stacked][+story[+building]]/[+seam[+ore]]/[+meaning[+pun]]
            Note: implies the structure is one of a number of layers, stacked together.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There is a restaurant on the fifth level of that office building.
            Our car is parked on level five.
            Their home is built on three levels, with two above ground.
            There was corruption at every level of the government. (abstract extension)
            A pun is a joke that works on two levels. (metaphoric extension)
            There are several levels of fossil bed in this rock face, from different geological periods.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a rank or position relative to others" type="">
        <commentary>
            LEVEL[+relation][+position][+rank][+comparative]
            Note: answers the question 'What rank?'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My son is in a college level math class. (as opposed to high school level)
            Only athletes who are performing at the highest level will make the Olympic team.
            These children are reading below their grade level.
            The study reports that more families were below the poverty level last year than the year before. (a threshold point)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>