<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="life-n">
    <commentary>14Jul08 added features, revised examples and definitions, merged Sense 8 with Sense 2, added senses and idioms. ahouston
        8Jan09 - merged senses, modified examples. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="Ongoing social activity, public or personal" type="">
        <commentary>
	    LIFE[+event][+event_set][+activity][+social][+ongoing]
	    </commentary><examples>The complexities of modern life have created new stresses on society.
            Life in the city is more hectic and expensive than life in the country.
            She made a new life for herself in Australia.
            He led a materialistic life that centered around outward appearances.
            Her life fell apart each semester during finals.
            The theater was his life.
            She lived life in the fast lane.
            Her life revolved around her children until they were in college.
            Mary wishes John would get a life.
            The governor retired from public life after he lost the last election. (public affairs and events)
            The students were settling into college life away from home.
            Life in the 14th century was quite different than life today.
            On Sunday mornings there is almost no sign of life except the newspaper vendors.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,13</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="2" name="Placeholder: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version=""/><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="A person's existence, their time span of being alive" type="">
        <commentary>
	    LIFE[+event][+state][+existence][+alive]
	    the condition of living or state of being alive
	    </commentary>
        <examples>These alleged facts in the composer's life are disputed in a recent biography.
            He believes in life after death. (a state of existence)
            The man bought life insurance. 
            Two firemen lost their lives in the blaze.
            They gave their lives for their country.
            For much of her life, she lived in Spain.
            The ruler declared himself emperor for life.
            We have known each other all our lives.
            The book describes the high points of his life's work in theoretical physics.
            The poet had a fascinating life.
            They ran for their lives from the sniper fire.
            He wrote a famous book on the lives of the saints.
            While there's life, there's hope.  (If one is alive, one can still hope)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,6,7,13</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Duration of an artifact's functionality" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+span][+temporal][+functionality][+of_artifact]</commentary><examples>The battery had a short life.
            This warranty is good for the life of the monitor.
            Regular cleaning and resealing will increase the life of your deck's finish.
            The life of this homeowner's policy has expired.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="Liveliness, vitality" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+quality][+manner][+vitality]
            spirit, sprightliness - 
            animation and energy in action or expression
        </commentary>
        <examples>It was a long, tedious play and the actors tried in vain to give it life.
            The young girl was full of life.
            She was the life of the party.
            The drunkard's eyes gazed up, without life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="A  living person" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+person][+alive]
            Note: the terms 'person' or 'people' can be substituted without loss of meaning.
        </commentary>
        <examples>His heroism saved a life.
            Five lives were lost in the accident.
            Modern antibiotics have probably saved millions of lives.
            These young lives were cut short by drug abuse.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="Living organisms, collectively" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+collection][+organism][+alive]
            living things collectively (mass noun)
            Note: occurs only in the singular form
        </commentary>
        <examples>The oceans are teeming with life.
            There is no life on the moon.
            The meteor impact ended much of the life on the planet.
            It would be thrilling to find life on Mars.
            When did life first begin on earth?
            The tracks in the sand were made by an alien life form.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8,10</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="Life sentence in prison" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+event][+punishment][+legal][+sentence][+imprisonment][+until_death]</commentary><examples>He got life for killing a policeman.
            If you're caught they'll give you life.
            These prisoners are doing life without parole.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">14</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="10" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="">Placeholder Sense</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="11" name="Placeholder: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="">Placeholder Sense</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="Art created from real models" type="">
        <commentary>LIFE[+entity][+artifact][+art][+created][+from_model][+real]</commentary><examples>The painter is most famous for his still life.
            Her life studies are on exhibit at the gallery.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">4</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="Become activated or animated" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: COME_TO_LIFE  (become animated)</commentary><examples>The puppeteer made the marionettes come to life.
            WIth a flip of the wall switch, machines began humming and whirring, and coming to life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idioms</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="14" name="However hard one tries" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: FOR_THE_LIFE_OF_ONE</commentary><examples>For the life of me, I don't see how we can fit this table into the dining room.
            For the life of him, Tom still couldn't understand what all the charges on the bill were for.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idiom</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="15" name="Attract special attention" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: LARGER_THAN_LIFE</commentary><examples>Problems can seem larger than life in the middle of the night.
            The famous singer walked into the restaurant, larger than life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idiom</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="16" name="Emphatic refusal" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: NOT_ON_YOUR_LIFE</commentary><examples>Not on your life would I let Mary's teenager babysit my toddler!
            John a conservative? Not on your life!
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version=""/><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>