<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="light-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="electromagnetic radiation" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+energy][+radiation][+electromagnetic]
            Note: refers to the waves that radiate and reflect off bodies, enabling us to see the bodies.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The speed of light is roughly 186,000 miles per second.
            There was a lot of glare from the light reflecting off the surface of the water.
            How long does it take light from the sun to reach the earth?
            The man was standing in a pool of yellow light at the foot of the stage.
            The police officer told John to step into the light.
            In soft light, she could still look beautiful.
            Herbs need lots of direct light to grow well.
            Astronomers would like to reduce light pollution in urban areas.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a source or body of illumination" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+entity][+source][+illumination][+lamp/+candle/+signal/+star]
            Note: refers to a body that is the source of radiation described in Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There were no lights on at Mary's house when we drove by.
            That small bluish light in the constellation is the star Sirius.
            A number of people reported seeing strange lights moving low on the horizon.
            Bob noticed that his engine light had come on again.
            From the hilltop, we could see the distant lights of the city.
            He drove through the intersection while the light was still yellow.
            The whole neighborhood was decked out in Christmas lights.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,14</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="perspective or orientation" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+state][+internal][+perspective]
            Note: implies a specific perspective, out of a set of possible ones
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            After speaking with Bob, we saw the matter in a different light.
            We are all viewing this problem in the same light.
            The audit did not put their company in a very favorable light. (a bad perspective on it)
            Let's put a more positive light on the situation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a state of understanding, comprehension" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+state][+internal][+understanding]
            Note: implies the understanding is universal with respect to something, not one of many possible interpretations (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The professor's lecture shed some light on the rather obscure analysis in chapter two.
            We saw light dawn on John's face when he finally got the joke.
            A warning light when off in her mind when she heard him use that tone of voice. (idiomatic)
            Bob finally saw the light about what's at stake with this piece of legislature.
            In light of their findings, new procedures were established. (based on understanding them)
            The guru promised them the inner light of truth if they followed his six-fold path.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,10</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="illuminated quality of pale colors" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+quality][+color][+effect][+illuminated]
            Note; refers to a quality of color on an object
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Lemon juice will brighten the natural lights of your hair.
            The artist dramatically used the darkest darks and lightest lights in his paintings.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a cherished or beloved person" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+entity][+person][+cherished]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Her granddaughter is the light of her life.
            John is the new light in Mary's romantic life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="daytime, period of visibility" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+state][+external][+visibility][+physical][+daytime]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The army will break camp and move out at first light.
            John decided to mow the grass while it was still light.
            They worked well past the light to finish harvesting the crop.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="public awareness, socially visible" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+state][+external][+visibility][+social][+public]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A young reporter brought this scandal to light in a four-page article.
            These back room procedures have needed to be brought into the light of day.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="emotional expression of the eyes" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+quality][+expression][+emotional][+facial]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We could tell he was joking by the light in his eyes.
            When Bob entered the room, I noticed the light in Mary's eyes.
            A strange light crossed her face when the incident was mentioned.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="igniter, match, device to make fire, flame" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+entity][+artifact][+device][+igniter]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            'Could you give me a light?' the woman asked him, holding her cigarette to her lips.
            He wandered the halls with his cigar in hand, looking for a light.	
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">15</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="a window or opening in a structure" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+entity][+structure][+architectural][+window]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            One of the lights was cracked in the mullioned window.
            The carpenter cut three horizontal lights in the wall facing the garden.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="an eminent person, leader of a field or cause" type="">
        <commentary>
            LIGHT[+entity][+person][+eminent]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He is the leading light of the Democratic party.
            The book covers such lights of the theater as George Bernard Shaw and Tom Stoppard.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="13" name="end result, finish" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: light_at_the_end_of_the_tunnel
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John can finally see the light at the end of the tunnel with his thesis.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idiom_1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="14" name="bedtime" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: lights_out
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It was lights out at 10 pm in Bob's military school.
            After lights out, little Johnny would read under the covers with a flashlight.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idiom_2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="15" name="fall asleep quickly" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: out_like_a_light
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The baby went out like a light as soon as Mary rocked him in her arms.
            After our 20-hour day of travel, we went out like a light at the hotel.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idiom_3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>