<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="lock-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="fasten something or become fastened" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Note: Use: fasten using a lock and a key, usually
        Includes: LOCK UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Don't forget to lock up the house when you go out.
        The door will lock automatically.
        I locked my bike to the fence.
        Lock the drawer even when you are in the room.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="lock_up" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>lock.01</pb>
         <vn>tape-22.4</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="place or confine in a secure place" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: LOCK AWAY, LOCK UP, LOCK IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        For punishment, they locked him in his room.
        She locked her jewels in the safe deposit box.
        She locked the pain away somehwere else and focused on what felt good.
        The old man locked the dog in the basement.
        Lock this prisoner up in that cell.
        Use this vacuum pack to lock in the flavor!
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
         <wn lemma="lock_away" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="lock_up" version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="lock_in" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>lock.03,lock.04</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Immobilization,Cause_confinement</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="(cause to)be fixed in a position, situation, or state" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The ship was locked in the ice through the winter.
        Here are some screws to lock the drawer into place.
        The therapist noticed that the patient's knees tended to lock during exercise.
        The mechanism tends to lock in cold weather.
        He locked his hands around his neck.
        The two dogs were locked in combat.
        She felt that she had become locked into a binding agreement. 
        I was locked in a frustrating argument for four hours.
        You are not locked into buying the parts from the same manufacturer.
        For a moment, their eyes locked. (compare to sense 4)
        Others stood frozen, locked in fear.
        They were locked in a laughing fit.
        Depending upon the lender, you may be able to lock in the interest rate.
        Large switching costs lock in a buyer once he makes an initial purchase.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,3,4,5,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="fix or aim something on a target, establish securely" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: LOCK IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The policeman locked his radar on the vehicle showing a speed of 86 mph.
        The pilot locked the enemy aircraft within his target sight.
        She locked her eyes on the man, matching his stare and curling her lip in a sneer.
        The strategy was to lock in the customers immediately.
        The only reason for inventing a new networking medium for this application is to lock in the consumer.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <wn lemma="lock_in" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>lock.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="pass or put a vessel through a lock, canal
         or river in a waterway" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        We lock through Montgomery Lock and Dam and move on.
        We are proud to say we lock through 6000 vessels of all shapes and sizes annually.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">8,9</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="prevent from entering or working" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: LOCK OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Management has threatened to lock out the workforce if they do not accept the new contract.
        He had to break into the house because his girlfriend had locked him out.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="lock_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>lock.05</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd,duffielc,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>