<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="lower-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="move to a lower position" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        A co-worker lowered the shelf with great force and hit me above the right temple.
        Well, I lowered the picture and the penguins looked at it with a lively interest.
        She lowered her eyes with disgust and stared at the crackling fire.
        Moments later an aide stalked out on the roof and lowered the flag again.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
 
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="reduce a measure of degree, quality or quantity" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Apple has quietly lowered the price of some of its build-to-order components.
        Should the drinking age be lowered to 18 or 19?
        The lack of rain had lowered the water level in the reservoir.
        The study found that watching television did not lower students' test scores.
        Lower your voice!
        The Homeland Security Secretary lowered the threat level for the nation's transit and ferry system.
        I decided to prepare for this film by lowering my expectations as far as they would go.
        Financial cutbacks have lowered the standard of infection control.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,3,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>lower.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="3" name="debase or humiliate" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: LOWER ONESELF
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I hate to lower myself to the typical blog begging you see around.
        Lecter would never lower himself to use bad language.
        Why oh why must Fairuza Balk lower herself to THE WATERBOY??
        Finally she had to lower herself to marry to a merchant.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <wn lemma="lower_oneself" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="4" name="modify vowel sound" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The Great Vowel Shift lowered their vowels to their current low-vowel pronunciation.
        Rule (7), which states that the short vowels are lowered relative to the long vowels, cannot be a universal.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="frown, look sullen" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He lowered with pain.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>