<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="market-n">
    <commentary>8jan08 - features added, examples added. ahouston
        24Jul08 added senses 4,5,6 and revised definitions, features and examples. ahouston
        19Dec08 - merged S2 with S1, revised definitions  ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a commercial system of buying and selling products" type="">
        <commentary>MARKET[+system][+commercial][+of_buying_and_selling][+product]
            Note: this refers to the general activities and rules that relate to buying and selling products
        </commentary>
        <examples>The economist is a strong advocate of free markets. (all such commercial sectors)
            Black markets spring up quickly in societies with communist governments.
            They took their house off the market when it wouldn't sell.   (refers to housing sector of commerce)
            The new medication was rushed to market before adequate testing was done.  (pharmaceutical market)
            The stock market was closed today for the holiday.
            The European markets were more heavily regulated than the Asian markets.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>market.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a public area set up for the commerce of tangible goods" type="">
        <commentary>MARKET[+location][+area][+public][+for_commerce][+of_goods][+tangible]
            Note: choose this sense when 'market' refers to specific locations where food and crafts are sold.
        </commentary>
        <examples>Sally and Mary like to visit the local farmers markets during the summer months.	
            They enjoyed the open air market in a Parisian neighborhood.
            We can buy lunch at one of the food stalls in the market in the town square.
            The local produce is brought to the central market by trucks and vans.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the level or amount of trading on the stock market in a timeframe" type="">
        <commentary>MARKET[+quantity][+measure][+of_activity][+trading][+on_stock_market]
            Note: choose this sense when activity level of stock market trades is implied
        </commentary>
        <examples>The long term trend for the market is looking bullish now.  (activity will involve selling at higher prices)
            The major markets around the world were quiet today, with very little trading.  (not much activity)
            Recent trends are an indication of another big market crash.  (dramatic overselling activity)
            The jittery market these past weeks is largely due to the uncertainty of oil prices.  (somewhat chaotic trading activity)
            The bottom fell out of the market during the financial panic.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2d</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="demand, the potential buyers of a given good or service" type="">
        <commentary>MARKET[+collection][+people][+role][+buyer][+potential][+with_demand]
            Note: Use this sense when 'demand'  can be substituted for 'market' with approximately the same meaning.
        </commentary>
        <examples>There is a huge market now for hand-held electronic devices.
            Their business model assumes a growing market for this service, which is questionable.
            Before they publish any book they try to determine the size of the market for it.
            There is a diminishing market in Japan for these products.
            The job market has picked up while the housing market has remained soft.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a grocery store" type="">
        <commentary>MARKET[+artifact][+building][+store][+grocery]
            Note: Choose this when 'grocery store' is a good substitution.
            Note: compare this with S3, which is usually more of an outdoor set of stalls, or tables
        </commentary>
        <examples>I picked up bread and milk at the convenience market on the way home.
            Mary shops at three different markets to get the best prices on cereal, detergent and canned goods.
            They are opening a big new health food market in the shopping mall.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>