<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="match-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="correspond or be compatible with, be equal to, fulfill or satisfy" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 MATCH NP2
        Note: neither NP1 nor NP2 sets a standard against which to measure the other
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Brown matched the Nets' Rick Barry shot for shot.
         The Rams matched the Washington Redskins' six-year contract offer with Butler.
         The two stories don't match in many details
         I found shoes to match my sweater.
         I found the jigsaw piece that matches that one.
         These footprints don't match his shoe size.
         Nothing can match cotton for durability
         The company matched the discount policy of its competitors
         I couldn't match her ability at the pool table.
         This hotel doesn't match my standards of cleanliness.
         Her vacation did not match her expectations.
         The course experience matched my expectations.

      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,4,5,6,8,9,10</wn>
         <omega/><pb>match.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Compatibility,Evaluate_comparison</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="provide funds complementary to" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The company will match one dollar for every dollar you put in your 401K.
         He matched 1 dollar for every 4 that we brought in for his charity.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>match.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="to pair or couple people or things" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] MATCH NP2 PP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         She will try to match her daughter with that wealthy European bachelor.
         Each dancer with a red ribbon was matched with a dancer wearning a blue ribbon.
         The movie matched the theme of having great wealth with that of wanting just a simple life.
         Airline passengers have discovered that their names were mistakenly matched with those appearing on federal watch lists.
         30,000 people said they were mistakenly matched to names on the list.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>amalgamate-22.2</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="oppose or pit against" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The game matched the league's best defensive teams.
         The third place game matched the California Quake with Sharp Edge.
         In this game, you will be matched against one of the other people in the room.
         Let them match their best athletes against ours.
         Match a chess player against the Russian champion.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>