<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="mix-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="commercially prepared dry food mixture" type="">
        <commentary>
            MIX[+artifact][+food][+dry][+prepared][+commercially][+mixture]
            Note: a special, narrow usage of Sense 2.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Betty said the cake was made from a mix.
            I like to keep biscuit and muffin mixes in the pantry.
            You only add eggs and butter to this brownie mix.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a blended substance from separate components" type="">
        <commentary>
            MIX[+substance][+blended][+from_components][+separate]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This green pigment is a mix of blue and yellow.
            The forecast for tomorrow is a wintry mix.  (combination of snow, rain and ice)
            Mary's homemade party mix is salted cashews, pretzels, and buttered wheat chex. 
            The bartender uses his own secret mix to make a whiskey sour.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="proportions of different constituents forming a whole" type="">
        <commentary>
            MIX[+collection][+subsets][+proportions][+of_whole]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their school has a good social mix of students.
            Sally's parties usually have an interesting mix of writers, painters and actors.
            The manager wants a mix of both full-time and part-time staff in her department.
            The movie's plot offers a good mix of romance and suspense. 
            The hotel's decor is a strange mix of antique and modern furnishings.
            This city is a fascinating mix of cultures and different languages.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the act of combining, blending, integrating" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            MIX[+event][+combining][+blending]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The bartender's mix of the martini took less than a minute.
            The mix of cooler water into the warmer water causes an upwelling of nutrients in the ocean.
            The student's thoughtless mix of the two chemicals caused an explosion in the lab.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="combined audio tracks in a recording" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            MIX[+artifact][+media][+audio][+combined_tracks]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The senior sound engineer approved the final mix of the recording.
            The rock singer didn't care for the dance mix of his most famous hit.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1e</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>