<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="mount-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="secure or put something in/on/to something else" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 MOUNT NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Mount the brackets to the fan, tighten bolts and pass the fan into the attic.
        I finally got one and removed the wheels and mounted the chair in the sleigh.
        A rigid frame mounts the engine far behind the front axle line for better handling.
        The tape allows consumer to mount pictures in frames.
        The children's work has been mounted on cards and put up on the walls of the classroom.
        The CCTV camera is mounted above the main door.
        You need to mount the CD before you can use it.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>mount.03</pb>
         <vn>put-9.1</vn><fn>Attaching,Placing</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="increase in amount, extent, or intensity" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 MOUNT
        Includes: MOUNT UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Costs are mounting up quickly. 
        Stress and fear mounted twisting my stomach into knots.
        The children's excitement is mounting as Christmas gets nearer.
        It isn't a good idea to let bills mount up.
        The stress is mounting up as the driving test looms.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="organize, prepare, and set in motion" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[agent] MOUNT NP2[patient]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The Flea Theater mounted the play in January with a rotating cast of celebrity actors.
        He mounted an army to &quot;free their holy land&quot; and marched onward.
        Colonel N. Kumar mounted an Army expedition to Teram Kangri peaks as a counter-exercise.
        By moving a Man to M7, I can mount an attack on Michael.
        We mounted a campaign asking people to send a small bag of rice to the needy.
        They took the debate public when they  mounted the exhibition 'Rembrandt/Not Rembrandt'.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,7</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>establish-55.5-1</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="get up on, place onself upon" type="">
      <commentary>
        Inludes: MOUNT UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Bobby crept up to the table and mounted the chair.
        She mounted up the horse and rode off.
        He mounted the platform and began to speak to the assembled crowd.
        Uncle Phil mounted his bike and they raced to the first stop sign.
        She mounted the waves in proud defiance.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <wn lemma="mount_up" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>mount.01,mount.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>Board_vehicle</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="go up, climb something gradually" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        We mounted the hill to a Roman ruin called the Magne Tower.
        The girls mounted the mountain, gossiping, and singing. 
        The young man slowly mounted the stairway, stopping from time to time.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>mount.01</pb>
         <vn>meander-47.7</vn>
         <fn>Traversing, Path_shape</fn> 
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="mate, breed" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        As the stallion mounts, the mare handler should walk her up a few steps.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>