<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="net-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an interconnected system of computers" type="">
        <commentary>
            NET[+system][+interconnected][+computer]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John set up a local area net in his house.
            You can probably find that antique book somewhere for sale on the Net.
            I check the local weather on the Net every morning.
            Personal data should always be encrypted when sending it over the Net.
            The new website gives that firm a compelling Net presence.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a mesh trap to catch creatures" type="">
        <commentary>
            NET[+artifact][+trap]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The fishermen laid their nets out in the calm waters of the bay.
            Have you ever caught butterflies with a net?
            He was caught in a net of lies. (metaphoric)
            The terrorist escaped the nets of several governments. (metaphoric)
            The huge scallop nets used by some fishing vessels destroy the ocean floor ecology.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="profit, revenues minus cost" type="">
        <commentary>
            NET[+quantity][+profit]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The firm's net income last quarter exceeded two million dollars.
            What was the net at the box office last night?
            His father's net estate after taxes was only a few thousand dollars.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="equipment in sports games" type="">
        <commentary>
            NET[+equipment][+sports]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The ball hit the net on the first serve.
            That goalie never lets a ball touch his net.
            John helped take down the volleyball nets after the picnic.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="mesh fabric" type="">
        <commentary>
            NET[+fabric][+mesh]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sally wore green net stockings to work yesterday.
            Those food workers wear hair nets and gloves.
            We slept in hammocks that were rope woven into nets.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>