<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="note-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="A very brief written piece of information" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+entity][+document][+short]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I received a rather cryptic note from John about tomorrow's meeting.
            The captain made a note of the incident in the ship's log.
            The children got in trouble for passing notes in class.
            There were several interesting notes jotted in the margins of the book.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,1,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a slight or suggestive characteristic of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+quality][+characteristic][+slight]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There was no note of sarcasm in his voice.
            There was a note of uneasiness at the hearing.
            This soup has a lovely note of thyme in it.
            She has a note of gaiety about her.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="financial instruments in paper form" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+entity][+instrument][+financial]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He pulled out a stack of notes in various denominations as well as two signed bank notes.
            My husband had to co-sign the note at the bank.
            The robbers took only notes and bonds from the vault, but left the coin collection.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a pitch or tone of music" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+event][+sound][+musical]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The soprano held the high note in an astonishing pianissimo. 
            The meeting ended on a sour note. (metaphoric use)
            Everyone knows the first four notes of Beethoven's Fifth Symphony
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="being of special interest or importance" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+quality][+status][+of_importance]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He is a sculptor of some note.
            All sorts of people of note were at Mary's party, including famous directors and playwrights.
            It was just another restaurant of no note that went out of business.
            Other items of note in the news were the opening of the new museum and the closing of the opera house.
            It is of some note that the author of this bestseller is a fourteen-year-old.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb>note.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="written musical notation" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+entity][+notation][+musical]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She couldn't read the notes of the score fast enough.
            I believe the last note of measure five is a misprint in this Schubert score.
            Do you now see which notes you are supposed to play?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">1b</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="an observation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            NOTE[+event][[+perception]+observation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Management has taken note of employees who surf the web on company time.
            They took no note of the nondescript man sitting on the bench.
            I took note of the time when we left the airport.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">4b</wn>
            <omega/><pb>note.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>