<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="notice-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="advance warning or notification of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            NOTICE[+event][+speech_act][+notification][+advance]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Money market rates are subject to fluctuation without notice.
            The tenant gave a month's notice that he would be moving out.
            John is giving notice at work tomorrow.
            The party was impromptu with very little notice given to the guests beforehand.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="observation, paying attention to something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            NOTICE[+event][+perception][+observation][+attention]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His sarcastic remarks did not escape our notice.
            It's come to our notice that Johnny has been absent a lot from school.
            Take no notice of the man standing behind the stage.
            Her boss took notice of Sally's hard work on the project.
            The young singer has attracted notice in places like London and New York.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>notice.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a publicly accessible document that announces or advertises something" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTICE[+artifact][+document][+public][+announcement]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There was a notice on the library bulletin board about a poetry reading on Tuesday.
            She reads the local paper mostly for the notices about upcoming social events.
            The notice in front of the house indicated it would be up for auction next Saturday.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>notice.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a personal document that requests you to fulfill an obligation" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTICE[+artifact][+document][+request][+for_payment]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John has received three overdue notices from the library.
            Mary was surprised to get a notice for payment due from her dentist's office.
            I got a notice for jury duty in the mail today.  (it's a summons to me)
            The draft board sent out notices to 18-year-old men, requiring them to register for the draft.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>notice.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a short critical review" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOTICE[+artifact][+document][+review][+critical][+brief]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He only has time to read the notices and book reviews in his science journals.
            The director received several good notices for his latest film.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>