<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="panel-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="any rectangular flat component of a larger structure" type="">
        <commentary>
            PANEL[+form][+rectangular][+flat][+component][+structure][+wall/+garment/+layout]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This old station wagon has wood panels on its exterior.
            This coverlet is made of alternating panels of velvet and corduroy sewn together.
            The main screen of the application is divided into four horizontal panels.
            John was pointing at the second panel of the comic strip and laughing.
            The central panel of this 14th-century Italian piece depicts the Immaculate Conception.
            This house has panel heating. (floor or ceiling panels with heating conductors)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a group of people appointed to a committee" type="">
        <commentary>
            PANEL[+entity][+group][+people][+committee][+appointed]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The lawyers have not finished selecting the panel of jurors.
            We have assembled a panel of experts to study the problem.
            John has been asked to chair a discussion panel at the conference next month.
            The contestants will be evaluated by an international panel of judges.
            They mostly have Hollywood celebrities on the panels of that quiz show.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the soft padding under a saddle" type="">
        <commentary>
            PANEL[+entity][+artifact][+saddle][+padding]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The panels of these old English saddles are quite worn.
            Mary bought a new panel for her saddle.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a flat partition that stands upright, a screen" type="">
        <commentary>
            PANEL[+entity][+artifact][+partition][+upright]
            Note: refers to a whole free-standing structure, not a component of something bigger (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The cubicles in this office space are separated by eight-foot panels.
            The nurse put up a privacy panel beside the patient's bed while she bathed him.
            These panels can be moved around to create different spaces in an open area.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="an electronic console" type="">
        <commentary>
            PANEL[+entity][+artifact][+console][+electronic][+instrument/+switchboard/+solar]
            Note: refers to an electronic device, an instrument
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The pilot noticed a warning light on his control panel.
            The switchboard panel began to light up like a Christmas tree.
            Pete installed solar panels on the roof of his house.
            Mary dimmed the panel lights of the car a bit to improve her night vision.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>