<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="position-n">
    <commentary>
        Added sense for financial market holdings, added features, added example, modified definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="spatial location or placement of something/someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+location][+physical][+region][+coordinates]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That chair is in a position where I trip on it frequently.
            The enemy took up a position on our right flank.
            The guns were shelling the Germans' positions.
            The race horses took their positions at the start.
            I don't like the position of that lamp against the wall.
            What is the angular position of Venus to the horizon?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2,7,8,10</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="opinion, attitude, stance, point of view, assumption" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+state][+mental][+attitude][+stance/+opinion/+assumption/+viewpoint]
            Note; implies a cognitive actor who holds the attitude.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She has a rather Kantian position on ethics.
            Their position on gun control didn't convince the senator.
            That position on the structure of the solar system was disproved long ago. (someone believed it once)
            Let's take the position that interest rates could be higher next year.
            John wrote the company's position paper on open source software.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,12,13,16</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="context, situation or circumstance" type="Abstract">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+state][+social][+context][+situation/+predicament/+circumstance]
            Note: focus is on abstract context, not physical context (see Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We found ourselves in a very attractive position
            Raising three kids alone, that's a tough position to be in.
            He felt he was not in a position to judge the merits of the case.
            The company's financial position is grim.
            Try to put yourself in their position with a civil war about to break out.
            Their firm is in a favorable position to expand operations in China and Thailand.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="financial holdings of an investor, a financial market commitment" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+holdings][+financial][+stock/+futures]
            [+commitment][+market][+financial][+long/+short]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Traders were having to cover their short positions during the sell off.
            John holds a long position in energy stocks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="profession, job, function includes position in team sports)" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+role][+job][+professional/+plater]
            Note: implies a specific job or duty of some kind, not a rank compared to others (see Sense 6)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He has a position with the National Security Agency.
            John will assume my position in the office while I'm away.
            What position did you play in college basketball?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6,9,15</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="rank in a sequence, standing in relation to others" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+relation][+rank][+sequence][+social/+competitive/+commercial]
            [+quantity][+number][+ordinal]
            Note: focus is on the pecking order or standing, not a specific duty or job (see Sense 5)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The book moved up two positions on the best-sellers list.
            She is currently in first position in the figure skating championship.
            He batted in the seventh position in last night's game.
            Their family enjoyed a high social position in the town for generations.
            Several of his would-be successors are already jockeying for position. (where they go in pecking order)
            The evidence is pointing to the highest positions in the government. (top dogs)
            He came from a lower socioeconomic position in society than his wife.
            They were taught to always know their position in life. (their status, not their employment)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,14</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a posture or arrangement, usually intentional" type="">
        <commentary>
            POSITION[+state][+physical][+posture]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He assumed the Lotus position.
            The position of the hands on the clock indicates it is nine thirty.
            The teacher showed the student the correct position to hold the violin.
            Can you show me the fourth position in ballet?
            The position of this major chord is C, E and G.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>