<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="potential-n">
    <commentary>
        1feb07 modified features of Sense-1, added commentary  ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a possible state, a future possibility" type="">
        <commentary>
            POTENTIAL[+event][+possible]
            Note: refers to a possible state of affairs that could happen in the future
            Note: occurs in phrases 'potential for X' where X is a possible, observable future event
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A stop sign could reduce the potential for accidents at that busy street corner.
            The director has been trying to identify and address all potential problems before the planetary launch.
            Betty argued that there is some potential for peaceful use of nuclear energy.
            The analysts now consider his potential for winning the next election to be low.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a latent capability or talent" type="">
        <commentary>
            POTENTIAL[+quality][+capability][+latent]
            Note: does not refer to a possible future -event- (Sense 1) , but a development of inherent ability, quality.
            Note: occurs in phrases 'X's potential' where X possesses an inherent quality
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The review says that the 24-year-old Australian shows great potential as a major dramatic soprano.
            Unfortunately, the potentials of the technology were never wholly realized.
            He saw the young entrepreneur's potential where others only saw failure.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="required work to move a particle in a gravitational or electric field" type="">
        <commentary>
            POTENTIAL[+quantity][+function][+work][+field][+electrical/+gravitational]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There is an electric potential at every point in space.
            Electric potential is work per unit charge.
            A book lying on a table has greater gravitational potential than a book lying on the floor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>