<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="prepossess-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="possess beforehand" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Notes: no examples found.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      *Mary had prepossessed the land before John.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="cause to be preoccupied" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[cause] PREPOSSESS	NP2[experiencer]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      The effect of this bodily grace is to prepossess the beholder.
      Mr. Peek is too much prepossessed by a liking for paternal government.
      Attenborough was prepossessed by his fascination with the subject at hand.
      His son John was by no means prepossessed by the appearance of his stepmother.
      South Korea is a nation prepossessed by social status and reputation.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="prejudice someone's opinion beforehand (often positively)" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent|cause] PREPOSSESS NP2[experiencer|patient] (PP[instrument|stimulus])
      NP1[agent|cause] PREPOSSESS NP2[experiencer|patient] PP[proposition]
      
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      As much as possible should be learned in the first lessons, in order to prepossess the pupils favorably.
      There is no occasion to prepossess the reader with an opinion of the merit and beauty of the work.
      Chatelart was prepossessed with an opinion that it belonged to the Duke of Nemours.
      Wyvis's handsome face and evident admiration of herself did not prepossess Margaret in his favor.
      His experience had not been likely to prepossess him in favour of the popular voice.
      Why will you prepossess your self against a Man that is Master of all Charms?
      It is no less certain that Maintenon had strongly prepossessed her against me.
      The Duchess of Valentinois prepossessed the King against it.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>prepossess.01</pb>
         <vn>NP</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="bonnj" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
