<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="press-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="reporters" type="Group">
        <commentary>
            Refers collectively to the newspapermen, writers, reporters, etc., who run the media.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            George W. Bush usually refuses to speak to the press.
            We'll be having a press conference tomorrow at noon.
            I put a &quot;Press&quot; tag around my neck to get past security.
            John was a member of the press.
            The Associated Press reported the results of the Indonesian elections this morning.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="urgency" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    PRESS[+event]
	    The quality of being insistent or pressing.  Being something that demands attention or immediate notice.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I've been hurried by the usual press of business matters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="news collection" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A general term for the collection and publication of news.  Does not refer to any specific people or organizations.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The freedom of the press is guaranteed by the First Amendment.
            An unbiased press is an essential part of a healthy democracy.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="printing machine" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A machine used for printing a large number of documents.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            In fourth grade I learned about the inventor of the printing press.
            Stop the presses!
            The mobsters smashed our presses before we could print the story about them.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="large crowd" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A tightly-packed crowd, usually of people.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I-95 is blocked up by a huge press of cars and trucks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="piece of furniture" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A tall piece of furniture that provides space for clothing.  Also called a wardrobe or an armoire.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John put his clothes on hangers and hung them in the press.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                6
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="machine that presses" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            Any device that exerts pressure on something.  Can be used to shape or form materials, or to keep wood from warping.
            Includes the weightlifting machine used to exercise shoulders and chest.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John bought a wine press and started his own vintage.
            Your brakes use a hydraulic press to put pressure on the wheels.
            When the shop class went home, they left their wood clamped in the presses.
            This morning I did three sets of one-seventy on the chest press.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                7 8 9
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="exertion of pressure" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    PRESS[+event]
	    The resultative noun of &quot;to press&quot;.  The act of putting pressure on something, such as a button.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The President can start World War III at the press of a button.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                10
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>