<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="present-v">    
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="show, deliver, put forward for consideration" type="">  
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The Ballet and Theatre will present their annual production of &quot;The Nutcracker&quot;.
        Rachel has presented her research at three professional conferences this year.
        The Flying Veal Chart Company proudly presents something very strange for show 3.
        The Games will be presented tomorrow to several countries.
        The speaker presented an inspiring speech that impressed the students.
        He took care to present his best side to the camera.
        That man used to present a very popular game show.
        We presented the arguments to him.
        He presented his complaints to the higher authorities.
        When the court reconvened, both parties presented their arguments
        to the jury.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,4,8,11</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>present.01</pb>
         <vn>fulfilling-13.4.1,reflexive_appearance-48.1.2</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="give, hand over, submit" type="">
      <commentary>
        Note: the simple act of handing over or giving something
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I presented my application to the bureaucrat behind the desk.
        The girl nonchalantly presented her money to the teller.
        Then he presented me with the bill!
        What gift will to present your love with this Valentines Day?
        The flag is then folded and presented to the next of kin.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,7</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>present.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="pose or introduce a problem, issue, or question" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Such actions presents a direct threat to national security!
        This presents an interesting question about the global structure of space.
        The faculty will present the students with a question by the end of this week.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>present.01</pb>
         <vn>reflexive_appearance-48.1.2</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="award or bestow honors" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The mayor came in person to present the prizes.
        The company will present awards for the best posters.
        Award winners were presented honors for the year.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>present.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="introduce somebody/something to somebody/something" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Permit me to present you to my friends of whom I was telling you at the ball.
        They were presented to the Queen.
        Her family planned to present her at the Christmas debutante ball in New York.
        Madam, permit me to present you to the security vault.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">9,12</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="portray or depict" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        In the film, Romeo and Juliet are presented as modern teenagers.
        Here, the artist has presented my grandfather as a hansome young man.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="offer or convey something formally" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The soliders presented salute to their commanding officer.
        May I present my warmest congratulations?
        I present my condolences to his family and friends.
        They wanted to present their respect and permanent gratitude to all.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="8" name="appear, happen, or come into being" type="">
      <commentary>
        Is: PRESENT ONESELF
        Note: Includes variations, like 'itself', 'yourself', etc.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Do something! The solution won't just present itself. 
        When an opportunity presents itself, take it.
        Present yourselves at the gate at eight o'clock. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>present.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="9" name="hold or carry a weapon as a salutation" type="">
      <commentary>
        To hold, carry, or point (a weapon) in a particular 
        manner as a salutation or sign of honor, usually 
        along the center axis of the body.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        After McLean had fired his revolver, he presented the weapon at her Majesty.
        After the war, Lawrence presented the rifle to King George V.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">13</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd, greenlm" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>