<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="prevail-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="win, emerge as dominant" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 PREVAIL[transitive] (OVER NP2)
        NOTE: in this sense, NP2 may be omitted. To test this sense, try to add &quot;over NP&quot;
              to the sentence.  If it is acceptable/natural/wouldn't make you cringe 
              if you heard it, then use this sense.
              EXAMPLE:
              okay: He has said he is confident that democracy will prevail (over other forms of government.) 
              not okay/weird: *Sunny skies will prevail (over cloudy skies.)
        NOTE: if the context is too ambiguous to determine the existence of NP2, choose sense 2.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The champion prevailed, even though it was a hard fight.
        The heroes prevailed against the enemy.
        I am sure that justice and common sense will prevail in the end.
        And did reason prevail over emotion?
        This technology will prevail over competing methods.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>prevail.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Finish_competition</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="exist" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1 PREVAIL[intransitive]
        Note: suggests that NP is prevalent, and therefore may have some influence
              in a given context, but not that it necessarily defeats opposing forces
        NOTE: if unsure of the inference of victory, choose this sense (see last example)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This is a region where snow and ice prevail.
        Sunny skies prevail across the northeast.
        The old customs still prevail in some parts of the country.
        This attitude still prevails among the middle classes.
        Fond memories will prevail for the team.
        This technology will prevail.  (in a context too ambiguous to determine if competing technologies are present)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>prevail.02</pb>
         <vn>exist-47.1-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="persuade or be persuaded" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: PREVAIL UPON,  PREVAIL ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He prevailed upon her to visit his parents.
        He was eventually prevailed upon to accept the appointment.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb></pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Attempt_suasion</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd, vieweg,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>