<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="producer-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a manufacturer or grower of commercial goods" type="">
        <commentary>
            PRODUCER[+maker][+goods][+manufactured/+grown]
            Note: can be human or artifact or organization
            Note: the production is purposive; for producer furnaces, people built the furnaces, so therein lies the intention.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our firm has been a producer of fine leather goods for two generations.
            Chile is a big producer of grapes and other fruit.
            The bill is supposed to help the small local producers market their crafts overseas.
            The output of fuel gas from those producers fell this year due to repairs. (furnace)
            They have been producers of good will around the world for decades. (metaphoric)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a financier of an entertainment project" type="">
        <commentary>
            PRODUCER[+person][+financier][+entertainment]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The producers of the new Broadway show lost a lot of money on that venture.
            Bill has been the producer of three hit comedies on television.
            The director and the producer have major disagreements about the film.
            The dance company is looking for a producer for its production of Swan Lake.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an entity that makes output as a consequence of other activity" type="">
        <commentary>
            PRODUCER[+output][-goods]
            Note: the source of the production does not intentionally do so.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our country is a big producer of pollution.
            I have read that termites are the largest producer of methane on the planet.
            Photosynthetic plants are producers of their own food, unlike animals.
            The producers of disease in the Third World include unclean water, malnutrition and mosquitoes.
            Astronomers finally discovered that quasars were the producers of the powerful x-ray radiation from deep space.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>