<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="program-n">
    <commentary>
        Added examples, commentary, split one group into two, revised definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="goal or strategy expressed in a formulated agenda" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+goal][+agenda][+formulated]
            a series of steps to be carried out to accomplish a goal
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their party is advocating a program for energy independence by 2020.
            The book offers a twelve-step program for fast weight loss in two months.
            The candidate described his energy and tax programs during his speech.
            John needs to get with the program!  (figurative)
            Bob follows a daily program of rising at six, running four miles, eating breakfast over email, then driving to his office by eight.
            The incentive program at our company has really motivated the guys in sales.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a performance, either broadcast or staged" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+event][+performance][+broadcast/+staged]
            a radio or television show, or public, performance (entertainment)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The program was an odd mixture of Stravinsky, Schoenberg and Scriabin.
            The program lasted more than two hours.
            The network has decided to cancel those two programs next season.
            Grandma gets up at 11:00 every day to watch her favorite programs.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a funded or sponsored public project or service" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+project][+public][+funded]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They worry there will be less money for the space program in coming years.
            Those children have benefited from several after-school programs.
            That church has a cradle-care program for infants during its Sunday services.
            Working mothers rely on the daycare program.
            The TVA was one of many government programs initiated during the Depression.
            Our rowing club is sponsoring a learn-to-row program this summer on the river.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a body of courses, curriculum of study" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+curriculum][+scholarly/+vocational]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The university is offering a new program in institutional economics.
            John's son enrolled in a vocational program at a local tech institute. 
            Bob is finding his premed program of study to be difficult.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a descriptive brochure handed out at performances" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+document][+brochure][+announcement][+theater/+sports/+music]
            an announcement of the events that will occur as part of a theatrical
            or sporting event
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The program has a brief biography about each football player.
            The program says there will be an intermission in an hour.
            Mary couldn't read the program notes very well in the dark theater.
            Let's pick up an extra program for Sally.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a code, a sequence of instructions" type="Computer Science">
        <commentary>
            PROGRAM[+code][+instruction][+sequence][+computer/+DNA]
            a sequence of instructions that, e.g.,  a computer, can interpret and execute
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John is rewriting all these old C programs into Java.
            Nasdaq stopped its program trading yesterday when the markets dropped over 200 points.
            The body's cells produce proteins according to the genetic program of DNA.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>