<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="project-n">
    <commentary>13sep06 - updated to WN2.1, added 2 senses (2 and 3), added features, examples. ahouston.
        17Dec08 - revised definitions and features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="An official task or undertaking, usually funded" type="">
        <commentary>PROJECT[+activity][+undertaking][+official][+funded]</commentary>
        <examples>The project to map the human genome took many years and many researchers.
            The funding agency has decided to go ahead with the pilot project on alternative fuel engines.
            During the Depression, the public works projects gave work to many unemployed people.
            John has not yet picked a research project for his senior thesis.  (an official stated problem or theme)
            The town did not have enough left in this year's budget for the downtown beautification project.
            The agent was assigned to a special project for which he had to go undercover. 
            These town projects are largely operated by unpaid volunteers.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a hobby, homemaking crafts and repairs" type="">
        <commentary>PROJECT[+activity][+homemaking][+hobby][+craft_or_repair][</commentary>
        <examples>The magazine describes several Halloween projects to do with children.
            Putting up the Christmas decorations will be a fun project to do when John and Mary arrive.
            Sally wants her husband to finish a few of the home improvement projects he started last fall.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">3c</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a low-income, public housing development" type="">
        <commentary>PROJECT[+collection][+artifact][+building][+housing][+public][+low_income]</commentary>
        <examples>Bob grew up in the projects on the south side.
            No neighborhood seems to want the low-cost housing project in their vicinity.
            Urban renewal tore down 19th-century houses and apartment buildings and built enormous projects in their place.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>