<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="prospect-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="possibility for the future" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            Most often the possibility for a person's future success, but can refer to any possibility for the future.
            Usually qualified by an adjective.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He has good prospects as a writer.
            I'm trying to improve the prospects for disadvantaged youth.
            The prospect of biological terrorism is constantly in our minds.
            Perhaps spending Christmas around a fireplace isn't such a bad prospect after all.
            What are my prospects for survival, doctor?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1 5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NP</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a candidate" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A person or thing that is being considered for some position.  Often used to describe job applicants.  A prospective employee.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The best prospects will ace the difficult questions on the interview.
            Anyone identified with the landlord was a bad prospect for marriage.
            With a hundred and fifty career goals, John was a good prospect for the hall of fame.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NP</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="literal viewpoint" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The view of something, usually a region.  
            Often used in the names of towns or places.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I lived in Prospect Point, Maryland, for two years after graduation.
            The hill has a great prospect of the valleys below.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NP</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="metaphoric viewpoint" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The 'view' or 'perspective' in a metaphoric sense; one's opinion of something.  Does not refer to expectations of the future.
            Often used in proper names; the popular magazine 'The American Prospect' refers to a metaphoric view of America.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John maintained a realistic prospect of his chance of success.
            What's your prospect on the situation?
            I wrote an article for The American Prospect.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NP</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>