<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="protocol-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="format and transmission rules for computer communications" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROTOCOL[+entity][+symbolic][+rule][+format][+communication][+computer]
            Technical specifications for how digital information is formatted
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            FTP is a file transfer protocol that enables users to copy files between their local computer and a remote network.
            HTTP is a protocol that transfers hypertext requests and information between computer servers and browsers.
            John is an expert on computer network protocols.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="codes of social conduct, rules of etiquette" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROTOCOL[+entity][+symbolic][+rule][+convention][+etiquette][+social]
            Norms of conduct, social behavior
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Protocol prohibits the Crown Prince from making public statements in his defense.
            What is the correct protocol at conferences when one's neighbor dozes during a talk?
            It was certainly a breach of protocol for him to decline acceptance of a Nobel prize.
            Bob didn't seem to understand the protocols required of a host at a formal dinner party.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="official written record of diplomatic agreements, treaty" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROTOCOL[+entity][+artifact][+document][+record][+official][+diplomatic][+agreement]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Both nations have agreed to abide by the new protocol.
            Negotiators are drawing up new protocols that will specify emission standards for the member countries.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="official written record of scientific or medical experiment" type="">
        <commentary>
            PROTOCOL[+entity][+artifact][+document][+record][+official][+experimental][+procedure][+medical/+scientific]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The protocol specifies the amount of increased dosage of the medication per successive administration of it.
            The drug manufacturer did not follow the published protocols for this new drug.
            A review by peer scientists is challenging the protocol described in this experiment.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>