<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="pursue-v">    
   <commentary>
	Note: No VPCs for this verb
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="seek or follow something" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Syntax Is: NP1 PURSUE NP2[topic[inanimate]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	The firm is pursuing an aggressive strategy to win market share.
	Critics felt the president was pursuing a reckless course. 
	Let's pursue this argument tomorrow.
	Can you pursue this matter before the next meeting?
	It is not known whether they will pursue an appeal.
        From 1991 to 1996, she pursued private practice in environmental medicine.
        From the beginning, she pursued the development of this yeast with single-minded purpose.
        City officials pursued a hunch that Mr. K received the discount.
        Christine pursued her entrepreneurial instincts.
        Doug pursued Bowerman's advice and in 1955 returned to Vancouver. 
        He pursued the interior life of spirituality with the same energy and focus. 
	Mary is still pursuing the perfect pair of shoes for her wedding gown.
	They pursued a northward course through the forest.	
        The road pursues a more northerly route.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3,4</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>pursue.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="2" name="chase someone" type="">
      <commentary>
	Syntax is: NP1 PURSUE NP2[patient[animate]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	The policeman pursued the thief through the alleyway and down some steps.
	Several Fortune 500 companies have been pursuing John. (figurative)
	Tom has been pursuing Sally for months to no avail. (figurative)
        Crazy Horse remained to battle General Nelson Miles as he pursued the Lakota and their allies.
        A United Nations peacekeeping force of technicians and superhumans pursued the robot into Afghanistan.
	My dog pursued a squirrel across the yard.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>pursue.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>