<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="quarter-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="provide housing for" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate|organization]] QUARTER NP2[theme[animate]] (PP[location])
      NP1[location] QUARTER NP2[theme[animate]
      NP1[theme[animate]] QUARTER PP[location]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Conan returned to the house where his company was quartered.
      He immediately ordered the village in which he had been quartered to be set on fire.
      They quartered the troops in an old factory building.
      This cantonment town quartered the British soldiers at the time of British Empire.
      I have quartered the troops constantly in houses, so that they have suffered very little.
      The soldiers quartered in the court- house, later the old city hall, and in the school-houses.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>quarter.01</pb>
         <vn>lodge-46</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="execute by tying a person to 4 horses and pulling them apart" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate]] QUARTER NP2[patient[animate]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Others participants in the revolt were condemned, some to be quartered, others to lose their heads.
      This morning Hacker and Axtell were hanged and quartered, as the rest are.
      Nikolas was quartered by horses in 1583.
      For me, receiving a blog award is like being drawn and quartered by bears.
      Robert Damiens was quartered by horses in 1757 for attempting to assassinate Louis XV. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>quarter.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="divide into quarters" type="">
      <commentary>
      Syntax includes:
      NP1[agent[animate]] QUARTER NP2[patient[concrete]] (PP[instrument])
      NP1[theme|instrument] QUARTER NP2[patient]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      Balder rapidly quartered the apple with a dagger.
      The shield depicts a yellow lion above a white field quartered by the cross of Saint George.
      Small fruits should be quartered by the method used for particulate foods. 
      The traditional Celtic year was quartered by the solstices and the equinoxes.
      An untanned, pickled calfskin was quartered by cutting down the backbone and across the waist.
      The resulting pulps were quartered by rotary splitter.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense></gr_sense>
         <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>quarter.03</pb>
         <vn>carve-21.2-1</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="bonnj" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
