<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="race-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a competition or contest" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RACE[+event][+social][+competition][+sports/+military/+business/+personal]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John likes to watch formula one races.
            Their candidate is expected to do well in the governor's race.
            The doctors performed the surgery in a race against time.
            The two firms are in a race to win the giant soft drink account. 
            John thinks the world is headed for another arms race.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="humans classified roughly by genetic stock" type="">
        <commentary>
            RACE[+group][+human][+shared][+genetics]
            Note: focus is on physical and (alleged/real) genetic traits.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary put down 'Caucasian' on the form as her category of race.
            Biologists do not believe the evidence is compelling for postulating genetically-based races of humans.
            The city was trying to avoid a race riot over the incident of alleged police brutality.
            The man did not want his daughter to marry anyone from a different race, creed or religion.
            Race relations are improving among the younger generation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="human cultural, religious or national groups" type="">
        <commentary>
            RACE[+group][+human][+shared][+culture]
            Note: focus is on a cultural or linguistic trait, not a biological or genetic one.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The story describes a brutal race of people who subjugate their peaceful neighbors.
            The scholar admires the literary brilliance of the English race.
            That religious sect believes they are god's chosen race.
            This river culture considers the mountain people to be an inferior race to themselves.
            The Slavic race lived in eastern Europe and parts of Asia.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2b</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a channel or groove to guide water or bearings" type="">
        <commentary>
            RACE[+structure][+channel][+industrial][+water/+ball_bearing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Something had clogged the race at the old flour mill.
            The ball bearings slide along a race.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a turbulent flow, as of air or water" type="">
        <commentary>
            RACE[+state][+physical][+flow][+turbulent]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Air driven backwards from an aircraft propeller is called the race.
            After the storm, the deep-cut mountain stream became a roaring race.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>