<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="rattle-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="emit short successive sounds by shaking" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Is: NP1[theme] RATTLE
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This beautiful snake rattled instead of striking me. 
        The curtain rod rattled angrily in response.
        The sun shade holder over the beer garden was rattling all night just below my window.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>rattle.02</pb>
         <vn>animal_sounds-38,sound_emission-43.2</vn><fn>Make_noise</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="shake up, impact" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes:
        NP1[theme] RATTLE PP[location]
        NP1[agent] RATTLE NP2[theme[concrete]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Only the butts of all muskets rattled angrily against the ground.
        The train lurched and rattled its way through the night winding its way through the forest.
        We rattled down the hill toward the village and its black castle of a colliery.
        The violent explosion rattled the windows.
        The prisoner rattled the bars of the cell.
        Engineers and researchers jolted, shook and rattled the house in a series of tests.
        We had an earthquake this weekend that rattled the whole house in Hollywood pretty well.
        When you rattled angrily at the door-knob she said very sharply, 'Who is that?'
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>rattle.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Cause_impact,Impact</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="disconcert, disturb" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] RATTLE NP2[theme[abstract]]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        And you shook me, rattled me right down to my soul.
        The book has rattled her enough to prompt further inquiry.
        The ascendant blogosphere has rattled the news media with its tough critiques and nonstop scrutiny.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>rattle.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Experiencer_obj</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="talk incessently" type="">
      <commentary>
        Includes: RATTLE DOWN, RATTLE OFF, RATTLE ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Our guide rattled down the names of all the kings, gods, temples and deities as we went along.
        He then rattled off a long list of the miracles the machine could achieve.
        Except for one parent who rattled on nonstop, the rest were really nice.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="rattle_down" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="rattle_off" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="rattle_on" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>Communication_noise</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>