<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="reception-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="manner of greeting" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            The manner in which something is greeted or received.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A stunned silence was the only reception to John's proposal.
            The speaker met an icy reception from the crowd.
            The launch of Intelli-Soft's new product had an unimpressive public reception.
            One of the most notable features of the book's reception in America is the questioning of the author's patriotism.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="social gathering" type="">
        <commentary>
	    RECEPTION[+event]
	    A formal gathering of people, often after a wedding.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            We got married in a church and held our reception in a large catering hall.
            They held a small reception to honor the visiting professor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="act of receiving" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RECEPTION[+event]
	    Any act of getting or receiving something-- a football, for example.
	    Can refer to electronic communication, but only as a specific instance of transmission.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            He made a record number of receptions during his football career.
            John is much more interested in the reception of Christmas gifts than the giving of them.
            I sent the letter last week, but there has been no sign of its reception.
            His reception of my broadcast occurred at ten o'clock this morning.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4 5 
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="quality of broadcast" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            The manner in which an electronic signal is received.  The quality or fidelity of a received broadcast.
            The phrase &quot;no reception&quot; is usually taken to mean &quot;poor reception&quot; in this context.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Let me call you back-- I get terrible reception on this phone.
            Let me call you back-- I don't get any reception on this phone.
            Our message lacked several key points of information due to disrupted reception during the broadcast.
            I started to get static in my reception of the radio station.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>