<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="recognition-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the state of being publicly admired, acknowledged" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+state][+social][+acknowledgment][+public][+admiration]
            Note: can refer to a work or a person, does not imply indebtedness
            Note: describes the well-regardedness of something or someone
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The 19th-century composer's work received little recognition during his lifetime.
            The film received a lot of recognition at several recent film festivals. 
            The recognition of Shakespeare as the greatest writer in the English language is universal.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the identification or the realization of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+state][+cognitive][+realization]
            [+event][+mental][+identification][+of_object]
            Note: when used to refer to 'recognition' by intelligent machines, the use is perhaps a metaphoric extension, wrt a 'mental event'.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's recognition of her assailant from pictures helped the police find and arrest the man.
            There is increasing recognition that diabetes frequently coexists with other chronic diseases.
            The bodies in the crash were burned beyond recognition.
            Optical character recognition was a new technology at that time.
            The company is developing advanced image recognition software to identify human faces.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the act of offering thanks to someone for some deed on their part" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+event][+communication][+offering][+thanks]
            Note: implies a specific event of offering thanks, implies indebtedness on the part of the giver of thanks (unlike Sense 1) 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We should give John recognition for attempting such a difficult task, even though he didn't succeed.
            She received the award in recognition of her courageous human rights work.
            The author gave little recognition to previous writers who have clearly influenced her style.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the chemical bonding of complementary molecules" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+event][+physical][+chemical][+bonding][+of_molecules][+complementary]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Molecular recognition is the driving force behind all biological processes.
            The catalyst must be present in order for the molecular recognition of hormone and receptor to occur.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="official acknowledgment by a government of the sovereignty of another country" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+event][+social][+political][+acknowledgment][+of_sovereignty][+by_government]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their formal recognition of the small country led to the establishment of an embassy there.
            Mainland China was angered by Taiwan's recent recognition by several nations. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the acceptance of a  statement (or convention) as valid or true" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+event][+communication][+acceptance][+of_validity][+of_convention]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The treaty led to the recognition of the Rio Grande as the border between the U.S. and Mexico.
            His recognition as the ruler was only accepted by part of the country's population.
            The recognition of Pluto as a planet was recently abandoned by the astronomical community.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="the chair of a meeting's granting the right to speak to an individual" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOGNITION[+event][+communication][+granting][+right][+speaking][+to_person][+during_meeting]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Without recognition from the chairman, the senator from Illinois could not make his motion.
            Recognition was given to the congresswoman from Idaho during the last ten minutes of the session.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>