<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="recovery-n">
    <commentary>
        9nov06 update to wn 2.1, added features. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="recuperation of health, healing" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RECOVERY[+event][+return][+gradual][+health]
            Note: implies return of biological health of specific organisms
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My recovery from the flu took about a week.  
            He underwent a number of surgeries but never made a full recovery.
            The process of recovery is more difficult for older dogs than for puppies.
            His mind suffered a trauma from which there was no recovery.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>recovery.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the act of retrieval, regaining something lost" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RECOVERY[+event][+action][+retrieval][+possession]
	    The act of regaining or saving something lost
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The recovery of the stolen files became the CIA's primary objective.
            After I accidentally deleted my thesis, I used a data-recovery system to get it back.
            The deep-sea divers attempted a recovery of the sunken treasure.
            The quarterback made a nice recovery of the ball.
            The simple operation resulted in the recovery of his sight. (it was lost, now regained)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>recovery.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="return to a prior state" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RECOVERY[+event][+activity][+return][+prior][+state]
	    The return to a prior state.
	    Note: does not refer to the health of specific individual organisms. (Sense 1)
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The National Wildlife Foundation was thrilled by the recovery of the bald eagle population. (implies the number of birds increased to previous levels)
            The recovery of the forest after the fire was surprisingly rapid.
            He argued that tax cuts were largely responsible for the economic recovery.
            The rower has improved his recovery after each stroke of the oar. (original position)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>