<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="record-n">
    <commentary>
        Contains idioms, off_the_record, for_the_record, on_the_record, on_record, of_record
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="repository of past information" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECORD[+repository][+information][+past]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The footprints in the sand left a record of the murderer's path up to the beach house.
            Her diaries provide an interesting personal record of rural life in the 1920s.
            The fossil record shows the emergence of this life form during the Cambrian era.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="tallied performances or activities" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECORD[+activity][+performance][+tallied]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This stock's outstanding record is not a guarantee of similar future performance.
            The San Diego team finished the season with a decent record of 32 wins and 8 losses.
            He still holds the world's record for the 100-meter dash.
            Her voting record at the Senate shows an inconsistent pattern on tax reform.
            His record of auto theft and petty larceny is as long as your arm!
            Their firm has a pretty good record of turning in good quarters, even during recessions.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,6,4,8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="phonograph or sound disc" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECORD[+repository][+disc][+audio]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This rare collection of classical records was produced in 1930.
            His band has just cut its first record.
            I dropped the stack of records on my foot.
            Jane's record went platinum after only four weeks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="legal written document" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECORD[+repository][+document][+legal]
            Note: often occurs in the plural
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Records of property transfers and taxes were destroyed in the courthouse fire.
            You can't return that computer without a written record of the purchase.
            The records show that offshore transactions were conducted on May 17th, 1999.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="pertaining to public dissemination" type="">
        <commentary>
            RECORD[+idiomatic][+information]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We'll include a list of names of participant for the record.
            His remarks at the meeting were intended to be off the record.
            These analyses are on the record in their archives and available to the public.
            The FBI has determined that she is a partner of record in several offshore firms.
            He went on record stating that he'd oppose the new education bill.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">for_the_record</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">on_the_record</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">off_the_record</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">on_record</wn>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">of_record</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>