<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="relationship-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="connection" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            Used interchangeably with 'relation'.  Refers to any connection between two things, including people.  
            The bond between two things, treated as an abstract entity.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I see no relationship between your words and your actions.
            The two variables have an inverse relationship.
            The Wall Street Journal published an article on the relationship between unemployment and inflation.
            The relationship between a mother and her daughter is the strongest imaginable.
            First cousins have a relationship by blood.
            Unfortunately, John had no business relationships in South America.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1 4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="being emotionally connected" type="">
        <commentary>
	    RELATIONSHIP[+event]
	    The quality of having an emotional connection, very often of the romantic variety.
	    Does not refer to the connection itself.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            John's wife found out about his adulterous relationship.
            Are you in a long-term relationship right now?
            We ended our relationship three years ago.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="being non-emotionally connected" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RELATIONSHIP[+event]
	    The quality of having a connection, but not an emotional one.  Often used with business and international relations.
	    Does not refer to the connection itself.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Intelli-Corp's friendly relationship with Microsoft was a huge asset.
            A diplomatic relationship with China resumed in the 1970s.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>