<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="relief-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the alleviation of distress" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+state][+alleviation][+distress]
            Note: refers to the state of alleviation, or something which causes this state.
            Note: refers specifically to the recipient of the relief
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Much to her relief, he picked up the phone on the first ring.
            It was a relief to the nervous passengers when the plane finally touched down.
            The new medication gave Bob some relief from his back pains.
            The rains brought relief to the parched crops. 
            He said John's relief of anxiety can be brought about by meditation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2,7,9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>relief.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="legal redress or remedy" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+event][+legal][+redress][+court/+taxation]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The court awarded him a generous relief as compensation for past injury.
            The president has promised tax relief for the middle class.
            Sally got a tax relief from her big charitable donations last year.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>relief.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="someone or something in the role of a substitute" type="">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+relation][+role][+substitute][+entity]
            Note: implies one entity/person can replace the function of another
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The relief nurse was late for her shift last night.
            He is one of the best relief pitchers in the American League.
            Mary can be the relief at the registration desk while you go for a lunch break.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the act of providing aid or assistance" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+action][+assistance][+material]
            Note: refers to a concrete action by an agent to assist, not the internal state of relief of the recipient (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The famine relief supplied to the region was not nearly enough.
            John took his wife on a cruise as a relief from all her pressures at work.
            Relief workers are sifting through mountains of rubble looking for survivors.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>relief.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a pause or respite from something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+event][+cessation][+pause]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We ran back to the house during the short relief from the downpour.
            Jack's character provides a bit of comic relief in the otherwise tedious movie.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>relief.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="ongoing government welfare" type="">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+activity][+ongoing][+aid][+welfare][+government]
            Note: occurs in the phrase 'on relief'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He's been on government relief ever since his back injury kept him from working.
            They receive relief checks once a month.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb>relief.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="sculpture style where carving is raised from a surface" type="">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+quality][+style][+sculpture][+raised][+surface]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These Greek sculptors were masters of high relief.
            We studied bas relief in our art history class.
            We looked at the relief map of the national park. (represents elevations)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="military liberation of a city or town" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+action][+liberation][+military]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His battalion was involved in the relief of Mafeking.
            Her grandfather lived to see the relief of his concentration camp during World War II.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="a sharply contrastive quality" type="">
        <commentary>
            RELIEF[+quality][+contrastive][+sharply]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary  liked the photo depicting the red-tiled roof in sharp relief against the sky.
            The book puts the two opposing theories into bold relief.
            The setting sun threw the snow-covered peaks into relief.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>