<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="responsibility-n">
    <commentary>
        Commentary, examples and definitions revised by ahouston
        Added a third sense group, not in the original file.
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="duty or obligation to something or someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESPONSIBILITY[+role][+authority][+duty]
            Note: can occur in the plural or singular
            responsibility as/for/of  NP/COMP{+duty}
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Jane accepts her responsibilities as a mother very seriously.
            They accused the director of having shirked his responsibilities to the board. 
            A computer has the responsibility of tracking the missile's course in real time.
            Management never assigned clear responsibility for the oversight of that product's development.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the quality or trait of being reliable, accountable or trustworthy" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESPONSIBILITY[+trait][+reliability]
            the trait of being trustworthy or dependable
            Note: 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The great heart surgeon exuded an air of responsibility about him.
            I didn't see a trace of responsibility in the face of that car salesman.
            Who could doubt the responsibility of that kindly priest?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a consequence, often negative" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESPONSIBILITY[+role][+causal]
            'take/bear' responsibility means to accept the role as a cause of some possible or actual event or state.
            responsibility for NP{+consequence}
            Note: this sense always occurs in the singular.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Who should take responsibility for creating this mess?
            No terrorist groups have yet accepted responsibility for the downed jetliner.
            She wouldn't accept sole responsibility for saving the children, she said John had helped, too.
            The sign states that the club does will not bear the responsibility for lost or stolen property.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="American Heritage">??</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>