<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="rest-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a remainder, the amount left over" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+quantity][+remainder]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We ate the rest of the pie for dessert tonight.
            After a pleasant Friday evening, it rained for the rest of the weekend.
            As for the rest, they can fend for themselves! (implies a larger group)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a state of repose or relaxation" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+state][+relaxation]
            X{+subject} REST
            Note: implies a subject experiencing repose, not necessarily relief from an irritant (see Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You'll feel much better after a good night's rest.
            Everyone needed a rest after the month-long push to get the project finished.
            We got snacks at the concession stand during one of the rest periods of the game.
            Couldn't we give this issue a rest for a while?  (metaphoric extension, leave it)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb>rest.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the cessation of something unpleasant, relief" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+state][+change][+cessation][+irritant]
            Note: implies relief from a specific source of bother or irritant, different from Sense 2
            Note: REST FROM X{+irritant}
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We finally got some rest from the jackhammers in the street below.
            The fields lay fallow for a year to let the land have a rest from over cultivation.
            He could find no rest from the accusatory voices in his head.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a state of inactivity, relative motionlessness" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+state][-motion]
            Note: implies lack of motion or movement, refers to inanimate objects as well as animate ones
            Note: often in the expression 'at rest'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The rest energy of a particle is equal to its rest mass times the speed of light squared, E = Mc2.
            That athlete's pule at rest is fifty beats a minute. (body is still, not moving)
            Bodies at rest are always defined relative to a frame of reference, not absolutely.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>rest.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the state of death" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+state][+death]
            Note: a narrow, special usage of Sense 4, implies a living creature permanently inactivated.
            Note: often in the expression 'lay to rest'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Her grandparents are both laid to rest in the town cemetery. 
            After ninety years of living, he finally found his eternal rest.
            That old superstition has finally been laid to rest. (metaphoric extension).
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a physical structure that provides support, bears weight" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+structure][+support][+weight_bearing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Tell the children not to stand on the chair rests!
            The bird found a rest to perch on in the hemlock tree.
            This special rest holds a machine gun.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a musical notation indicating a pause" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+notation][+musical][+pause]
            Note: refers to written musical notation in a score
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The score indicates a full rest at the end of measure 16.
            The pianist believes this is a typo, the composer did not intend a half rest in the fourth measure.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a small interval of time without sound, a pause" type="">
        <commentary>
            REST[+quantity][+interval][+time][+pause]
            Note: refers to the actual pause in time during a musical or reading performance.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The singer has two whole rests before beginning the next portion of the aria.
            The poet used rests during his recitation, to emphasize the rhythms in the blank verse.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1c</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>