<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="restriction-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a state of limitation, as physical or cognitive" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESTRICTION[+state][+limitation][+physical/+emotional/+cognitive]
            Note: implies a natural contingency responsible for the limitation
            Note: does not imply a general principle, but some specific situation or contingency
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob has experienced some restriction of movement in his left arm after the accident.
            At one time the Van Allen Belt was believed to pose a restriction to human space travel. (natural hazard)
            The restrictions of our visual capabilities do not hold for bees, which can also see ultraviolet light.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a regulation, a rule" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESTRICTION[+symbolic][+rule][+legal/+linguistic/+combinatoric]
            Note: implies a general principle that can be stated as a rule
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The airlines have placed a restriction on the number of carry-on bags per passenger.
            You must accept the restrictions on the use of this software before purchasing it.
            Some restrictions apply.
            Selectional restrictions dictate what sorts of arguments verbs may take, e.g., agent, patient, instrument.
            Restriction enzymes have advanced molecular biology tremendously because they always cut DNA at identical points along the sequence. (they follow rules)
            The military curfew has placed restrictions on where civilians may go after dark. (decrees)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the act of confining, preventing or blocking something" type="">
        <commentary>
            RESTRICTION[+action][+circumscribing][+blocking/+confining/+preventing]
            Note: implies a specific action undertaken by an intentional agent
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The doctor advised restriction of activity until the swelling in the ankle goes down.
            This study examines possible benefits of fasting and calorie restriction for those suffering mental disorders of aging.
            Raising the interest rates is a move intended to create restrictions on how much money flows into the economy.  (it is an effect or consequence, not a decree)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>