<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="return-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="tax document" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            The document that gives tax collectors information about someone's liability.  What you file with the IRS.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His gross income was enough that he had to file a tax return.
            The IRS is auditing me because I lied on my return.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="homecoming" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    The act of returning to a place you've been before, often a home.  Refers to the moment of arrival, not the return trip.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            On John's return from Australia, we threw a 'welcome home' party.
            I made a sandwich after my return to base camp.
            You've been awaiting my return for years, haven't you?
            Pressing &quot;Enter&quot; on my typewriter caused a carriage return.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">2,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="going the other way" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    The act of journeying back to a place you've been before.  Refers to the return trip, not the moment of arrival.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I met John during his return from Australia.
            I walked uphill on my way to school, but the return trip seemed much easier.
            When you buy a round-trip ticket, you're paying for a return flight as well.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="giving something back" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    The act of returning an object, either to a place or to a person.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Upon the book's return to its rightful owner, the young lady was given a tongue-lashing.
            The day after Christmas usually fills our store with clothing returns.
            Making my library returns is a pretty expensive affair for me.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="yields on investment" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            Usually refers to the income from land or other property. 
            Can also be used more vaguely, to mean good things that arise from something else (e.g. I wish you many happy returns). 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My investment has a return of about five percent annually.
            Many happy returns in the new year.
            The projected return is too low for me to take the risk.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.04</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="repeated happening" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    The recurrence of an event, action, or phenomenon.  When something happens that has happened before.
	    This is a metaphoric kind of &quot;arrival&quot;, when something has not necessarily moved.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The birds typically fly back just before the return of spring.
            John's return as Hamlet on the London stage was applauded by critics.
            I tried going to another doctor after the return of my illness.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">7,13</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="verbal reply" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    The act of responding to something that has been said.  A comeback or retort, often in a disagreeable manner.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I tried insulting John, but his sharp returns put me in my place.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.02</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="button on a keyboard" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            The button on a computer keyboard or typewriter (also called &quot;Enter&quot;) that causes a carriage return.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Be sure to hit the return key after you type your name.
            I became a free verse poet by hitting &quot;Return&quot; while writing diary entries.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="response to an act" type="">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    Used in a very general way as a response to an action or event, often in the sense of &quot;payback&quot; or revenge.
	    Usually only in vague phrases like &quot;in return&quot; or &quot;as a return&quot;.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            They scored three points on us, but we scored five in return.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="tennis stroke" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    A tennis stroke that returns the ball to the other player.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            John won the point on a cross-stroke return.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">11</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="football play" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RETURN[+event]
	    In American football, the act of running after a kickoff, punt, interception, or fumble.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            He dodged through crowds for a thirty-yard return on the kickoff.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">12</wn>
            <omega/><pb>return.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>