<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="reverse-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="change direction, become undone" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Note: Different from sense 3 because there is no exchange of places
      Note: In this sense, something is being undone, not necessarily exchanged
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Rising export and import prices in 1987 reversed the trend of recent years.
        The new manager hoped to reverse the decline in the company's fortunes.
        The UNDO command can reverse your steps back to the first thing you ever did.
        Many of the deterimental effects can be reversed by moderate exercise.
        The Supreme Court reversed, ruling that the video implicated legitimate concerns.
            (compare carefully to sense 2)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>reverse.01</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="formally revoke or overturn previous decision or ruling" type="">
      <commentary>
        Note: This is a formal, legal usage.  Please compare carefully to sense 1; the Court can reverse 
        (change its stance or opinion) in sense 1; sense 2 specifically refers to the ruling or
        law being revoked or overturned.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The Court of Appeal reversed the earlier judgment and set him free.
        The council reversed their earlier vote.
        The boy is asking the court to reverse a ruling barring him from karate
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>reverse.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="turn inside out or upside down; make or become opposite" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax Includes: 
        NP1 REVERSE
        NP1 CONJ NP2 REVERSE
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        You can reverse the cloak and wear it with the lining on the outside.
        Choose any 3 colors to make this hat, and reverse the hat so you have 2 hats.
        So in some respect, Tim and I have reversed our situations; he stays at home and I work.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>reverse.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="go backwards" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She reversed into the parking space. (UK usage for AM 'backed')
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>  
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd,duffielc,vieweg" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>