<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="rise-n">
    <commentary>
        24AUG06 updated to wn2.1, collapsed wn senses 3,6 into one group. ahouston
        24AUG06 added sense 7, added features, changed examples and definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a measurable increase, gain" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RISE[+event][+growth][+amount/+frequency/+size/+strength]
            [+quantity][+amount][+gain]
            Can refer to any increase in strength, amount, frequency
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There has been a three-percent rise in prices across the board.
            The stock's rise began this morning when the market opened.
            They are concerned about the recent rise in crime.
            The pilot looked at the rise in pressure on the oil gauge.
            The rise and fall of the lecturer's voice lulled the students to sleep. (strength of acoustic energy)
            There has been a noticeable rise in the incidence of tuberculosis.
            Glacial melting will lead to a rise in sea levels around the globe.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>propbank.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Upward motion or movement" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    RISE[+event][+action][+physical][+movement][+upward]
	    A physical event of moving upwards
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            They cheered the rise of the hot-air balloon.
            I like to wake up before the rise of the sun. (apparent to our frame of reference)
            John begins his rise from bed at about noon.
            They continue to build more high rises in Vancouver. (orientation is upwards)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>rise.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Slope" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            RISE[+entity][+structure][+geographical][+static][+upthrust]
            A piece of land or other physical object that has an upward slope.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The car couldn't make it up the rise.
            We climbed to the top of the rise and looked down on the village below.
            The road has a steep rise to it just outside of town.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a strong emotional reaction" type="">
        <commentary>
	    RISE[+event][+state][+emotional][+reaction][+strong]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's political remarks got a rise out of John.
            I hoped to get a rise out of Bob by repeating everything he said.
            It was so hot, not even the postman delivering mail could get a rise out of the dogs.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW-online">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="wave or moving ridge" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            RISE[+entity][+structure][+geographical][+dynamic][+wave][+water/+earth]
            A wave that lifts the surface of the water or the ground.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The surfer caught the rise as it approached.
            The earthquake created a twisting, two-foot rise along its fault line.
            You can get twenty-foot rises on this beach when there is a storm at sea.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="development, origin or appearance of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            RISE[+event][+appearance][+origin/+development]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The rise of civilization probably began in Mesopotamia.
            The dictator's actions gave rise to an organized rebellion against him.
            The book tracks the meteoric rise and fall of his political career.
            The Kyoto Protocol has begun its rise from obscurity.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW-online">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="vertical distance between two positions" type="">
        <commentary>
            RISE[+quantity][+distance][+vertical][+step/+slope/+trousers]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The carpenter created the staircase with a six-inch rise. (height of each step)
            The tailor measured the rise of the trousers from the crotch to the waistline.
            The rise of this slope is one foot for every three horizontal feet.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">
                1e
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>