<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="risk-n">
    <commentary>Included the idiom at_risk
        11dec08 merged S2 with S3. Revised features and commentary. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a source or agent of harm, a threat" type="">
        <commentary>RISK[+role][+agent][+cause][+of_harm][+threat]
            Note: Choose this sense if 'menace' or 'threat' can be substituted for 'risk'
        </commentary>
        <examples>The high-speed traffic on that road is a risk to the wildlife that cross it.
            Nuclear waste could present a contamination risk for the water supply.
            This medication may pose risks for pregnant women.
            All this dry underbrush is creating a serious fire risk.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="Do Not Choose: Placeholder Sense" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the probability or likelihood of a bad outcome" type="">
        <commentary>RISK[+quantity][+measure][+probability][+of_outcome][+bad]
            Note: Choose this sense if 'risk' can be easily replaced with 'probability' or 'chance'
        </commentary>
        <examples>This insurance policy explicitly does not cover flood risk.
            The risk of a heart attack is greater for smokers than for non-smokers.
            He was considered a poor risk for that new surgical procedure. (low probability of success)
            Junkies and prostitutes engage in behavior that is high risk. (implies high probability of something bad)
            This drug has only a low risk of side effects.
            There is more risk capital available than before for startups. (capital for funding endeavors with uncertain outcomes)
            The NASA director chatted about the risks and rewards of overseeing a planetary launch. 
            Navigating the two nations towards a peace settlement is not without risk. 
            Clean your wound every day to reduce the risk of infection.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3,4</wn><omega/>
            <pb>risk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="vulnerable to a specific harm or peril" type="">
        <commentary>Idiom: at risk</commentary><examples>These children are considered to be the most at risk for dropping out of school.
            With its stock plummeting, that company may be at risk for a hostile takeover.
            Why put yourself at risk unnecessarily, get your flu vaccination today.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="Merriam-Webster online">idiom</wn><omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>