<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="satisfaction-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="good feelings" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            A pleasant feeling that people can experience.
            Can't be increased or decreased; can't begin or end.  It's just a feeling.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I got the feeling of satisfaction that comes from a job well done.
            Dull, repetitious work gives him no satisfaction.
            It was with great satisfaction that I sampled the chef's new sauce.
            Some of the most famous words in rock'n'roll are, &quot;I can't get no satisfaction.&quot;
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="state of being satisfied" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            The quality of being satisfied, or the level of being satisfied.  It can be increased or decreased, and it can begin or end.
            The phrase &quot;to his satisfaction&quot; means &quot;to the point where his state of satisfaction begins&quot;.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We're constantly working to increase customer satisfaction.
            Customer satisfaction is our greatest goal.
            When taking the driver's test, you must perform to the satisfaction of your examiner.
            My satisfaction with your product abruptly ended when you raised your prices.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="fulfilling a desire" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SATISFACTION[+event]
	    The act of fulfilling a desire, need, or appetite.  Usually an instantaneous event.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The satisfaction of John's incredible appetite didn't occur until the ninth serving of dumplings.
            All he really craves is the satisfaction of his perverse sexual desires.
            Unfortunately, we haven't been able to achieve the satisfaction of your demands.
            The satisfaction of my demand for coal occurred when I received a truckload of it yesterdays.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="something that is owed" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            Refers to an object (usually money) or an abstraction (usually honor) that one person owes to another.  
            Usually compensation for some wrongdoing.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            When they robbed his house, he came to me looking for satisfaction.
            Sir, I demand satisfaction!
            We were unable to get satisfaction from the local store after they bungled our order.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>