<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="scale-n">
    <commentary>
        17oct06 update to wn2.1, combined senses 2 and 3, added examples   ahouston
        22oct06 added sense 7, added features, modified definitions. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="abstract system of measurements, graduated according to some rule" type="">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+system][+measurement][+graduated][+magnitude]
            Note: refers to the system of graduated markings, measurements
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Judging on a scale of 1 to 10, today was a 9.
            How bad is the pain on a scale of 1 to 10?
            These employees are at the top of the pay scale in their industry.
            The two friends came from opposite ends of the social scale. (figurative extension)
            They converted the numbers to a binary scale. (2-value system)
            The vertical axis is given on a logarithmic scale.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the relative magnitude or size of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+quantity][+magnitude][+relative]
            Note: refers to a quantitative size, ratio or relative magnitude
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They entertained on a grand scale.
            Mass production has lead to economies of scale in many industries. (bigger scale is cheaper)
            The scale of this map is 1:2500.  (a ratio of size to something else)
            Mary's boutique started out on a small scale, but grew quickly.
            The model is not drawn to scale. (not a uniform mapping of size compared to the original)
            These processes occur over very large time scales, e.g., tens of millions of years.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Placeholder sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>   
        </commentary>
        <examples>
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a device that measures weight" type="">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+entity][+physical][+artifact][+device][+measuring][+weight]
            a tool for measuring, often weight.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John weighs himself every morning on the bathroom scale.
            Use the postage scale to see how many stamps this package will need.
            The sign over the door of the apothecary depicted a pair of scales.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="protective sheath covering something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+entity][+physical][+covering][+sheathing][+protective][+plant/+animal/+garment]
            plates of skin or shell (or metal) forming a covering
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            That fish has pretty irridescent scales.
            We closely examined the scales on the moth's wings.
            This lotion will smooth away scales of dead, dry skin and leave your face smoother and younger-looking.
            This type of arrow can easily pierce the types of scale armor sewn onto leather.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="notes" type="Music">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+system][+sequence][+cyclic][+note][+musical]
            a series of notes differing in pitch according to a specific scheme
            Note: a specific, technical and narrow use of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The second movement of the concerto is written in a minor scale.
            He illustrated the scale of C major by playing its sequence of notes on the piano.
            They could hear the soprano singing scales in the practice room.
            Indian music uses different scales than most Western music, employing quarter tones.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a deposit or residue" type="">
        <commentary>
            SCALE[+entity][+physical][+covering][+coating][+substance][+deposit][+residue]
            Note: similar to Sense 5 in terms of a covering, but it is not protective in nature, just a residue
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The old tea kettle had a build-up of scale inside it.
            The dental hygienist removed scale from the patient's teeth with a metal implement.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3a,3b</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>