<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="seat-n">
    <commentary>
        includes idiom: by_the_seat_of_one's_pants
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a space allocated or reserved for someone or something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+location][+spot][+allocated]
            [+position][+reserved]
            Note: focus is on the allocation of a position, not the physical artifact of support (see Sense 2)
            Note: does not identify a specific structure to sit on, but a position relative to something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We got seats to the Red Sox game for tomorrow night.
            John held our seats for us while we fetched drinks for everyone.
            There are no available seats in business class on this flight.
            Bob took a seat on the edge of the table.
            Everyone please take your seats and we'll begin the movie.
            This energy bill has taken a back seat to more pending issues in Congress. (figurative extension)
            The firm's president found himself in the driver's seat when the CEO resigned suddenly. (figurative extension))
            They added another 200 seats to the auditorium. 
            He may lose his seat in the Senate next term.
            She's in the hot seat now over this scandal. (figurative extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <wn version="MAC">1c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a chair or other object used for sitting on or providing support" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+structure][+support]
            [+role][+support][+sitting]
            Note: focus is on the physical support, chair, -not- the allocation of a position (see Sense 1)
            Note: refers to a specific, identifiable structure for sitting or support.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary is reupholstering the seats of her dining room chairs.
            These large rocks can serve as seats for our picnic in the woods.
            This is a special-purpose light-guiding seat for pilot lamps of electronic machines.
            The three-year old uses a potty seat in the bathroom.
            The convicted murderer will get the hot seat. (electrocution chair)
            The police found the man slumped over in the driver's seat. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,4</wn>
            <wn version="MW online">5a</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a center of authority or power, often a city" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+relation][+role][+center][+authority]
            [+location][+city]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Washington D.C. is the seat of the federal government.
            Our town is the county seat.
            Rome was the seat of power for milennia. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the buttocks, derriere" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+anatomy][+human][+buttocks]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She landed on her seat while attempting a jump on the ice.
            Children usually get their booster shots in the seat, not in the arm.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the back part of a pair of pants" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+clothing][+pants][+portion][+back]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The seat of these trousers seems a little large.
            John tore the seat of his pants on a nail.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="a manner of sitting astride a horse while riding" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEAT[+quality][+manner][+posture][+riding][+horse]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The riding instructor told Mary her seat was too far back when the horse did his jumps.
            You must have an excellent seat during dressage to impress the judges.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2b</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="using intuition and experience, not theory or mechanical aids" type="">
        <commentary>
            Idiom: by_the_seat_of_one's_pants
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She learned to sail by the seat of her pants.
            He just seems to be able to fix cars and machines by the seat of his pants.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">by_the_seat_of_one's_pants</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>