<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="segment-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a specified portion of a whole" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEGMENT[+relation][+portion][+specified][+whole]
            Note: refers to a subset, identified by some trait, that is part of a larger whole
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The younger segment of our population has not been vaccinated against small pox.
            Cargo transport is one segment of the airline industry that has been doing well.
            All segments of the Democratic party seem to agree on this issue.
            You've got a five-minute segment to air that piece on the kidnapping. (a portion of total time allocated to your message)
            Mary laid out all the segments of the pattern for the dress she was planning to make.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="an anatomical unit, comprising one of a series of similar units" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEGMENT[+structure][+anatomical][+unit][+sequenced]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The cake was decorated with segments of orange. (natural sections of the fruit)
            The biology students examined the dissected segments of an earthworm.
            There are three main segments to an insect body, the head, the thorax and the abdomen. 
            Which segment of your middle finger has the hairline fracture?
            These segments of DNA from two different species appear to have similar protein-building functions.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a topic within a larger production, as television or a magazine" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEGMENT[+production][+topic][+broadcast/+publication]
            Note: focus is on the subject matter, not the size of space/time allocated to the topic (differs from sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John wrote an interesting segment on single fathers for the local paper.
            The next segment of our program discusses the changing role of NATO in the post-Cold War era.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a geometric figure that is intersected by a line or lines" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEGMENT[+form][+geometric][+figure][+intersected]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A segment of a circle is enclosed between an arc and a chord.
            Figure 1 shows a horizontal line bisected into two equal segments by a perpendicular line.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the smallest distinct unit of speech, a linguistic unit" type="">
        <commentary>
            SEGMENT[+structure][+linguistic][+unit][+speech][+smallest][+distinct]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Vowels and consonants are distinct segments that comprise the basic phonology of a language, such as English or Russian.
            Stress and intonation are not considered segments of language, but are co-occurring elements of prosody.
            These segments are contrastive in some languages, but not in others.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1d</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>