<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="session-n">
    <commentary>
        6oct06 updated to wn2.1, added features, examples. ahouston
        6oct06 - merged sense 4 with sense 2, sense 4 is dummy sense. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="Formal meeting for deliberations" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            SESSION[+event][+social][+meeting][+official][+deliberating][+legislative/+judicial/+academic]
            A meeting for the purpose of executing a group's function.  
            Often refers primarily to government or &quot;official&quot; functions.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The President addressed a joint session of Congress.
            The legislative session doesn't begin until June.
            This legislation will be introduced during the next parliamentary session.
            The first session of the Water Buffalo Lodge has come to order!
            Mary is chairing one of the sessions at the conference.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="period of time used for some purpose" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SESSION[+event][+expanse][+temporal][+period][+purposeful][+activity]
	    A period of time allotted to some activity, often informal social gatherings
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm famous for my night-long cram sessions before big exams.
            The concert was little more than a friendly jam session with fifty thousand spectators.
            We had a pretty good recording session this morning.
            The two friends met after school for a short gossip session.
            When you log out of the program, the changes you made during your last session will be discarded.
            Class is currently in session, so keep your voices down.  (the time passing right now)
            Mary disapproved of Bob's late-night drinking sessions with his buddies.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a school term, the time it spans" type="">
        <commentary>
	    SESSION[+event][+expanse][+temporal][+term][+school]
	    The timeframe for an academic term.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The spring session begins on January fourth and lasts until May second.
            The session at John's school does not end until after Memorial Day.
            They offer two six-week sessions during the summer.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
            
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>