<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="settlement-n">
    <commentary>
        27jul06 merged senses 3 and 5, added examples, added features. ahouston
        27jul06 added 3 new senses from other dictionary sources. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the people who found a community" type="">
        <commentary>
            SETTLEMENT[+group][+people][+colonizers]
            the body of people who settle far from home but maintain ties with
            their homeland; inhabitants remain nationals of their home state but
            are not literally under the home state's system of government
            Note: focus is on the people, not the buildings, infrastructure (Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement worked hard all year to send money back to their families. 
            The settlement was wiped out by successive raids of local tribes.
            They are a religious settlement who do not believe in marriage.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="small town, village" type="">
        <commentary>
            village - 
            SETTLEMENT[+location][+physical][+town][+small]
            Note: focus is on the locale, the infrastructure of the town
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement was located in Virginia.
            There was no school or church in the tiny settlement.
            Several new settlements have arisen in the past couple of years along the river.
            It was a fairly large settlement in Queensland for those times.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="resolution of a disagreement" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            a conclusive resolution of a matter and disposition of it
            SETTLEMENT[+event][+resolution][+disagreement]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement of the dispute wasn't for several days.
            They finally reached a pay settlement with the union.
            The owner reached an out-of-court settlement with the plaintiff.
            Will there ever be a settlement to the problems in the Middle East?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>settlement.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the activity of colonizing" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SETTLEMENT[+event][+activity][+colonizing]
	    colonization
	    the act of colonizing; the establishment of colonies
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement of the New World by Europeans occurred over centuries.
            Israel's settlement of immigrants in the Gaza strip was controversial.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the voluntary legal act of bestowing ownership of property" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            SETTLEMENT[+activity][+transfer][+legal][+bestowment][+property]
            Note: implies a choice in the bestowment, unlike Sense 7
            Note: does not, of itself, imply a dispute (see Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement of the wealthy actor's estate took several months.
            There were some challenges by the heirs to the settlement of the family farm.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2a</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>settlement.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the act of liquidation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            SETTLEMENT[+event][+liquidation][+required][+assets]
            termination of a business operation by using its assets to discharge
            its liabilities
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The settlement of the company was on March 1st.
            They'll be auctioning off the assets as part of the settlement.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="the quantity or amount of bestowed property" type="">
        <commentary>
	    SETTLEMENT[+event][+quantity][+amount][+property][+bestowed]
	    Note: refers to a specific (sometimes unstated) quantity
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            She received a hefty settlement from her father's estate.
            The settlement of the younger son was smaller than he had hoped for.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2b</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>settlement.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="the subsiding of ground or a structure on it" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SETTLEMENT[+event][+activity][+physical][+subsidence][+ground]
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            A boundary wall, which has cracked due to settlement, is to be replaced.
            You can expect some settlement of your house over the years.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>