<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="shop-n">
    <commentary>
        Includes idiom: talk_shop
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a retail store with merchandise for sale" type="">
        <commentary>
            SHOP[+building][+store][+retail]
            [+role][+merchandise][+seller]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We bought souvenirs in the small charming shops of the Greek village.
            You can buy gourmet dog biscuits at the new pet shop.
            This is where all the shop girls from downtown go for a quick lunch.
            Can we buy a newspaper at that tobacco shop?
            You can visit our shop online. 
            They run a small public relations shop in New York.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a work area for manufacturing or repair work" type="">
        <commentary>
            SHOP[+building][+workplace][+trade][+manufacturing/+repair]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John's car will be in the repair shop all afternoon.
            The shop floor of their assembly plant has a great safety record.
            I believe that bottling company is a union shop. (workers will join a union)
            This machine shop ships parts overseas as well as within the United States.
            The shop called to say your car is ready.  (a repair place)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="instruction or coursework in a trade" type="">
        <commentary>
            SHOP[+instruction][+course][+trade][+carpentry][+metalwork]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We made metal boxes in shop class today.
            Tony is taking five classes this semester, including shop.
            Mr. Green is our shop teacher.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a trade or business, profession" type="">
        <commentary>
            SHOP[+activity][+profession]
            Note: used in the idiom talk_shop
            Note: used in the idiom set_up_shop
            Note: focus is on the activity of business, not on a specific location. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary told them she didn't want to talk shop over dinner.
            Bob gets bored whenever his brothers start talking shop.
            There is so much shop talk around here!
            These kinds of headhunters just set up shop out of their garages.  (start a business)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>