<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="side-n">
    <commentary>
        9AUG06 added features, examples, senses 9 and 10. ahouston
        9AUG06 split sense 3 into sense 3 and sense 4 ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="A POSITION beside something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+location][+proximity][+reference]
            A point or location in proximity to another location.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The dog sat by John's side to be petted.
            They always sat on the right side of the church. 
            The patient is experiencing numbness on the left side of his body.
            We swam to the opposite side of the lake.
            She stood by his side through thick and thin. (figurative extension)
            Right now it's night on the other side of the planet.
            There is support for this bill from both sides of the aisle. (implies physical proximity, opinion and social group)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>side.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="A SURFACE on something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+form][+extension][+surface][+box/+crystal/+building/+mountain]
            SIDE[+form][+extension][+surface][+figure][+mathematical]
            A surface of an object, e.g., a face or line
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They painted a growing tree on the side of the house.
            He examined the bottom side of the box.
            This style of diamond has six sides.
            The hypotenuse of a right triangle is always it's longest side.
            From a distance we could see the lava flow on the side of the mountain.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="groups in conflict or contention with each other" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+entity][+group][+social][+faction]
            Implies units of people in opposition, e.g., armies or teams
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Armies on both sides suffered terrible casualties. 
            Their side always wins at softball because they have better hitters.
            A fast ball struck out the side to end the inning.
            They are trying to bring the different sides together to negotiate a ceasefire. (implies people meeting)
            Time is not on their side. (metaphoric extension - time is not an ally, a team member)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an opinion on an issue" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+state][+mental][+opinion][+contending]
            Note: refers to the opinion on an issue, not people themselves (see Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There are two sides to every question.
            John didn't want to take sides in the argument.
            Mary wanted to know which side of the issue Bob supported.
            All the politicians claimed to be on the side of law and order.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a contrasting alternative" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+relation][+contrast][+alternative]
            Note: no implication of conflict with other alternatives, differs from Senses 3 and 4
            Note: implies a quality or feature from among a possible set.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He's a little on the heavy side.
            It brought out his better side.
            He is on the purchasing side of the business.
            It was a side of Mary we hadn't seen before.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="line of inheritance" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+relation][+inheritance][+biological]
            A family line of descent
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He gets his brains from his father's side.
            Sally is my aunt on my mother's side.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="large slab of meat" type="Meat">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+structure][+carcass][+dressed][+half][+animal]
            [+quantity][+portion][+half][+carcass][+dressed]
            A lengthwise dressed half of an animal's carcass used for food
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Go to the store and get a side of beef for the BBQ, George.
            The restaurant ordered several sides of pork and beef every week.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="horizontal spin, as of a ball" type="Sports">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+state][+physical][+spinning][+horizontal]
            The spin given to a ball by striking it on one side or releasing it
            with a sharp twist.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            George shot the 8 ball with side spin.
            That pitcher threw a great side ball over the plate.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="in a subsidiary role to something else" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+relation][+role][+subsidiary]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Both of these drugs have known side effects.
            He had a couple of mistresses on the side.
            Keep focused on the main goal and don't let the side issues get you off track.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3a</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="a dish of food auxiliary to the main course" type="">
        <commentary>
            SIDE[+substance][+food][+prepared][+auxiliary] 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'll have a burger, a shake and a side of fries.
            Many people signed up to bring side dishes to the potluck.
            You get a choice of two sides with your entree.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3b</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>