<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="sink-v">    
   <commentary>
     Note: Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) go down below the surface or to bottom of liquid" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SINK NP2[patient]
                   NP1[patient] SINK
        NOTE: This may be seen as a sub-sense of sense 2, with the
                   understanding of going down in a liquid.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        We think the ship was sunk by a freak wave.
        Britain sank warships as a gesture of disarmament.
        Four years ago, the canoe sank before it embarked on its maiden voyage.
        The Titanic was a passenger ship which sank (to the bottom of the ocean) in 1912.
        Enemy aircraft sank two battleships.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="(cause to) fall or subside to a lower place, level, or value" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SINK NP2[patient] PP[locative/temporal]
                   NP1[patient] SINK PP[locative/temporal]
        NOTE: may be used metaphorically; often has negative connotations
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The water in the lake sank several feet during the long, dry summer.
        Sink the bucket into the well and draw water.
        The wounded soldier sank to his knees.
        The exhausted runner sank to the ground.
        The sun glowed red as it sank slowly below the horizon.
        Student numbers have sunk considerably this year.
        Voice sank into a whisper.
        The wind sank toward the evening.
        The dollar sank again yesterday.
        He looked at the huge pile of work on his desk and his heart sank.
        He sank into deep despair when he lost his job.
        The family sank into a state of disgrace.
        The patient is sinking fast.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,6,7,8</wn>   
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="(cause to) pass into a specific state or condition" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[actor] SINK PP[state/condition]
        Note: Unlike sense 3, this does NOT imply deterioration of the state of NP1. 
              Note: There is not a strong negative feeling to this sense.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He sank into Nirvana.
        He sank into a deep sleep, and dreamed no more.
        Once home to an estimated 20000 people, Petra eventually sank into obscurity.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="(cause to) descend into a softer substance" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SINK NP2[patient] PP
        NP1[patient] SINK PP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The legs of the garden chair sank into the soft ground.
        That part of the building has been sinking into the ground for a while now.
        The dog sank her teeth into the ball and ran off with it.
        She sank back into her large cushion.
        I will sink into my bed and sleep for a few hours before going back to work.
        I sank fingers into soft sand.
        A big dog sank its fangs into the thigh of one of Gary's soldiers.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5,8,9</wn>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="(cause to) seep into something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1 SINK PP[locative]
        NP1 SINK IN PP[locative]
        Metaphorical: absorb meaning, make an impression, become felt or understood
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The water is sinking slowly into the ground.
        Smear a little oil on the surface and leave it to sink in.
        Borman gulped as the implications of Putnam's words sank in.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="sink_in" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="(cause to) invest, put money or resource into something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SINK NP2 PP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        On his advise, we sank money into a new housing project.
        He must have sunk millions into these theaters.
        The Senate recently sank efforts to raise fuel efficiency standards.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="dig or force into ground" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SINK NP2 PP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Sinking more wells is the best way of obtaining more clean drinking water.
        The first stage of building the fence is sinking the posts into the ground.
        To construct a cofferdam you need to sink pilings into the seabed.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="8" name="sports term: cause a ball to reach the 'goal'" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He sank the putt to force the second playoff hole.
        Chetri flicked the ball to Hossain, who sank the ball in the right corner of the goal.
        He sank the ball, threw a very good changeup and he had his best breaking ball ever.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>sink.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd, vieweg,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>