<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="situation-n">
    <commentary>
        Groups, definitions, commentary and examples revised by ahouston.
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the state of affairs in a given context" type="Abstract">
        <commentary>
            SITUATION[+state][+status][+context]
            Note: can be negative or positive
            Note: the context is often explicit, as a preceding adjective, 'romantic situation', as a following COMP, 'situation trying to help Mary move', or as a deictic to broader discourse context 'this situation'. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The political situation in the Middle East has taken many twists and turns of late.
            When you're in a social situation, be sure to stand up straight.
            Their company was in a tough financial situation.
            We cannot escape our human situation.
            John was depressed for years about his romantic situation.
            The military is trying to back out of this situation.
            I got myself into quite a situation trying to help Mary move.
            The network decided to pull two situation comedies last season.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="employment, job" type="Abstract">
        <commentary>
            SITUATION[+status][+employment]
            Note: this is a specialized sub-sense of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Being director of the labs will be a very visible situation for her.
            Bill hated his situation as foreman at the old paper mill.
            Just what is his situation at that company?
            John's new situation at his firm entailed a big raise in his salary.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="physical location or site" type="Concrete">
        <commentary>
            SITUATION[+location][+spatial]
            Where/how something is physically situated.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            If we change the situation of the sofa, the room will look more spacious.
            There's always a right angle at the situation of two perpendicular lines.
            The situation, or site, of the receptor is determined by a sequence of nucleotides.
            The situation of the moon and sun at the center top of the painting is quite symbolic.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>