<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="smell-v">
   <commentary>
     Syntax is: Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="perceive through olfactory sense" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The officer said he smelled a strong odor of alcohol on the suspect's breath.
        I smelled a llama because I am AWESOME!
        For years I thought it was the screen I was smelling.
        I knew I thought I was smelling camphor.
        You smell that? Do you smell that?
        When Patricia stepped back he smelled coffee rather than her perfume.
        He smelled her frying eggs and onions.
        I need to know if turkeys can really smell?
        Can dogs really smell cancer?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.01</pb>
         <vn>see-30.1,stalk-35.3</vn><fn>Perception_active,Perception_experience</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="perceive (metaphorical)" type="">
      <commentary>
        includes: SMELL OUT
        NOTE: do not include idioms listed in sense 8
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I smell trouble.
        But I was guilty and my 7 year old smelled victory a mile away.
        I think most feminists smelled them coming a long way off for the last ten years or so.
        I have the great instincts for smelling a problem possible.
        Instead, he smelled out the intruder and recognised him.
        I'm not saying the process is perfect but a number of the applicants can be smelled out right away.
        As drifts of bad checks massed behind him, he smelled out new green pastures.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <wn lemma="smell_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>smell.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="emit an odor" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1 [theme] SMELL
        NOTE: Carefully compare to senses 4 and 6
              In this sense, the quality of the smell is irrelevant;
              there is only a general emittance of odor
              This sense is almost always used with negatives and questions.
              (compare the negative for this sense--doesn't smell=no odor--
               to the negative for sense 6--doesn't smell=doesn't stink)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Sometimes a newbie makes a scented candle that doesn't smell when you burn it.
        It either didn't smell at all or the scent disipated very quickly.
        Looking at the picture, she remarked that while the flower was pretty it was too bad that it didn't smell.
        Does it smell? The initial stages of fermentation do have an odor, but it goes away after a few days. (making wine)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.02</pb>
         <vn>smell_emission-43.3,stimulus_subject-30.4</vn><fn>Chemical-sense_description</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="emit a particular quality of odor" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[theme] SMELL ADJP/ADVP
        NOTE: Carefully compare to senses 3 and 6; all three
              senses are related
              In this sense, the perceiver is making a judgement
              about the quality of the odor
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The 2/3 smelled like a gas leak as we went through Times Square and Penn Station.
        He smelled pleasantly of aftershave, without even an undertone of stagnant urine.
        He rode horses and he smelled horsy, leathery and pipey.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.02</pb>
         <vn>smell_emission-43.3,stimulus_subject-30.4</vn><fn>Chemical-sense_description</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="have a particular quality (metaphorical)" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        This case smelled bad from the start.
        Do you mean he smelled like money?
        He said the murder case smelled of corruption.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="stink; reek" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[theme] SMELL
        NOTE: Compare carefully to sense 3 and 4;
              In this sense, the unspoken odor is clearly bad-smelling
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I'm not surprised that mothers think their baby's waste matter doesn't smell.
        The locker room really smells.
        Do farts really smell worse in the cold, or does it just seem that way?
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.02</pb>
         <vn>smell_emission-43.3,stimulus_subject-30.4</vn><fn>Chemical-sense_description</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="SMELL UP: cause to stink or reek" type="">
      <commentary>
        is: SMELL UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        After I had lit it, it smelled up my entire bedroom.
        Some reported their sponges caught fire, smoked and smelled up their houses.
        Your football teams played so bad that they smelled up the whole city!
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="smell_up" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>smell.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="8" name="idioms (see list)" type="">
      <commentary>
        includes: SMELL THE ROSES, SMELL A RAT, SMELL THE COFFEE
        NOTE: do not choose this sense for literal uses
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        SMELL THE ROSES (appreciate life)
        I was able to stop smoking because I was smelling the roses.

        SMELL A RAT (suspect something to be wrong)
        Ms. Freeman smelled a rat, and told the producer that she wanted to know what was going on.

        SMELL THE COFFEE (become aware)
        That's when the Hollywood community collectively woke up and smelled the coffee.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>smell.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>