<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="spot-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="particular place" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A physical location with respect to the region around it.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This is a nice spot for a picnic.
            Clear a spot on the table so I can put my bags down.
            One spot in the swimming pool is warmer than any other.
            John's bald spot caught my attention.
            My mother chose our next vacation spot.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="advertisement" type="">
        <commentary>
	    SPOT[+event]
	    A section of time on broadcast media (or, in some cases, a space in a magazine) bought for advertising purposes.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            A thirty-second spot can cost thousands of dollars during prime time.
            The company's ad campaign involves radio and television spots.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="stain" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            Usually a non-permanent marking, caused by substances such as dirt or ink. Some type of blemish.
            Can be used metaphorically. 
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You've left ink spots all over my term paper!
            I wiped away the spot on his cheek.
            Your association with John has left a spot on your reputation.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3 14
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="contrasting mark" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A small marking, usually involving color, that stands out from its surroundings.  Not a stain.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The plane shrank from my vision until it was just a spot on the horizon.
            My dog, like most other dalmatians, is white with black spots.
            John saw spots before his eyes after Mary slapped him.
            The appearance of liver spots on your skin is a sign of old age.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4 11
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="scheduled time" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A period of time, often involving entertainment, that must be scheduled in advance.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A better-known singer took your spot on the program.
            I've left a spot open for our power lunch on Wednesday.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="characteristic" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A single attribute of something.  A metaphoric kind of &quot;marking&quot;.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mr. Smith's acting was the only bright spot in this dull movie.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                6
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="entertainment place" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A slightly-informal way of referring to a place of entertainment.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John is a great guide to the city because he knows all the hip night spots.
            I took my date to the hottest spot in town.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                7
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="official position" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A position in an organization.  Usually a job, but can refer to any official situation.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I heard there's a spot open at Intelli-Soft.
            He occupies a spot on the Board of Directors.
            It's hard to get accepted because a hundred people are applying for three available spots.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                8
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="9" name="little bit" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            Signifies a small amount of something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Would you care for a spot of tea?
            I had a spot of rheumatism for a few days.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                9 10
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="10" name="bright light" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            Usually appears in the term &quot;spot light&quot; (usually called &quot;spotlight&quot;).  
            Used to signify the center of attention.  Can be used metaphorically.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            When the teacher called on him in class, John felt like he was on the spot.
            The spot light shined down on the dancer.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                12
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="11" name="thing of specified value" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A thing, such as a playing card or a piece of currency, that has a clearly-defined numeric value.  Usually slangy.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm a little low on cash-- can you lend me a ten-spot?
            He played a three-spot to win the hand.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                13
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="12" name="weightlifting help" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The aid that a spotter provides to a weightlifter.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Don't try to lift those weights without a spot, John.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                -
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>