<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="squeeze-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="exert pressure or influence on something" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SQUEEZE NP2[squeezed]
        Includes: SQUEEZE FOR
        NOTE: compare carefully to sense three; this sense does not refer
        to causing a change in location, but it can refer to a change in state due to direct pressure
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Squeeze the lemon and add a couple tablespoons along with some broth.
        He then squeezed my hand in a gesture of solidarity and affirmation.
        He reloaded the gun, took aim and then squeezed the trigger.
        Small businesses are being squeezed by heavy taxation.
        It's dangerous because the feds want to squeeze him for information.
        To have squeezed the universe into a ball.
        His eyes, seemingly squeezed upward into slits, narrowed still further.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,4,7,8,9</wn>   
         <wn lemma="squeeze_for" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>squeeze.01</pb>
         <vn>knead-26.5,touch-20-1,wipe_manner-10.4.1-1</vn><fn>Manipulation</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="extract by exerting pressure or influence" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SQUEEZE NP2[purpose] from/out of NP3[squeezed]
        Includes: SQUEEZE OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Squeeze some juice from the lemon.
        After cleaning the floor, he squeezed the dirty water from her cloth.
        The studio is using marketing tricks to squeeze profit from the movie.
        They managed to squeeze confession from suspect.
        We have an excellent travel agent who can squeeze a deal out of a stone.
        He managed to squeeze out a timid &quot;thank you&quot; (of himself).
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <wn lemma="squeeze_out" version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>squeeze.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="3" name="push or cram something/someone into something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SQUEEZE NP2 (PP[concrete, temporal, locative])
                   NP1[agent] SQUEEZE PP[locative]
        includes: SQUEEZE IN
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The boy squeezed between the boxes and closed his eyes.
        The car's quite full, but we could manage to squeeze another person.
        I must have put on a lot of weight. I can't squeeze into my favorite jeans.
        While we're in Australia, we're hoping to squeeze in a trip to the Barrier Reef.
        I'm very busy this week but I could squeeze you in at 2.30 on Tuesday.
        Conversation? Funny. You listen and squeeze a word or two in every five minutes.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>funnel-9.3-1-1,push-12-1-1</vn><fn>Cause_to_move_in_place</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="barely manage or succeed in doing or surviving something" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax includes: NP1 SQUEEZE PP 

        Includes: SQUEEZE BY, SQUEEZE THROUGH, SQUEEZE OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I barely managed to squeeze through the exam with a D.
        Can you squeeze by on 40 dollars a day?
        She squeezed through the crowd and found a seat at the front.
        They managed to squeeze under the fence and get into the festival without paying.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="squeeze_by" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="squeeze_out" version="3.0">2,4,5,6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="exclude" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] SQUEEZE NP2 (OUT) PP

        Includes: SQUEEZE OUT
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        The company squeezed them out by means of aggressive marketing.
        The show has been squeezed out of prime time slot.
        Some employees were squeezed out by the recent budget cuts.
        People within this income group are being squeezed out of their tenure and home of choice.
        Justice has been squeezed out of the criminal justice system, as wrongful convictions are at a high rate.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="squeeze_out" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>squeeze.04</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="hwangd,duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>