<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="start-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="moment of beginning" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    START[+event]
	    The most common sense.  The event of starting, in a fairly general way, either with or without an causal agent.
	    Think of this as the moment at which something begins.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            I knew from the start that we were a perfect couple.
            I got my start in Hollywood because my uncle was a director.
            The pitcher had over a hundred starts in his career.
            The exact start of the war was hard to pinpoint.
            We got a late start on the day.
            The play always has a ten o'clock start.
            He was responsible for the start of negotiations.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1 2 3 5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>start.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="first part" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            The first section of something.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The start of the race was full of hills.  
            I thought the start of the movie was a little boring.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                -  
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>start.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="starting place" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            Refers to a location, not a moment in time.  The place at which something begins.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We're only about a mile from the start.
            The start of the race was located in a cornfield.
            The start line had been painted on the ground.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                6
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb></pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="involuntary motion" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    START[+event]
	    A term that describes a bodily motion, usually indicating surprise or some strong emotion.  A little jump.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            John awoke from his nightmare with a start.
            She gave a start when I touched her on the shoulder.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>start.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="amount of head start" type="">
        <commentary>
	    START[+event]
	    The advantage that is gained by starting before others do.
	    A kind of possession that a person can have; it can have a definite size.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            John only won because he got a head start.
            With an hour's start on us, they'll be hard to catch.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                8
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>start.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="starting signal" type="">
        <commentary>
	    START[+event]
	    The thing that is used to begin an event, usually a race.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The start for the race was a loud electronic beep.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                7
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>