<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="sterilize-v">    
   <commentary>
     VN other_cos-45.4 not mapped; I'm not sure this verb really fits in that class
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="make free of bacteria, germs" type="">  
      <commentary>
      Note: In all senses, be wary of adjectival uses!
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I sterilized the spreader by dipping it in alcohol and burning off the alcohol.
        Of those using boiling water, 41 sterilized the utensil before putting the feed into it.
        We sterilized the counter tops and the carpets and the walls. We even sterilized the mailman. 
             (Note: 'sterilizing the mailman' jokingly refers to making free of germs, not sperms!)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>sterilize.01</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="make infertile" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Sweden sterilized the highest proportion of its own citizens.
        Failing to become pregnant, she learned from Dr. Hines in 1975 that she had been sterilized. 
        In the 1930s he sterilized the eggs and reared the maggots aseptically.
        I surface-sterilized the seeds according to the method in the Valvekens.
        I still want to keep the purported advantages of organic living soil so I still have not sterilized the potting medium.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="make inoffensive" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Today's Broad Street, polished and sterilized; the parade of all stars from the 1980's dispossessed.
        They sterilized the terminology with euphemisms.
        It was articulated in a language sterilized of personal and social potentiality.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>sterilize.01</pb>
         <vn>other_cos-45.4</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="Insulate (oneself) from the foreign          exchange market to counteract the effects of a changing monetary base." type="">
      <commentary>
      Note: FINANCIAL USAGE.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      The central bank sterilized about 75% of all capital inflows.  
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,corvey" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>