<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="storage-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="keeping" type="Activity">
        <commentary>
            Retaining, holding, or keeping something, usually as a commercial activity.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Intelli-Soft has invested in top-of-the-line meat-storage facilities. (facilities that are used for storage activities)
            I'm currently working in the self-storage market.
            Our company had to pay a pretty hefty storage fee.
            I need another hundred feet of storage space near the waterfront. (space that is used for storage activities)
            &quot;I think The American Moving and Storage Company is really a front for the mafia,&quot; John said.
            The storage of food is essential for the growth of a city-- that's why granaries are so important.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3 6
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="state of being stored" type="">
        <commentary>
            The quality of being stored.
            This is a time-bounded event, though it will mostly be used with phrases such as &quot;in storage&quot;.  
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The storage of my car began a few minutes ago.
            My car is currently in storage.
            I need to get my car out of storage.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="place for keeping" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            A depository for goods; a physical place where things are stored.  
            Note that phrases such as &quot;storage space&quot; and &quot;storage facilities&quot; do not use the word &quot;storage&quot; as a physical place.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We've got a hundred feet of storage near the waterfront.
            There's a car storage near the docks.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="computer memory" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A digital storage device, or the amount of space that can be used to store information.
            A digital kind of &quot;Entity: Place for keeping&quot;, as above.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He bought thirty gigabytes of new storage.
            Your computer starts slowing down when you run out of storage.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                5
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="keeping digitally" type="Activity">
        <commentary>
            The process or act of storing information in a digital form.  A digital kind of &quot;Activity: Keeping&quot;, as above.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I spent a hundred dollars trying to increase my storage capacity. (capacity that is used for storage activities) 
            All our memory is being wasted on the storage of John's high-resolution pictures.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                4
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>