<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="study-n">
    <commentary>
        Revisions of examples, definitions, commentary by ahouston.
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a specific inquiry or investigation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    STUDY[+event][+activity][+inquiry][+specific]
	    A specific inquiry, often with a time duration local to the present.
	    Note: usually (always?) in the singular, plural sounds marked.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Detective John's study of the crime scene revealed no important clues.
            After a quick study of her test results, the doctor determined that Sally was anemic.
            Their accident report will require a careful study of the aircraft's  maintenance history.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>study.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the acquisition of knowledge" type="">
        <commentary>
	    STUDY[+event][+activity][+acquisition][+knowledge]
	    The act of acquiring knowledge through directed mental effort, reading, analyzing, writing
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mastering a second language requires a lot of study.
            John needs to improve his study habits to get through all the material in that biochemistry course.
            I hope your studies at school are going well.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>study.02,study.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="finding or set of results, often published and scholarly" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+finding][+scholarly][+report/+experiment/+article]
            A finding, often written, that describes the results of some inquiry, e.g. scientific or medical.
            Note: occurs unmarked in both singular and plural
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My data is consistent with the 1998 study by Hill that documented drug abuse in minors.
            That new study on the health benefits of seaweed is not yet published.
            His studies of cold fusion could not be replicated by other scientists.
            Studies show that eating chocolate and drinking wine are good for you.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>study.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="contemplation, deliberation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+activity][+contemplation][+reflection]
            Cogitation, deep thought, or meditation.  
            Note: only occurs in the singular
            Note: differs from Sense 1, no search to an unknown, but an assessment of what is right before one.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's face indicated her deep study of the Rembrandt painting in front of her.
            Give this proposal some study tonight and get back to me tomorrow.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a room for literary or scholarly pursuits" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+building][+room][+scholarly]
            A room typically used for reading, writing, and studying.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Professor Plum was murdered in the study-- but who murdered him, and with what weapon?
            I knocked lightly on the door of the study.
            The walls of his study are lined with bookshelves. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the general pursuit of a discipline or body of knowledge" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+inquiry][+general][+domain][+knowledge]
            Note: unmarked is the singular, rare (never?) occurs in the plural
            Note: Does -NOT- imply a specific time duration of the inquiry, this is different from Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Anthropology is the study of human beings.
            Teachers should be highly knowledgeable in their field of study.
            The study of how cancer cells metastasize has been evolving radically in recent years. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb>study.02,study.03</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="artistic practice in the form of a sketch, drawing or musical composition" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+composition][+artistic][+practice]
            Note: occurs unmarked (naturally) in the plural and singular
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I love these early pencil studies of Van Gogh.
            The sculptor made several studies in clay before casting the form in bronze.
            He wrote a beautiful little Baroque counterpoint study.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">7,10</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a person who memorizes or learns quickly" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            STUDY[+person][+learner][+rapid]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Management has been observing what a quick study Bill is on the new project.
            Bob really puts time in on his drama roles, because he is not a quick study.
            You need to be a quick study with that orchestra because they play new repertoire on short notice.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">9</wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>