<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="stuff-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="material or tangible substance" type="">
        <commentary>
            STUFF[+entity][+substance][+tangible]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The theory conjectures that tiny strings are the most basic stuff of the universe, out of which everything else is made.
            The sticky stuff on the countertop was hard to clean up.
            Wheat is the stuff they use to make bread out of.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="collection of miscellaneous artifacts or possessions" type="">
        <commentary>
            STUFF[+collection][+artifact][+possessions][+miscellaneous]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This antique shop has some really interesting old stuff.
            The old tenant left a lot of his stuff in the apartment when he left.
            What do you want to do with all the stuff on the porch?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="information content via discourse" type="">
        <commentary>
            STUFF[+information][+content][+discourse]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Don't listen to that stuff - it's total nonsense!
            A lot of boring stuff goes on in the middle of the movie, but the climax is exciting.
            His lecture was all stuff we'd heard before.
            Don't give me that stuff!  (say those things)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a fundamental constituent or characteristic of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            STUFF[+quality][+characteristic][+fundamental][+of_something]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His rags-to-riches Hollywood success is the stuff of dreams.
            The average worker was made of more resilient stuff than politicians imagined.
            Suspense is the very stuff of narrative.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="personal knowledge and skill" type="">
        <commentary>
            STUFF[+quality][+skill][+knowledgeable][+personal]
            Note: uses with self-reference to the subject.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            When it comes to molecular biology, John really knows his stuff.
            The young pitcher assumed the mound and showed his stuff to a sequence of batters.
            The actress really strutted her stuff in the final act of the play.
            He has the stuff to be an Olympic athlete.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1d</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>