<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="submit-v">    
   <commentary>
     Note: Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="yield control to another being or force" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[animate] SUBMIT to NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        In the end, many Congresspeople who knew that the resolution was bad policy submitted to the pressure to vote for it.
        Soldiers are taught to submit to authority immediately.
        Although an employee is equal to the boss as a man, the employee must submit to him because he holds a higher rank.
        Were he able to simply reverse his will and submit to fate, he would find peace more swiftly.
        There, Alexander Nevsky, the bane of Germans, submitted to the inevitable and accepted Mongol lordship over all of Russia.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">3,6,10</wn>   
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>acquiesce-95,contribute-13.2-1-1</vn><fn>Compliance</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="hand over or put in" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1 [agent] SUBMIT NP2[concrete] to NP3[human]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She submitted a proposal to the agency.
        We submitted an application for a grant to the NSF.
        Submit your website URL to 40 major search engines for FREE!
        You can submit a letter to the Voice of San Diego editors on this page.
        On Feb. 9, 1989, Jeannette Dinning, Lighthill's daughter, submitted the estate for probate.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,4,8,9</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>submit.01</pb>
         <vn>contribute-13.2-1-1</vn><fn>Submitting_documents</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="put forward an idea or question for approval or judgement" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        I submit to you that the accused is guilty.
        I jokingly submit to him that this is environment where all editorial decisions should be made.
        I had submitted to her that there was a 50/50 chance of failure.
        Finally they stopped a day laborer and submitted the question to him.
        I submitted the problem to tech support, and everything was quickly resolved and working.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,5</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense group="1" n="4" name="undergo" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Workers are often not allowed to form unions and are easily submitted to unfair treatment.
        He had not submitted to punishment without some resistance.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">7</wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
