<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="substance-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="physical matter, material which things are made from" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUBSTANCE[+entity][+physical][+matter]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Tiny strings may be the underlying substance of all matter in the universe.
            The steel tubes were coated with a waxy substance.
            An envelope of a white substance was found on the Senator's desk.
            It's an outreach clinic for substance abusers.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the core, essence, gist, content of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUBSTANCE[+entity][+symbolic][+information][+content]
            [+relation][+role][+essence][+message]
            Note: refers to the content of something, not its truth value (see Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The substance of the treaty centers on the mutual elimination of trade tariffs.
            The substance of the theory is that language is an innate faculty. (what the theory is about)
            What was the substance of the CEO's message to the Board of Directors?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the state of affluence, wealth" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUBSTANCE[+state][+affluence]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The owners of the America's Cup racing yachts are all men of considerable substance.
            Her series of best-selling novels has made her a woman of substance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="validity, merit" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUBSTANCE[+quality][+validity]
            Note: refers to the likelihood of something being true
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There is no substance to any of these rumors about Bob.
            Although not yet experimentally confirmed, there is much substance to the theory of the Higgs particle.
            Their accusations of insider trading were without substance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2b,2c</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="import, significance, character" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUBSTANCE[+quality][+importance]
            Note: refers to the value of worth, significance assigned to something (not truth value, see Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He felt he had not accomplished anything of substance in his life.
            The meat was tasty but the sauce somehow had no substance. 
            She gave them the impression that she lacked substance as an actress.
            Critics concluded that it was a novel of no substance.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>