<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="sum-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an amount of money, a price paid or received" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUM[+quantity][+amount][+money]
            Note: always refers to money
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The interior decorator charged them an enormous sum for redoing just the dining room.
            There were sums of money involved in that deal.
            They are buying the small firm for an undisclosed sum.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the resulting quantity of performing the mathematical operation of addition" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUM[+quantity][+total][+computation][+addition][+mathematical]
            Note: refers to the resulting value, not the act of computing (Sense 4)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            What is the sum of six plus four?
            The test included some problems requiring you to find vector sums.
            The sum of these two prime numbers is not itself a prime.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a total aggregation of things" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUM[+entity][+group][+aggregation]
            Note: refers to a bunch of things, parts, stuff, not a number value (Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            What if the sum of human knowledge could be contained on a single microchip?
            The sum of the team's experience is a formidable asset for the company. 
            In this case the whole is bigger than the sum of its parts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the core or essence of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUM[+quality][+essence]
            Note: includes the idiom, in_sum, which means 'in summary', a kind of core or essence.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The sum of his argument was that pollution is bad and someone should pay for it.
            The sum of the matter is that we need to hire a lawyer.
            In sum, this experiment does little to further our understanding of metabolic pathways.
            And that, in sum, is her view of the world.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the task of performing mathematical addition" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUM[+activity][+task][+mathematical][+addition]
            Note: refers to an actor performing the act of addition, not the resulting number value.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children were doing sums in class today.
            Let Sally figure the bill, she's good at sums.
            Little Johnny is better at sums than he as at reading.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>