<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="supply-n">
    <commentary>
        31aug06 updated to WN 2.1, added features, examples, modified defs. ahouston
        31aug06 split sense 1 into sense 1, sense 3. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an available quantity of a resource" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUPPLY[+quantity][+amount][+available][+resource]
            an amount of something available for use
            Note: the modifier specifies the resource, X supply, supply of X
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our supply of toothpaste is running low.
            Get a free printer with your purchase - while supplies last! (quantity of available printers)
            Some chemical has contaminated their water supply.
            John probably has a lifetime supply of paper clips in his desk drawer.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>supply.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="act of providing a desired resource" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SUPPLY[+event][+activity][+providing][+resource][+desired]
	    the activity of supplying or offering goods and services
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            This firm is engaged in the supply of raw materials to the steel industry.
            Economists study the supply of, and demand for, goods and services in a society.
            It's an argument from supply side economics.
            The U.N. has criticized that nation for its supply of arms to terrorist organizations.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>supply.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="goods, provisions" type="">
        <commentary>
            SUPPLY[+entity][+resource][+desired]
            Note: often occurs in the plural.
            Note: refers to stuff, not a quantity of something (see Sense 1)
            Note: often does not have an accompanying modifier, as Sense 1 usually does
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Our mini-fridge in the hotel room was stocked with supplies.
            Each hiker will have to carry their own supplies on their back.
            Do you need any supplies from the lumber store?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>