<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="survey-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="study" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SURVEY[+event]
	    A scientific study that usually involves asking the opinions of many people.
	    Can also refer to the results of such a study.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            A survey of the consumers revealed that our new product tastes terrible.
            Hello, I'm conducting a telephone survey about your favorite toothpaste brands.
            Bush's popularity plummets, survey says.
            Reading the Zagat Survey is a trusted method of finding new Italian places in Philadelphia.
            The British government has launched a new survey of its voters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                1
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>survey.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="piece of paper" type="Entity">
        <commentary>
            The physical document that a scientific study uses to collect opinions.  The paper that asks the questions.
            Only use this sense when the physical document is clearly being referred to.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I handed him a short survey, and he filled it out with a red pen.
            Have we collected all the surveys from the participants?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                -
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="summary" type="Abstraction">
        <commentary>
            A short, descriptive summary of events or information; a metaphoric way of looking something over.  
            Often used to refer to introductory academic classes.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I'm in a survey course that covers all the basics.
            He wrote a short survey of his idea.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                2
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="seeing" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    SURVEY[+event]
	    The act of looking at something.  Often used scientifically to refer to the exploration and mapping of new areas.
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            My initial survey of the patient gave me an idea of his injuries.
            His survey of the battlefield was limited.
            NASA is going to use an airplane for its next Mars survey.
            The Geologic Survey Team met disaster when exploring the volcano.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">
                3
            </wn>
            <omega/><pb>survey.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>