<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="swallow-v">
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="pass through the esophagus" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: 
        1. refers to the physical act of gulping, or passing substance into the body
        2. fictive (or unrealistic) act of taking in through mouth and esophagus, counts.
        3. if the swallowing entails more than just pushing something (air or otherwise)
        through the throat, then consider other senses first.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
	It is easier to swallow pills if you take them with some water.
     	Jonah was swallowed by a whale.
	The fish was too big for the bird to swallow whole.
	Bob swallowed hard, took a deep breath and jumped off the high dive.
	The patient is having trouble swallowing.
        There was an old lady who swallowed a cow. I don't know why swallowed the cow.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>swallow.01</pb>
         <vn>gobble-39.3-2,hiccup-40.1.1</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="destroy, engulf, subsume, take in entirely" type="">
      <commentary>
        Note: This sense is MORE than a simple metaphorical extension of sense 1.
        By the act of swallowing, what was the essense of the entity swallowed is no more.
        The focus is not only on the swallower but also on the extinction of the entity
        swallowed. 
	Includes: SWALLOW UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
     	The Germans quickly swallowed Poland during the blitzkrieg. 
	A rogue wave swallowed up the small fishing boat.
	The little mom and pop stores are being swallowed up by the big chains.
        The roof repairs have pretty much swallowed up our savings.
        Monthly debts were swallowing up his paychecks.
        Too much of the town's conservation land is being swallowed up by developers.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,3</wn>
         <wn lemma="swallow_up" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>swallow.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="rescind, retract, revoke a statement or remark" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: implies the statement has previously been made
      </commentary>
      <examples>
     	John had to swallow his words when his accusations of Bob being a thief proved untrue.
	She refused to swallow her words to her mother that had been made in anger.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="suppress a feeling, attitude, inclination" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
     	Sally swallowed her anger at the lewd remark and continued her speech.
	They may have to swallow their pride and ask Bob's parents for a loan.
	He swallowed his urge to pop John in the nose.
        We need to swallow hard, force a smile, and congratulate them and wish them well.
        Our investors might need to swallow hard before listening to the housing expert.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <omega/><pb>swallow.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="speak indistinctly, mutter" type="">
      <commentary>
	Note: always refers to an act of speaking, uttering
      </commentary>
      <examples>
     	The child tends to swallow his words when talking in front of strangers.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
         <omega/><pb>swallow.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="accept or believe a distasteful state of affairs or an unlikely story or account" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        IPU won't swallow the bitter pill of pharmacy deregulation.
   	He can't seem to swallow the idea that his kid has a drinking problem.
        The taxpayers won't swallow another override this year.
        It's hard to swallow his story about the accident, given the evidence in front of us.
	The public seems to be swallowing the account given by the senator.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">7,8</wn>
         <omega/><pb>swallow.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NP</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense> 
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,brownsw,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>