<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="swell-v">
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="(cause to) increase in size, number, intensity" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax includes: NP1 SWELL (up)
                   NP1 SWELL NP2
        NOTE: the &quot;swelling&quot; NPs may vary, being the actual objects
        that are swelling, or representations of the object (as in &quot;music&quot;
        represented by &quot;orchestra&quot;, or &quot;the number of laborers/people&quot; 
        represented by &quot;labor/population&quot;)
        Includes: SWELL UP
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Wind swelled the sails.
        This repatriated labor has swelled the skilled workforce.
        Free trade has swelled the ranks of independent businessmen.
        The crowd swells at the Rainbow Family gathering.
        The US foreign-born population swelled in the 1990s.
        Arcturus is old and has swelled into a red giant type star.
        The orchestra swells into a cheerful, sweeping sound.
        Her throat swelled shut as a result of the peanut allergy.
        She said her eyes swelled so fast her contacts popped out.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3,6</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>swell.01</pb>
         <vn>calibratable_cos-45.6-1,entity_specific_cos-45.5</vn><fn>Cause_change_of_position_on_a_scale,Cause_expansion,Change_position_on_a_scale,Expansion</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="fill with emotion" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        His heart swelled, and the tears gathered in his eyes, as they rested on the baby.
        He swelled with holy anger at the disloyalty of those around him.
        A mighty rage shook him, he swelled and choked with resentment.
        She swelled at the memory; she loved her son more purely than the others she loved.
        Downtown Mexico City swelled Saturday with the accumulated frustration and rage of the poor.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>swell.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="come up, as of liquid or gas" type="">
      <commentary>
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Thick columns of smoke swelled into the sky as heavy winds fanned the fire.
        She went a bit deep and the water swelled into her boot.
        The heady brew of sanitary chemicals and bean curries swelled up into the air.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>swell.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>