<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="talk-v">    
   <commentary>
        Includes: VPC and idioms for talk.
        Note: VPC talk_back does not map to a WordNet sense.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="to converse, speak, or use language" type="">  
      <commentary>
	Includes: talk_about, talk_back, talk_of, talk_over, talk_shop,
	talk_turkey 
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
        They are talking to several investment firms.
        We need to talk.
        The children were told not to talk to each other during the test.
        We cannot talk about that classified information to anyone without a security clearance.
        I've never heard him talk about the details of his divorce.
	They talked about Dante's Inferno in class today.
        Before long, your computer will be able to talk back to you.
        If you're in a fantasy world as a preschooler, everything would talk back to you.
	They talked of the old days back in Ireland.
	Let's sit down and talk over how we are going to approach this issue.
	John and Bill never stop talking shop!
	Bob sat down with his team to talk turkey about missing the deadline.
        Mary's baby hasn't started talking yet.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3</wn>   
         <wn lemma="talk_about" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <wn lemma="talk_of" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="talk_over" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="talk_shop" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="talk_turkey" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>talk.01</pb>
         <vn>talk-37.5</vn>
         <fn>Chatting</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="to spill the beans" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK (PP) (PP[recipient])
        includes TALK ABOUT (when not refering to a specific conversation, discourse, or lecture)
        Note: it implies a subject matter or information that was disclosed to someone.
        Note: differs from sense 4 in that it can be brief, informal, secretive
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Be careful what you say around here because the secretary does talk. 
        The mob put a hit out on the bookie for talking to the police.
        There are speculations that Johnny may sign a 3-year contract with the Mets, but so far he's not talking.
       </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
         <omega/><pb>talk.01</pb>
         <vn>talk-37.5</vn>
         <fn>Chatting</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="to lecture formally to an audience" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK[duration] (PP) (PP[recipient])
        Note: differs from sense 2 because implies a formal public discourse of some length.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        John will talk about recent theories of dark energy at the Physics Symposium.
        Bob gets nervous when talking in front of a large audience.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>talk.01</pb>
         <vn>lecture-37.11-1</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="to persuade, convince or influence someone" type="">  
      <commentary>
        Includes: talk_into, talk_out_of
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK NP2[patient] INTO/OUT_OF NP[goal]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        John talked me into joining his crew for the Bermuda race.
        We couldn't talk them out of painting their house bright orange.
        They are trying to talk him out of resigning his post.
        I was excited for the bike ride, but the stormy weather talked me out of it.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version=""/>
         <wn lemma="talk_into" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="talk_out_of" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>talk.02</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>Talking_into</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="5" name="to belittle or condescend towards" type="">  
      <commentary>
       	Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK_DOWN PP[recipient]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Don't talk down to the cleaning lady.
	The students dislike the way the professor talks down to them.
	She didn't mean to talk down to them.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="talk_down" version="3.0">1,2</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="6" name="to answer impertinently" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK_BACK PP[recipient]
        NOTE: this sense does not refer to simple responses (see sense 3);
        if an example is ambiguous, and you are not confident that the specific
        inferences of rebellion and rudeness are there, tag it with sense 3.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        It's dishonorable to talk back to a cop.
        Don't talk back to your mother!
        Donny Darko is a smartass high school student with a tendency to talk back to his teachers.
        In a totalitarian system, you aren't allowed to talk back to the government.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="7" name="direct or control to the ground" type="">  
      <commentary>
       	Syntax is: NP1[agent] TALK_DOWN NP2[patient]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Air traffic control had to talk the plane down through the fog during an emergency landing.
	The control tower talked down the plane whose pilot had fallen ill.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="talk_down" version="3.0">3</wn>
         <omega/><pb>talk.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
  <sense group="1" n="8" name="negotiate the terms of an agreement" type="">  
      <commentary>
       	Syntax is: NP1[actor] TALK_TERMS (PP)[goal]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Are they talking terms about this house?
	The two sides are expected to talk terms tomorrow about a settlement.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn lemma="talk_terms" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
       <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,brownsw" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>