<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="talk-n">
    <commentary>
        Added senses, including one discussed by the authors of this file, modified examples and definitions. Added commentary. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="conversation, spontaneous verbal dialogue" type="">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+discourse][-structure][+conversation][+impromptu]
            Note: does not entail a specific goal or topic of discussion. (different from Sense 2 and 5)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The talk and laughter at the neighbor's party next door went on into the wee hours.
            We had a quiet talk by the fire over a glass of wine.
            The host of that famous talk show is stepping down next season.
            This romance novel has too much pillow talk.
            The two job candidates engaged in small talk while they waited for their interviews.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="analytical discussion, analyses" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+discourse][+structured][+analysis][+/-written]
            Note: implies a specific target of discussion, also allows a written context, as well as spoken.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            His poetry contains much talk about love and anger.  (poetry can be read or spoken)
            She had a serious talk with her son about drinking and driving.
            I overheard some shop talk about computer operating systems waiting in line at the movies.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="negotiations or official, structured dialogue" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+discourse][+structure][+negotiation][+official]
            Note: almost always occurs in the plural
            Note: implies an official context, (different from Sense 2)
            Note: implies a goal or purpose for the discussion and an outcome.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their president has offered to initiate talks with the rebels.
            Labor and management are in talks right now over the fate of the company's pension plan.
            The arms talk has been cancelled for a third time.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1f</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a lecture, a verbal presentation" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            TALK [+event][+presentation][+lecture]
            the act of giving a talk to an audience
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I attended an interesting talk on local history.
            We skipped the afternoon talks at the conference and went diving.
            The coach gave the team a pep talk before the big game. (informal extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="gossip, speculation, rumor" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+discourse][-structured][+speculation][+rumor/+gossip]
            Note: entails a specific target of discussion. (different from Sense 1)
            Note: implies unstructured, speculative discussion (different from  Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The talk on the street is that their firm is going to be bought out.
            There has been talk about you lately.
            There has been no talk of resuming diplomatic relations with that nation.
            The young actress is the talk of the town.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="pointless chatter, prattle" type="">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+discourse][-structured][+prattle][+monologue]
            Note: implies a pejorative quality to the conversation (different from Sense 1)
            Note: often suggests a monologue, or pronouncements, of an individual.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He's all talk and no action.
            His pronouncements about using alternative energy sources have thus far been just empty talk. 
            It's just a lot of talk, nothing will come of it.
            Don't listen to his double talk!
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a way of speaking or making an utterance" type="">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+action][+utterance][+sass/+gibberish]
            TALK[+action][+utterance][+pitch][+sales]
            TALK[+quality][+speaking][+sassy/+infantile/+hustling]
            Note: focus is on a manner of speaking more than the content (differs from Sense 6 in this respect)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            John always walks away when the sales talk begins.
            That child has learned a lot of back talk and uses it on her parents.
            Mary speaks baby talk to her pets.  (utterances trying to mimic child language acquisition, not the real deal)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="any signal, such as gesture or vocalization, that serves as communication" type="">
        <commentary>
            TALK[+signal][+vocalization/+gesture]
            [+role][+communication]
            Note: describes any signal that functions as a means to communicate.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary's little girl enjoyed a book about a child who could understand bird talk.
            The parents have recorded many of their child's first instances of baby talk.
            She used her hands to make happy talk.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW">8</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>talk.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>