<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="technique-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the specific manner in which an act is executed" type="">
        <commentary>
            TECHNIQUE[+event][+manner][+specific][+of_execution]
            Note: refers to a specific instance of how an endeavor is performed, executed
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The chef swirled icing on the cake with great technique.
            Critics say there is little technique in the novel's flat-footed prose. (although not an event in time, the linear structure of the novel is a kind of performance)
            The skater's technique during the spin was sloppy and she slipped on the ice.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="training, skillfulness that is learned" type="">
        <commentary>
            TECHNIQUE[+quality][+ability][+ongoing][+learned]
            Note: refers to a general or ongoing learned skill, not a specific instance of using it. (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Her voice is beautiful but her operatic technique still need some work.
            The technique of the Russian ballerinas is famous throughout the dance world.
            The knuckle ball technique of that baseball pitcher is flawless.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a body of knowledge describing methods, practices" type="">
        <commentary>
            TECHNIQUE[+entity][+abstract][+information][+methodology][+specific]
            Note: refers to a body of knowledge in itself, not a specific event of using it. Often occur in the plural.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Certain techniques for making stained glass have been lost through the ages.
            This medical journal describes new surgical techniques being developed.
            Tape recording is an analog technique that has been largely replaced by digital technologies.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>