<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="telephone-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an electronic device that sends and receives voice communication" type="">
        <commentary>
            TELEPHONE[+artifact][+device][+electronic][+handset][+communication][+voice]
            Note: refers to all aspects of the physical handset consumer device
            Note: occurs in the plural naturally
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary has a cordless telephone in her bedroom.
            The telephones don't seem to be working.
            He picked up the telephone receiver and listened in on their conversation.
            The remote eco-resort has no television, no computers and no telephones.
            Rotary phones use a telephone dial.
            They put a telephone extension into the bathroom.
            The police found the man strangled with a telephone cord.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a communication system that transmits audio signals converted to electrical or radio signals over large distances" type="">
        <commentary>
            TELEPHONE[+technology][+communication][+remote][+signal][+transmission][+voice]
            Note: refers to all aspects of telephone as a communication technology or service
            Note: doesn't occur in the plural, because it refers to a general system or technology
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Before telephone there were no telemarketing calls.
            The reporter had a telephone interview with the author. (via this technology instead of TV, etc.)
            I've never met him, I've only had telephone conversations with him.
            We exchanged telephone numbers.		(codes associated with the service, not specific handsets)
            John believes there is an error on his telephone bill.
            Someone cut the telephone wire outside the house.
            Are they listed in the telephone book?
            Those remote villages don't even have telephone service.
            The car swerved and hit a telephone pole. (a component of the whole communication system)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a parlor game which distorts a whispered message passed around a group of people" type="">
        <commentary>
            TELEPHONE[+event][+social][+game][+message][+distorted][+passing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children played telephone at the birthday party.
            When we played telephone 'you said that you were sorry' became 'used Edna wore a sari'
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>