<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="threat-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a cause or agent of harm, danger" type="">
        <commentary>
            THREAT[+cause][+effective][+harm]
            [+relation][+role][+agent][+harm]
            Note: implies X BE threat, X is the perceived cause of harm
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They view outsourcing as a threat to their jobs.
            Hurricanes are a threat to many coastal communities.
            Mary was a threat to Bob's masculinity when she beat him at chess.
            The Tigers were a real threat this year in the playoffs. (extended usage)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a state of exposure to harm" type="">
        <commentary>
            THREAT[+state][+exposure][+harm]
            Note: refers to X being in a state of exposure to harm, including probability of it
            Note: often occurs in prepositional phrases 'under/with' the/a threat
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            She lived with the threat of a recurrence of her cancer.
            Thousands of jobs came under threat when the company went bankrupt.
            The country has lived for decades under the threat of civil war.
            Is there any threat that the virus could become airborne?
            There is some threat of rain this afternoon. (the afternoon is in a state of risk)
            The threat of another terrorist attack did not stop people from taking the subway.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a declaration of intention to harm" type="">
        <commentary>
            THREAT[+action][+declaration][+intention][+inflict][+harm]
            Note: implies an intentional declaration of an actor/agent to inflict harm
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Members of his family have received death threats.
            The plaintiff insisted his remark to the woman did not constitute a threat.
            Their threats of a walk-out did not materialize. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>