<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="tower-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a tall, narrow enclosed structure, attached or  freestanding" type="">
        <commentary>
            TOWER[+structure][+enclosed][+tall][+narrow][+attached/+freestanding]	
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The courthouse has a large clock tower.
            The air boss stood in the conning tower of the aircraft carrier.
            John thinks Bob has lived in an ivory tower too long to understand how politics really works. (figurative extension)
            That twenty-story tower is apartments for graduate students.
            The king locked his prisoners in a tower.
            That tall structure is the main cooling tower of the nuclear power plant.
            We could see several flashing red lights from the radio towers on top of the hill.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="any form with a tall narrow shape" type="">
        <commentary>
            TOWER[+form][+shape][+tall][+narrow]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The waitress brought us a giant platter of bacon and eggs with a tower of pancakes in the middle of it.
            The child knocked over his tower of blocks in a fit of rage.
            Sally stores all her CDs and DVDs in plastic towers.
            Can we clear this tower of boxes and trash off the front porch?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a powerful or strong person" type="">
        <commentary>
            TOWER[+person][+powerful]
            [+role][+supporter][+strong]
            Note: power is often of character or behavior, but can be physical
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They view their leader as a tower of strength.
            He was a tower of courage in the face of the enemy.
            He grandfather was still a tower of a man at eighty--five.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an upright-style personal computer" type="">
        <commentary>
            TOWER[+computer][+personal][+upright]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary got rid of her old tower pc and replaced it with a sleek laptop.
            This computer desk is designed to hold a tower and a printer.
            John prefers a pizza-box style computer to a bulky tower.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a small hauling boat, tugboat" type="">
        <commentary>
            TOWER[+vessel][+boat][+small][+strong][+hauler][+tug]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            A small yellow tower was hauling a commercial barge into the harbor.
            Her grandfather was a pilot of a tower in New York Harbor.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>