<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory SYSTEM "inventory.dtd">
<inventory lemma="trade-v">    
   <commentary>
	Added VPC trade_in and trade_off
   </commentary>
   <sense n="1" type="" name="buy and sell, engage in commerce (possibly
   without currency)." group="1">  
      <commentary>
	NP[+agent] TRADE[-transitive] (PP[+commodity]) (PP[+trade_partner])
	NP[+agent] TRADE[+transitive] NP[+commodity]
  	Note: implies a commercial, usually financial, transaction.  Can be metaphorical.
      </commentary>
      <examples> 
	Oil stocks were trading at over $62 dollars a barrel.
	The senator argued that we should be trading with Cuba.
	Bill traded both stocks and bonds on Wall Street for years.
	Several recent issues were actively trading on Nasdaq today.
        That firm trades mostly in precious metals.
        This devilish child helps none, but he trades in usury, covets, robs, and steals as he may.
        He trades in stunted lives and undernourished spirits; he gives them voices.
        The powers that be trade heavily on the fear of the masses.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,3,5</wn>   
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>trade.01</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense n="2" type="" name="perform a swap or exchange" group="1">  
      <commentary>
	NP[+agent] TRADE/TRADE_IN NP[+discarded] (PP[+acquired])
	includes VPC trade_in
	Note: does not imply a financial transaction. Car trade-ins involve money, but the trading aspect (usually a deduction in cost) is a swap or exchange of comparable products.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        He trades in on emotionally charged subject matter (abstract and ambiguous use; acquired item omitted, but swap inferred)
	Mary said she'd love to trade places with the CEO of Google.
	The children like to trade Pokemon cards.
        Needing a win to stay in contention for the $25000 purse, he trades in four vowels.
	Jack is trading in his old Volvo for a newer model. (exchange is part of the total transaction)
	I traded two cards for two new ones in the last hand.
	They have traded integrity for ambition. (figurative)
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">2,4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>trade.01</pb>
         <vn>exchange-13.6-1</vn>
         <fn>Exchange</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <sense n="3" type="" name="TRADE_OFF: take turns" group="1">
      <commentary>
        NP[agent] and NP[agent] TRADE_OFF (PP) NP[activity/responsibility]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        My husband and I trade off dish duty.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

    <sense n="4" type="" name="TRADE_(UP)ON: rely upon or use, possibly in a
         negative way." group="1">
      <commentary>
      Is: TRADE (UP)ON
      </commentary>
      <examples>
      The court's decision traded heavily on a single Kantian principle.
      There are ghouls who trade on the hopes of the desperately ill.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0"></wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"></wn>
         <omega></omega><pb>NM</pb>
         <vn>NM</vn>
         <fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,duffielc,brownsw,dehart" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>
