<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="trailer-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a hauled vehicle that transports or conveys things" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRAILER[+vehicle][-motorized][+transport][+truck/+boat]
            Note: implies hauling goods, not living quarters (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Traffic is stopped on 93 due to an overturned tractor trailer.
            You can't move a sailboat with that sized keel on a boat trailer.
            The landscaping company hauls its gardening tools in a trailer.
            You could carry a fairly big power boat on that trailer hitch. (context is Sense 1)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a mobile home,  transportable living quarters" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRAILER[+vehicle][-motorized][+habitation]
            Note: implies living quarters, not hauling goods, (see Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The family moved around from trailer camp to trailer camp.
            Mary and John lived in a house trailer while their home was being renovated. 
            Two people were killed when a tornado struck their trailer park.
            They haul their small mobile home around with a trailer hitch. (context is Sense 2)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="cinematic preview, short pieces from a film" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRAILER[+media][+preview][+film]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The trailers for that new thriller are pretty intense.
            Sally thinks they probably showed the best bits of that film in the trailer.
            We had to sit through six trailers before the feature film started.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="person who is a laggard, a poke" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRAILER[+role][+laggard]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob was the trailer on his tour, always late and the last one back on the bus.
            That colt was considered a trailer until his win by three lengths today.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a plant with extended, hanging tendrils" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRAILER[+organism][+plant][+tendril][+extended]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This purple wisteria is a lovely trailer over a trellis.
            She wanted trailers, such as weeping willows, planted along the bank.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>