<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="transfer-n">
    <commentary>
        12jan07  updated to wn 2.1, added features. ahouston
        23jan07 - combined senses 1,3. ahouston
        23jan07 - added senses 7,8, added examples. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the relocation or conveyance of someone/something" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    TRANSFER[+event][+action][+movement][+relocation][+entity][+concrete/+abstract]
	    the act of transporting something from one location to another
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            A patient had died after transfer from the County Hospital to Saint Mary's.
            This trade policy will help expedite the transfer of wealth to poorer nations.  (ongoing process)
            John performs a nightly transfer of all his files to a backup tape.
            The transfer of the music from vinyl record to magnetic tape eliminated much of the background noise.
            Mary asked her boss for a transfer to the west coast. (the act of relocating her there)
            That football player's transfer to the Rangers cost a million dollars. (trading the player implies relocating him)
            The banker transferred some of his investment earnings to a secret offshore account.  (relocated the asset)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>transfer.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="person" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRANSFER[+entity][+person][+vocational][+relocation][+employment/+studies]
            someone who transfers or is transferred from one position to another
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The best student was a transfer from LSU.
            The number of transfers from the community colleges to state universities is up this year.
            Bob is a transfer in sales from our Dallas office.
            These soldiers are transfers from the 82 Airborne. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary>
	    TRANSFER[+event]
	    
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="ticket" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRANSFER[+entity][+artifact][+document][+ticket][+transportation][+change]
            a ticket that allows a passenger to change conveyance
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I've lost my transfer somewhere in my briefcase.
            You'll need a transfer to change to the 79 bus.
            That stack of pink tickets are commuter train transfers.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="carry-over skill, a generalization of knowledge" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    TRANSFER[+event][+process][+cognitive][+generalization]
	    application of a skill learned in one situation to a different but similar situation
	    </commentary>
        <examples>
            The transfer of her receptionist skills to waitressing went smoothly.
            Previous experience with a microphone led to negative transfer for the young singer studying operatic techniques. (note: implies an impedance to acquiring the new skills)
            The therapist helped John to explore the transfer of his self-doubts to his ways of interacting with other people.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="conferral of property, financial or legal transaction" type="Event">
        <commentary>
            TRANSFER[+event][+transaction][+legal][+conferral][+authority/+ownership]
            changing ownership
            Note: refers to a legal event of bestowing ownership or authority, not a -relocation- of an asset (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It took several weeks for the transfer of the title of the house to be completed.
            The transfer of power usually occurs peacefully in democracies. (a legal right conferred on a new person)
            The lawyer set up the transfer of power of attorney from Bob to Bob's brother.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="graphic image that can be rubbed off on fabric" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRANSFER[+entity][+artifact][+image][+graphics][+applicable]
            Note: refers to physical appliques or paper designs.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The tourist shops sell T-shirts with iron-on transfers.
            The children applied decorative paper transfers to the colored Easter eggs.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">1e</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="location where someone or something changes mode, e.g., transportation" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRANSFER[+location][+point][+exchange][+transportation[+passenger]/+conversion/[+power]]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            During rush hour, the central transfer station processes thousands of rail commuters.
            The rebels succeeded in blowing up an important transfer point for the electricity grid of the city.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb>NM</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!--  -->
    <WORD_META authors="hertlerb ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>