<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="travel-v">    
   <commentary>
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="journey, move or proceed" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax includes: NP1 TRAVEL (by) PP
        Includes: TRAVEL BY 
        Note: (meaning &quot;to pass by this way&quot;)
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        We travelled north on Route 508.
        He travelled from Rome to Naples by bus.
        Do you prefer to travel by plane or by train?
        Bands of relatives traveled together.
        Waves that have traveled a long way from their source will have undergone much dispersion.
        The dust particles traveled around the world in about two weeks.
        Trains traveled back and forth all day and night playing a significant part in the growth and economic development of this country.
        They always had some food to spare for strangers who happened to travel by.
        She has always wanted to travel around the world.
        Texas Governor Rick Perry has traveled to Iraq with three other governors in a surprise visit to troops from their states.
        Senator Coleman traveled to International Falls to participate in an ice fishing clinic.
        We are planning to travel to India next January.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,5,6</wn>
         <wn lemma="travel_by" version="3.0">1</wn>
         <omega/><pb>travel.01</pb>
         <vn>run-51.3.2-1</vn><fn>Travel</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="move upon or across" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1 TRAVEL NP2[location]
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Oliver Stone traveled the world in 94 days to film the movie.
        Artist Michael Parkes traveled the globe in search of meaning.
        These were ingenious trees that traveled the oceans of the earth in ready-to-grow packages called propagules.
        The busiest day in Maine Turnpike history occurred this year on Friday, August 1, when nearly 247000 vehicles traveled the highway. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="">4</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version="3.0"/>
         <omega/><pb>travel.01</pb>
         <vn>run-51.3.2-1</vn><fn>NM</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>

   <WORD_META authors="duffielc" sample_score="-"/>  
</inventory>