<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="trust-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="arrangement for managing assets on behalf of a beneficiary" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRUST[+relation][+management][+custodial][+asset]
            [+asset][+managed]
            Note: often refers to financial accounts with a designated custodian
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The property is to be held in trust for his son and daughter.
            The family's estate is being managed through a trust corporation in Dallas. (a firm that oversees trusts)
            The wealthy entrepreneur set up a trust fund for each of his children.
            That nation became a trust territory after the war. (extension - a dependent country administered by another)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the state of believing in, or having confidence in, something or someone" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRUST[+state][+mental][+belief][+confidence]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I have no trust in his ability to get us there on time.
            This treaty could provide the foundations of trust between the nations.
            John used only primary sources in his research, taking nothing on trust.
            Their business transactions are based on trust, not legal documents.
            He has betrayed his friends' trust by lying about this issue.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2,3,5,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a non-competing group of businesses, a cartel" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRUST[+organization][+group][+business][-competing]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Which U.S. president was famous for trust busting?  (breaking up monopolies)
            The legality of that large oil trust is being looked into by the courts.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="an organization, often charitable, managed by trustees" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRUST[+organization][+charitable]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Mary is on the board of two national trusts for historical preservation.
            Bob was appointed treasurer of a local charitable trust.
            Pierre is part of a brain trust in Washington. (extension - a group of people tasked with policy decisions)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3a</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="being in a position of responsibility" type="">
        <commentary>
            TRUST[+relation][+responsibility]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They have placed their daughter in the trust of a renowned psychiatrist.
            She is a person in a position of trust.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>