<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="type-n">
    <commentary>
        1sep06 - merged sense 7 with sense2, added features updated to WN 2.1, added examples. ahouston
        1sep06 - merged sense 6 with sense 1. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="subcategory in a classification system, a kind" type="">
        <commentary>
            TYPE[+system][+classification][+subcategory]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            What type of sculpture do you prefer? 
            The word 'element' contains five different types of character.
            The child has a different blood type than his mother.
            Which type of diabetes does her brother have?
            Their store has many types of stone and brick to choose from.
            That type of argument is only ad hominem and not based on logic or evidence.
            It's a type of star that no longer emits radiation in the physical light spectrum.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a person with distinct traits" type="">
        <commentary>
            TYPE[+entity][+person][+distinct][+trait]
            [+relation][+role][+category][+instance]
            Note: informal usage usually refers to people considered odd or eccentric
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            There were a lot of professor types at the party.
            The guy next to me on the bus was a real type. (informal)
            You'll see all types in that part of town. 
            The tall blond surfer was not really Mary's type.
            She's more the athletic type than her sister.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a reference standard in biological taxonomies which form the basis for next higher level in the taxonomy" type="Biology">
        <commentary>
            TYPE[+system][+classification][+subcategory][+taxonomic][+biologic]
            [+relation][+role][+standard][+reference]
            the taxonomic group whose characteristics are used to define the next higher category
            Note: a restricted, scientific subsense of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The type specimen for the species Homo neanderthalensis was the specimen 'Meanderthal-1&quot; discovered in 1856.
            A type genus is the nominal genus that is the name-bearing type of the next higher level family-group.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="printed characters" type="">
        <commentary>
            TYPE[+entity][+symbol][+character][+printed]
            printed characters, written symbols of langugae
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Small type is hard to read.
            The headings should be in bold-faced type.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="typewriter piece" type="">
        <commentary>
            TYPE[+entity][+artifact][+block][+small][+metal][+printing]
            a small metal block bearing a raised character on one end; produces a
            printed character when inked and pressed on paper
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He dropped a case of type, so they made him pick it up.
            She cleaned the types off with a soft cloth.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <!-- more senses go here -->
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>