<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="understanding-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a cognitive state of comprehension of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            UNDERSTANDING[+state][+cognitive][+comprehension][+of_subject]
            Note: implies a specific subject or knowledge domain that is understood by an agent.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Her understanding of Russian is excellent.
            The students displayed little understanding of the material on their exams.
            Bob admitted his understanding of quantum mechanics was pretty shaky.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the general capacity for rational thought" type="">
        <commentary>
            UNDERSTANDING[+quality][+capability][+of_thought][+rational]
            Note: refers to a general capacity of an agent to carry out reasoning or rational thought - not mastery of a specific content of information (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Johnny is a child of sufficient intelligence and understanding to know better.
            Will computers ever develop true understanding and reasoning capabilities?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an agreement between parties" type="">
        <commentary>
            UNDERSTANDING[+state][+social][+agreement][+informal]
            Note: implies a reciprocal agreement between people about something
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I thought we had an understanding about no smoking in the house.
            He was allowed to come only on the understanding that he would be on his best behavior.
            We reached the understanding that we would agree to disagree about it.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a sympathetic inclination" type="">
        <commentary>
            UNDERSTANDING[+quality][+inclination][+sympathetic]
            [+state][+emotional][+empathy]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We thanked them for their kindness and understanding during our family crisis.
            It's a delicate situation that needs to be handled with some patience and understanding.
            John blurted out the joke without any understanding for Mary's feelings.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="an interpretation or explanation" type="">
        <commentary>
            UNDERSTANDING[+state][+cognitive][+belief][+interpretation]
            Note: refers to an agent's belief, conclusion, interpretation of events
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            My understanding was that he is planning to move out on the 30th.
            Was it your understanding that the president was opposed to this new policy?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>