<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="use-n">
    <commentary>28Jan09 - added features, examples, revised definitions. ahouston</commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the employment or operation of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>USE[+event][+employment][+operation][+of_artifact]
            Note: 'use' does not imply a decrease in size or amount during the operation or employment of the thing
        </commentary>
        <examples>We enjoyed the use of the pool at John's house while he was away.
            The doctors are being trained in the use of a new surgical instrument.
            The use of public transportation has increased in recent months.
            She is famous for her unusual use of slang in her poems.
            The man lost the use of his legs after the accident.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">15 6</wn><omega/>
            <pb>use.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the consumption or ingestion of something" type="Event">
        <commentary>USE[+event][+consumption][+of_resource]
            Note: This 'use' implies that the thing is being reduced in size or amount
        </commentary>
        <examples>John stopped his use of recreational drugs after college.
            The congressman is being charged with the illegal use of public funds.
            The company is trying to diminish wasteful uses of energy.
            The banks' use of overnight deposits ensures their financial solvency. 
            The doctor told him to discontinue the use of that new antidepressant.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">4</wn><omega/>
            <pb>use.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the function or purpose of something" type="">
        <commentary>USE[+role][+function][+purpose][+of_something]
            Note: Pick this sense if 'purpose' can be substituted for 'use' without loss of meaning.
        </commentary>
        <examples>He put his knowledge to good use.
            There is no use in crying about it.
            What use is money if you never have time to enjoy it?
            A credit card can open some door locks, although that is not its intended use.
            This herb has various culinary uses.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">23</wn><omega/>
            <pb>use.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="shrewd or devious manipulation to gain personal advantage" type="Event">
        <commentary>
	    USE[+event][+event_set][+manipulation][+devious][+for_advantage][+personal]
	    </commentary><examples>Bob's use of family connections to get a promotion at work annoyed his coworkers. 
            The parents were oblivious to their daughter's use of tantrums to get her way.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="2.0">7</wn><omega/>
            <pb>use.01</pb>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="cstocker ajarrett" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>