<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="version-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="an interpretation, an account or reading of an event or situation" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+activity][+statement][+interpretation]
            Note: in the context of art, implies same language, same art form, but different style
            Note: does not imply the existence of a sequence of variants (see Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He told the police his version of what happened that night.
            Their two versions of the accident don't seem to match up very well.
            Have you ever heard Jimi Hendrix's version of the Star-Spangled Banner? (figurative extension)
            Mary dislikes that stage director's post-modern versions of Shakespeare's plays. (interpretation)
            John did his version of a used car salesman for us at the party.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="variant or variation of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+opus][+variant][+sequenced]
            Note: often implies a sequence of such incremental variants, modified over time.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            I was able to retrieve an earlier version of my file from a backup tape.
            CVS is a software tool that helps maintain version control of files in a distributed environment.
            In one version of that joke, the three guys in the bar are a musician, a doctor and a minister.
            You need to download a newer version of your browser.
            This is a condensed version of the original full length novel.  (same opus just shortened)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0"/>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="an adaptation of an opus to a different form" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+opus][+adaptation][+form][+art]
            Note: implies the source and target are different art forms.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The film version of that bestseller didn't do well at the box office.
            Tchaikovsky's Swan Lake is a ballet version of a classic fairy tale.
            It would be very difficult to do a video game version of that movie.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the translation of an opus from one language to another" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+opus][+translation][+linguistic]
            Note: implies a source language and a target language into which the opus was translated
            Note: implies both source and target are the same art form, different from Sense 3
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            An English version of this Russian novel will be available next year.
            Does this version of the Japanese film have English subtitles or dubbing?
            Many critics think this is the best English version of the Iliad.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="the state of having one's organ in an abnormal position" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+state][+abnormal][+position][+organ]
            Note: usually refers to the position of the uterus.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The doctor determined that the woman had a version of the uterus.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">4a</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the medical procedure of manually turning the uterus" type="">
        <commentary>
            VERSION[+activity][+physical][+procedure][+medical][+turning][+uterus]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            External cephalic version is a method to turn an embryo from a breech to a normal position in utero. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>