<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="volatility-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a measure of large directed movement, usually unpredictable" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLATILITY[+quantity][+measure][+movement][+large][+directed][-predictable]
            Note: often refers to the price movements in financial markets
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The volatility of the stock market is one of its risks. (stock can lose value very fast)
            The relative volatility of a stock to the whole market is called its Beta.
            Volatility in the markets is difficult to predict.
            These fiscal policies may reduce the volatility of the currency.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the chemical property of changing easily to a vapor" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLATILITY[+transformation][+chemical][+easy][+vapor]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The volatility of Mary's perfume made the entire room reek of it.
            The students were asked to measure the volatility of three different liquids at room temperature.
            The liquid evaporated very quickly because of its volatility.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a highly emotional disposition or temperament" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLATILITY[+disposition][+excitable] 
            Note: often refers to an individual nature, but also to collective social behavior.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sam's volatility in the workplace cost him two jobs.
            Mary found the artist's ego and volatility tiring to be around.
            The volatility of this political showdown has increased in recent weeks. 
            The crowd's volatility subsided when the rock star stood up, unhurt. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="the ability to fly" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLATILITY[+ability][+fly]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The children ran outside to test the volatility of their paper airplanes.
            Domestic chickens have limited volatility, usually flying only to tree branches.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>