<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="volume-n">
    <commentary>
        15sep06 updated WN2.1 , added features, expanded defintiions, added examples. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="space occupied" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLUME[+quantity][+amount][+space][+3D]
            The amount of 3-dimensional space occupied by an object.  (often
            expressed as a relative amount)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The gas expanded to twice it's original volume.
            Mix one volume of the solution with ten volumes of water.
            The volume of the box is the product of it's length x width x height.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="an approximated amount of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLUME[+quantity][+amount][+approximated]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            It is usually cheaper to buy in large volumes than in small ones.
            The celebrity receives volumes of fan mail daily.
            When the volume of imports exceeds the volume of exports there is a trade deficit.
            The manufacturer only makes small volumes of their high-end perfumes.
            Volume on the big board today was heavy.  (quantity of trades in a financial market)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="2" n="3" name="book" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLUME[+entity][+artifact][+document][+book]
            [+relation][+member][+set][+publication]
            A book often one of a series
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He used the large encyclopedia volume as a doorstop.
            He asked for the 1989 volume of the Annual Review.
            These volumes should go on a different shelf.
            She just published her second volume of poetry.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="loudness" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLUME[+quality][+loudness]
            The magnitude of sound
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The kids played their music at full volume.
            Turn the volume up, I can barely hear the TV.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="fullness, thickness" type="">
        <commentary>
            VOLUME[+quality][+fullness]
            Note: a derivative special sense of Sense 1
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This shampoo will add volume to fine, limp hair.
            The egg whites will add some volume to the boiled frosting.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">2c</wn>
            <omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett cstocker" sample_score=""/>
</inventory>