<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="water-n">
    <commentary>
        16nov06 update wn2.1, added features. ahouston
        16nov06 - split sense 1 into sense 1, sense5, added senses 6 and 7. ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="The chemical substance, H2O, as it occurs in liquid form" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+entity][+substance][+chemical][-organic][+H2O]
            Note: refers to the -substance- in general, not a body formed of it.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            he asked for a drink of water.
            You should use branch water, not soda water, to make a mint julep.
            Three-quarters of the Earth's surface is covered with water. (refers to the substance not a body)
            Water cannot put out electrical fires.
            There is a water hazard near the fourth hole on this golf course. (hazard filled with substance H2O)
            Note: the 'hazard' must be modified with 'water', unlike a lake or ocean, we don't have to say a 'water lake' or a 'water ocean'.
            Many patients reported their illnesses were cured by taking the waters of that spring.
            That's just water under the bridge now. (idiomatic usage - 'water' here is the substance)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1,6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="public utility access of H2O" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+state][+availability][+service][+utility][+public]
            Note: refers to H2O as a paid-for commodity, a public utility.
            Occurs with verbs that relate to mechanical processes, e.g., 'shut off', 'restore'
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They restored the water to that neighborhood in two hours.
            The utility company shut off their water because they hadn't paid their bills.
            Do you pay for water and electricity? (refers to a service provider).
            Are you on city water this far out in the country?
            There is no running water in this log cabin.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="geographical body of H2O" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+entity][+form][+geographical][+body][+liquid][+ocean/+lake/+bay]
            Note: refers to a large geographical form (ocean, lake, river) that contains H2O.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            They invaded our territorial waters. (refers to a region of ocean near a sovereign nation)
            They were sitting by the water's edge at the lake. (refers to the structural edge of the lake)
            John has done a lot of blue water sailing. (open ocean)
            The bill was intended to clean up the polluted waters of the industrial heartland. (rivers, lakes)
            We are sailing in uncharted waters with this new endeavor. (metaphoric extension)
            Commercial jets must have two engines to fly over water. (implies a large -body- of water)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="biological liquid excretion, e.g, urine" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+entity][+substance][+chemical][+organic][+biological][+excretion][+liquid]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The child made water in his bed again last night.
            The doctor asked the patient whether he had trouble passing water.
            The woman believed she was in labor when her bag of waters broke. (sac of amniotic fluid)
            The child developed a large water blister on his heel from the new boot.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="fundamental element of nature according to ancient philosophy" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+substance][+element][+fundamental][+ancient]
            Note: refers to a pre-scientific notion of water, which includes powers and traits no longer ascribed to the substance, H2O
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The ancients believed everything was made of either earth, air, fire or water.
            Pisces is one of the water signs of the Zodiac.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the quality of transparency, purity, in a gem" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+quality][+transparency][+gem]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            We admired the water of Mary's blue-white diamond.
            Gems of the first water will cost a lot more than those without it. (highest measured clarity)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a financial stock with false value, i.e., the underlying asset does not support the worth of the stock" type="">
        <commentary>
            WATER[+entity][+abstract][+asset][+share][+stock][+value][+false]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The accountant determined that the company's stock was just water.
            John was swindled by a sleazy broker who sold him some water.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>