<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="weakness-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="a flaw or imperfection" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEAKNESS[+quality][+flaw]
            Note: implies an imperfection, not a physical fragility (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            You must evaluate your product's strengths and weaknesses.
            The chess master exploited a weakness in his opponent's defense.
            The weakness of his argument should be apparent.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="a state of social or political powerlessness" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEAKNESS[+state][+social][-power][+political]
            Note: refers to political or social power, not physical or emotional frailty. (Sense 3)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Their party's weakness in the senate means there may not be enough votes for the bill.
            The withdrawal of troops may be perceived as a weakness in the eyes of our adversaries.
            The military sensed weakness in the dictator's regime and attempted a coup. 
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a state of fragility, infirmity, faintness" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEAKNESS[+state][+fragility][+physical/+emotional]
            Note: implies a lack of strength in some dimension
        </commentary>
        <examples> 	
            The patient reported experiencing sudden weakness and shortness of breath.
            A microphone could help overcome the weakness of her voice.
            The engineers detected several structural weaknesses in the bridge. 
            The weakness of the radio signal makes it hard to decipher. 
            We felt a weakness in our knees at the sight of the charred bodies.
            The weakness of her emotional state could be worsened by shocking news.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="reduced purchasing power of a currency" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEAKNESS[+state][+reduced][+purchasing][+power][+currency]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Will the dollar's weakness attract investors or scare them away?
            The extreme weakness of that nation's currency is destroying their middle class.
            Because of the dollar's weakness against the euro, John decided not to travel to France this year.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a preference or indulgence for something" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEAKNESS[+quality][+orientation][+attraction][+extreme]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Bob has a weakness for tall, blond Scandinavian women.
            Mary's weakness for double-cream cheeses made it hard to stick to her diet.
            I have a real weakness for dark chocolate.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>