<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="weight-n">
    <commentary>
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="the force exerted on a body's mass by a gravitational field" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+force][+physical][+gravitational][+exerted][+body][+mass]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Pete has lost a lot of weight in the past six months.
            The weight of a person on the moon is about one-seventh of what it is on the earth.
            The old bridge creaked under the weight of the cement truck.
            What is the atomic weight of oxygen?
            Bob and Tom are in different weight classes in competitive wrestling.
            Two large passengers were re-seated in the forward cabin to distribute the plane's weight.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="sports equipment used in lifting exercises" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+entity][+artifact][+equipment][+sports][+lifting]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            This gym has all the newest weight machines.
            John built up his arm and abdominal muscles by working out with free weights.
            Bob saw Pete at lunch in the weight room.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="the relative importance, significance assigned to something" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+quality][+importance][+relative][+assigned]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The famous professor's recommendation carried great weight with the board of trustees.
            Their social prominence doesn't carry much weight in this neighborhood.
            The boss's son tended to throw his weight around in the office.
            The candidates' words in the debate will carry a lot of weight with voters.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="oppressive or worrisome emotional state" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+state][+emotional][+oppressive][+worrisome]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Moving the deadline up by two weeks removed a big weight from our shoulders.
            The man felt suicidal from the weight of the world pushing down upon him. 
            He was buckling under the weight of increasing responsibilities at work and at home.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="a standardized system of measurements for heaviness" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+system][+measurement][+standard][+heaviness]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These canned goods have their metric weight printed on the labels.
            This scale gives weight in both pounds and kilograms.
            In the avoirdupois system of weight a pound is equal to 16 ounces.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="unit piece to measure the heaviness of something" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+entity][+artifact][+measuring][+unit]
            [+quantity][+measure][+unit][+heaviness]
            Note: refers not to a whole system, but a single object with a given heaviness.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The grocer placed two weights on one side of the scale, and potatoes on the other.
            The diver added another 2-pound weight to his belt to neutralize his buoyancy.
            Each jockey had weights added to his saddle bags.
            They used cobblestones as weights in the bottom of the ship. (heavy pieces of material)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4,7</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="a coefficient assigned to elements in a frequency distribution in order to indicate the relative importance of each element" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+quantity][+number][+coefficient][+distribution][+frequency]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These weights were not adjusted for age or income.
            The weighted round-robin scheduling model was used because computer server weight can be adjusted in this algorithm.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <sense group="1" n="8" name="a grade of density, as of fabric or typeset" type="">
        <commentary>
            WEIGHT[+quantity][+grade][+density][+fabric/+type]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            These summer suits are made of a lighter weight fabric than those winter suits.
            Use a heavier weight font for the section headings.
            The lamp and sculpture next to the couch add too much weight to that side of the room. (extension)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MW online">11,13</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
     
    
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>