<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE inventory
  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'>
<inventory lemma="withdraw-v">
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN senses.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="remove to or from a place or situation" type="">
      <commentary>
         Syntax is: NP WITHDRAW (PP[locative])
                    NP WITHDRAW ONSELF (PP[locative])
         NOTE: Also figurative
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         Last year, I had to withdraw indefinitely from school.
         The enemy troops withdrew to the border.
         See how the tide has withdrawn to that line of rocks?
         Let's withdraw to the library for some privacy.
         Quietly, I withdrew myself from the room.
         He is withdrawing from competitive skiing.
         She'll be withdrawing from her position as CEO next year.
         After his wife died he withdrew into a life of solitude.
         Newsman later withdrew from his earlier position calling it premature.
         After the accident, he withdrew into himself and refused to talk.
         The robbers withdrew several bags of gold into the van.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">1,2,3,6,7,8,10,11</wn>
         <omega/>
         <pb>withdraw.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="recall or take back something" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax is: NP1 WITHDRAW NP2 (PP[locative])
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The FDA is withdrawing several allergy drugs from the market.
         She vowed never to withdraw her accusations of him.
         The Minister duly apologized unreservedly and withdrew his remarks unconditionally.
         The UN has withdrawn its troops from the country.
         Eleven million bottles of water had to be withdrawn from sale due to a health scare.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">4,5</wn>
         <omega/>
         <pb>withdraw.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="tap a resource" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1 WITHDRAW NP2 (PP{P NP[source]})
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         The child was withdrawing water from the town well.
         He withdrew too much money from his checking account last month.
         That nation has probably withdrawn more than half its oil supply. 
         I just withdrew fifty dollars from my account.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">9,12</wn>
         <omega/>
         <pb>withdraw.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="4" name="reveal or produce" type="">
      <commentary>
       Syntax is: NP1 WITHDRAW [concrete] NP2
                  NP1 WITHDRAW [punctual] NP2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
         He withdrew a knife from his pocket.
         The magician will now withdraw a rabbit from his hat.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <wn version="3.0">12</wn>
         <omega/>
         <pb>withdraw.01</pb>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="ahouston,hwangd" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>