<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="woman-n">
    <commentary>12Jan08 update to wn2.1, added features, modified definitions, examples  ahouston
        14Jan08 added additional sense 5 ahouston
    </commentary>
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="female human individuals" type="">
        <commentary>WOMAN[+individual][+person][+female]
            Refers to specific female individuals, -not- a whole gender class (Sense 2)
        </commentary>
        <examples>The woman gave birth to twins.
            These women are all successful entrepreneurs.
            Mary said only three women came to the meeting last night.
            Women and children were put on the lifeboats first.
            John likes to date tall women.
            Our women's basketball team went to the nationals.  (this refers to a specific group of individuals)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="the female gender as a class" type="">
        <commentary>WOMAN[+class][+gender][+female][+human]
            Note: refers to a class, a whole species' gender, not individual females (Sense 1)
        </commentary>
        <examples>In this painting, woman is symbolized by the moon, and man by the sun.
            A woman's metabolism is different from a man's.  (refers to women as a gender class)
            This suit is designed for a woman's body.  (class of women)
            She devoted her life to women's rights in developing nations.
            She is a professor in the women's studies department.
            Women's basketball has become a popular sport.  (It refers to the gender at large, not a specific group of players)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a wife, girlfriend, or mistress" type="">
        <commentary>WOMAN[+person][+female][+role][+lover]
            Note: a narrow sub-sense of Sense 1, which refers to the romantic role played by a female
        </commentary>
        <examples>Although they never married, she was his woman for 20 years.
            John told Bob to stay away from his woman.
            The famous actor has had a lot of women in his life.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a female domestic worker, employee" type="">
        <commentary>WOMAN[+person][+female][+role][+employee][+domestic_worker]
            Note: a narrow sub-sense of Sense 1, referring to females in the role of menial domestic worker.
            Refers to a female menial worker, e.g., charwoman, laundress.
            Note: a somewhat archaic usage
        </commentary>
        <examples>Let the woman in tomorrow so she can clean the house.
            Mary recommended a woman she uses for light cooking and housekeeping.
            He had a woman come in twice a week to do the laundry.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <sense group="" n="5" name="Placeholder Sense: Do Not Choose" type="">
        <commentary/><examples/>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="">Placeholder Sense</wn><omega/>
            <pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    <WORD_META authors="ahouston" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>