<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="world-n">
    <commentary>
        11Jul08  added features, revised definitions and examples, added Sense 6 and idiomatic usages. ahouston
    </commentary>
    
    <sense group="1" n="1" name="our planet earth, or other such planets" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+entity][+natural][+planet][+earth]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            He wants to sail around the world.
            It is the world's highest mountain.
            We could do nothing to save our world from the radiation blast of a supernova.
            He dreamed of exploring other worlds in a space craft.  (extended usage)
            In what part of the world is the Sahara Desert located in?
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">4</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="2" name="people in general, humanity" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+group][+people][+humanity]
            All or some of the people on the Earth
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            All the world loves a clown.
            The world was shocked by his statement.
            Major leaders of the world are meeting in Zurich this week.
            In the film the hero saves the world from a deadly virus. (refers to the people)
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">3,7,8</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="3" name="a personal social sphere or existence" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+state][+social][+existence][+personal]
            Note: refers to the ongoing, overall setting of an individual's existence
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Sally and George are in two totally different worlds.
            In her world men are generally suspect until proven innocent.
            His world came crumbling down when she fired him.
            She said, &quot;I want to rock your world&quot;.
            He's off in his own world again, happily tinkering with electronics in the basement.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">2</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="4" name="a characterized social sphere or environment" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+state][+environment][+characterized]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The child was engrossed in the world of insects.
            In the computing world this device is called a 'mouse'.
            The English-speaking world has continued to grow throughout the past 50 years.
            The couple did not want to visit countries in the third world.
            There were not so many roads in the ancient world as there are today.
            She was a legend in the world of British theater during the 1930s.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">6</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="5" name="secular life, outside religious influence" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+state][+social][+existence][+secular]
            The concerns of the material world as distinguished from a supernatural one or an afterlife.
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The monks left the world behind in their pursuit of spiritual enlightenment.
            The minister told them to be more concerned with the kingdom of heaven than with the temptations of this world.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">5</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="6" name="the cosmos, all reality, existence in general" type="">
        <commentary>
            WORLD[+state][+universe][+reality]
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            Leibniz argued philosophically that our world is the best of all possible worlds.
            John said in a perfect world he'd never get spam in his inbox. (hypothetical reality)
            The world apparently operates according to the laws of quantum mechanics.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <sense group="1" n="7" name="Idioms" type="">
        <commentary>
            NOT_LONG_FOR_THIS_WORLD (about to die)
            BEST_OF_BOTH_WORLDS  (enjoy two things at once)
            BRING_INTO_THE_WORLD (give birth to)
            COME_INTO_THE_WORLD (be born)
            COME_UP/GO_DOWN_IN_THE_WORLD (become richer or pooer)
            IN_THE_WORLD (emphatic device)
            FOR_ALL_THE_WORLD (emphatic device)
            OUT_OF_THIS_WORLD (very positive)
            THINK_THE_WORLD_OF (hold in high esteem)
            WORLDS_APART (very different)
        </commentary>
        <examples>
            The patient is not long for this world.
            With his city condo and country house, he's got the best of both worlds.
            Mary brought three children into the world.
            He came into the world during the Depression.
            These entrepreneurs have come up in the world recently.
            Where in the world did you find that beautiful dress?
            What in the world have you done to your hair!
            That man looks for all the world like my younger brother.
            Mary's chocolate brownies are out of this world.
            He thinks the world of his father.
            She and I are worlds apart when it comes to entertaining.
        </examples>
        <mappings>
            <wn version="MAC">Idioms</wn>
            <omega/><pb/>
        </mappings>
        <SENSE_META clarity=""/>
    </sense>
    
    <WORD_META authors="ajarrett" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>