<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE inventory  SYSTEM 'inventory.dtd'><inventory lemma="yank-v">
   <commentary>
     Contains duplicate WN mappings.
   </commentary>
   <sense group="1" n="1" name="jerk suddenly" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] YANK/YANK ON NP2[object]
        NOTE: there is no direction given here; if a direction/goal/change of location
              is given (either in the utterance or surrounding context), choose sense 2
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        Her mother yanked her belt robe tight and disappeared into her room.
        She had no idea who had yanked her. (with no change of location in the given context)
        Elian yanked his cloak tighter about his shoulders as the cold seeped through the cloth.
        He yanked his reins and turned his horse around and led the squad at a gallop.
        Well I wouldda yanked his chain but ya never know where that's been.
        At least Rambo yanked on his puppet strings.
        I yanked on it in several directions and I couldn't figure out how to move the thing.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>yank.01</pb>
         <vn>push-12-1,split-23.2,hold-15.1-1,carry-11.4</vn><fn>Cause_Motion,Manipulation</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="2" name="quickly or sharply pull and move" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] YANK NP2[object] PP[direction/goal/source]
        NOTE: May be used with resulting state ('open'), including metaphorical usages
              ('into submission') 
      </commentary>
      <examples>
        She yanked the door open.
        He was fishing in Chesapeake Bay when an 18-ft. fish yanked him into the water.
        Presley reached into the van, grabbed the prisoner's hair and yanked him into submission.
        Jeanne grabbed both Sue Ann's hands and yanked her off the toilet.
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>yank.01</pb>
         <vn>split-23.2,carry-11.4,hold-15.1-1,push-12-1</vn><fn>Cause_motion,Manipulation</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <sense group="1" n="3" name="remove, take out (abstract)" type="">
      <commentary>
        Syntax is: NP1[agent] YANK NP2[abstract] (PP[source])
        NOTE: compare carefully to sense 2; in this sense, the source need not be 
              overtly stated and the meaning of 'remove' will still be understood.
              This may be considered to be a sub-sense of sense 2.
      </commentary>
      <examples>
       He posted his review, only to find out that Amazon yanked his writing immediately.
       Quinn was not satisfied at the rate at which he was learning English and she yanked him from class.
       Detroit went into an uproar, and the local ABC affiliate briefly yanked him from its schedule.
       This is the third time a broadcast radio or television station has yanked the program. 
      </examples>
      <mappings>
         <gr_sense/>
         <wn version="3.0">1</wn>
         <wn lemma="" version=""/>
         <omega/><pb>yank.01</pb>
         <vn>carry-11.4,hold-15.1-1,push-12-1,split-23.2</vn><fn>Cause_motion,Manipulation</fn>
      </mappings><SENSE_META clarity=""/>
   </sense>
   <WORD_META authors="duffielc,greenlm" sample_score="-"/>
</inventory>